<Issue id="16901" key="FAB-4039" number="4039" project="10002" reporter="scottz" creator="scottz" type="10002" summary="perf TBD1" priority="2" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2017-05-19 18:14:32.0" updated="2018-07-20 14:12:51.0" resolutiondate="2018-07-09 18:23:38.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="38583"> <description><! CDATA This system testcase is a Performance Benchmark test (refer to FAB-3989) that measures TPS for a short burst of transactions as described below:  +Test Name+:  *FAB_NNNN_4thread_1000i_kafka*  +Component+:  system test, performance TPS measurement  +Description+:  Create the specified number of threads. Half will simultaneously each start sending 1000 transactions to one peer in the first organization, while the remaining threads will send to one peer in the other organization.  For testcases sending invokes, PTE must receive Success Events for all transactions, and all threads will query to verify the final invoke transaction sent.  +Artifact Locations+:   * test/regression/daily/systest_pte.py * test/tools/PTE/runTest.sh - script used to run all PTE tests * test/tools/PTE/<FAB_NNNN_testname> - new directory containing input files for test steps; note the testname (such as FAB_NNNN_4thread_1000i_solo) must match the directory name exactly, so we can reuse the common driver runTest.sh  +Network Topology+:  standard network as defined in FAB-3770 , except in this testcase we use solo orderer  +Client Driver+:  PTE  +Input+:  .../test/tools/PTE/runTest.sh  <testcase_name>  +Output+:  The test passes when all the sent transactions are processed successfully and written to the ledger with no error events raised, and after the last invoke transaction on each thread is verified. TPS can be measured by manual inspection but currently does not influence the pass/failure result. In future we may enhance the PTE tool to automatically determine the TPS, at which time we could modify the assertion in the CI testcase in systest_pte.py to ensure the TPS is not lower than an acceptable value.  ></description> </Issue>
