<Issue id="17816" key="IS-1017" number="1017" project="10401" reporter="farooq_m_khan" assignee="seanbohan_sovrin" creator="farooq_m_khan" type="10002" summary="Sovrin-Client: Use consistent terminology for Agent and Wallets per the Sovrin Provisional Trust Framework V2 whitepaper" priority="3" status="10405" created="2017-06-13 10:29:47.0" updated="2019-03-29 21:04:17.0" votes="0" watches="2" workflowId="50543"> <description><! CDATA Drummond has published a version V2 of the Sovrin Provisional Trust Framework:  http://forum.sovrin.org/t/final-review-v2-of-the-sovrin-provisional-trust-framework/305?u=drummond   With regard to terminology, it deprecates the terms *“app”* and *“client”* in favor of just talking about *agents*. It contains the following definitions in section 3:  *Agent*. A software program or process used by or acting on behalf of a Sovrin Entity to interact with other Agents or directly with the Sovrin Ledger. Agents are of two types: Local Agents run at the edge of the network on a local device, while Cloud Agents run remotely on a server or cloud hosting service. Agents typically have access to a Wallet in order to perform cryptographic operations on behalf of the Sovrin Entity they represent.  *Local Agent*. An Agent that runs at the edge of the network on a local device, such as a smartphone, tablet, laptop, automotive computer, etc. Mutually exclusive with Cloud Agent. A Local Agent may be an app used directly by an Identity Owner, or it may be an operating system module or background process called by other apps. Local Agents typically do not have a Service Endpoint, but do have access to a Local Wallet.  *Cloud Agent*. An Agent that does not run at the edge of the network on a local device, but remotely on a server or cloud hosting service. Mutually exclusive with Local Agent. A Cloud Agent typically has a Service Endpoint and may have access to a Cloud Wallet. Cloud agents may be hosted by an Agency.   *Wallet*. A software module, and optionally an associated hardware module, for securely storing and accessing Private Keys, Master Secrets, and other sensitive cryptographic key material or other Private Data used by a Sovrin Entity. A Wallet may be either a Local Wallet or a Cloud Wallet. In Sovrin infrastructure, a Wallet implements the emerging DKMS standards for interoperable cryptographic key management.  *Local Wallet*. A Wallet, typically used by a Local Agent, that operates at the edge of the network on a local device and stores its cryptographic key material in a secure enclave or other secure storage on that device. Mutually exclusive with Cloud Wallet.  *Cloud Wallet*. A Wallet that operates remotely on a server or cloud hosting service and stores its cryptographic key material securely on that server or cloud service. Cloud Wallets will typically use an HSM (Hardware Security Module). Mutually exclusive with Local Wallet.     Sovrin-Cli needs to be updated so the terminolgy suggested in above document is the one we use in CLI for naming all our commands corresponding command parameters etc.       ></description> </Issue>
