<Issue id="32765" key="INDY-1581" number="1581" project="10303" reporter="vladimirwork" assignee="krw910" creator="vladimirwork" type="10002" summary="DOC: Request for release notes on Indy-node 1.6.70" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="10001" created="2018-08-11 13:31:08.0" updated="2019-03-29 20:34:38.0" duedate="2018-08-19 00:00:00.0" resolutiondate="2019-03-29 20:34:38.0" votes="0" watches="2" workflowId="44001"> <description><! CDATA *Version Information* indy-node 1.6.70 indy-plenum 1.6.49 indy-anoncreds 1.0.11 sovrin 1.1.13  *Major Fixes* INDY-1473 - Several nodes (less than f) get ahead the rest ones under load INDY-1539 - Pool has stopped to write txns INDY-1497 - Re-send messages to disconnected remotes INDY-1478 - Pool stopped writing under 20txns/sec load INDY-1519 - 1.3.62 -> 1.5.67 forced upgrade without one node in schedule was failed INDY-1502 - tmp.log must have unique name INDY-1199 - A node need to hook up to a lower viewChange INDY-1470 - One of the nodes laged behind others after forced view changes INDY-1544 - View Change should not be triggered by re-sending Primary disconnected if Primary is not disconnected anymore  *Changes and Additions* INDY-1491 - As a Trustee running POOL_UPGRADE txn, I need to specify any package depending on indy-node, so that the package with the dependencies get upgraded INDY-1555 - Monitor needs to be reset after the view change INDY-1545 - GC by Checkpoints should not be triggered during View Change INDY-1542 - Validator Info must show committed and uncommitted roots for all states INDY-1475 - Explore timing and execution time INDY-1493 - Memory leaks profiling INDY-1531 - Bind connection socket to NODE_IP INDY-1496 - Enable TRACK_CONNECTED_CLIENTS_NUM option INDY-1378 - We should update revocation registry delta value during REG_ENTRY_REVOC writing INDY-1480 - Support latest SDK in Indy Plenum and Node INDY-1468 - Latency measurements in monitor should be windowed INDY-1528 - Trust anchor permission not needed for ledger writes  *Known Issues* INDY-1517 - Docker pool can't be built because of new python3-indy-crypto in sdk repo (i) The problem described in INDY-1517 will be fixed in the next release of indy-node. Workaround for this problem is to add python3-indy-crypto=0.4.1 to the list of packages to be installed. INDY-1447 - Upgrade failed on pool from 1.3.62 to 1.4.66 (!) Note that INDY-1447 was fixed in indy-node 1.5.68, but it still presents in indy-node 1.3.62 and 1.4.66 code. So, *some of the nodes may not to be upgraded during simultaneous pool-upgrade*. If this problem will appear, stewards should perform manual upgrade of indy-node in accordance with this instruction:  https://docs.google.com/document/d/1vUvbioL5OsmZMSkwRcu0p0jdttJO5VS8K3GhDLdNaoI  (!) To reduce the risk of reproducing INDY-1447, it is *recommended to use old CLI for pool upgrade*.  (!) *Pool upgrade from indy-node 1.3.62 to indy-node 1.6.70 should be performed simultaneously for all nodes due to txn format changes.* (!) *There must be sovrin package upgrade to 1.1.13 version after indy-node package upgrade. You need to specify package=sovrin in pool-upgrade command to do this.* (!) *All indy-cli pools should be recreated with actual genesis files.* (i) *For more details about txn format changes see INDY-1421.*  ></description> </Issue>
