<Issue id="36444" key="FAB-13466" number="13466" project="10002" reporter="nageshbandaru" assignee="denyeart" creator="nageshbandaru" type="10004" summary="Getting error REQUEST_TIMEOUT:localhost:7051" priority="3" resolution="10204" status="6" created="2019-01-01 18:37:57.0" updated="2019-11-18 03:10:15.0" resolutiondate="2019-01-02 15:09:12.0" votes="0" watches="3" workflowId="47977"> <description><! CDATA Hi,     I am using 'balance transfer' example and trying to use my own names for the orderer, CA, peers, so i just updated and renamed in the config files.  Once i start the network, i am able to register user, join peer, install and instantiate chain code. but while invoke the chain code it is showing below error (Node running window): *  ** I am using Fabric 1.3 version and all prerequisites are installed based on document.  Note:  I have not done any changes to Node SDK provide in the balance transfer. i have created my own chaincode and using that.    Attached all the configuration files and log files, also i have attached chaincode i am running(recon.js)     below is the error from node console:   2019-01-01 23:53:32.131   ERROR  invoke-chaincode - REQUEST_TIMEOUT:localhost:7051  2019-01-01 23:53:32.132   ERROR  invoke-chaincode - Error: ChannelEventHub has been shutdown at ChannelEventHub.disconnect (/home/seeraj/blockchain/blockchainpoc/node_modules/fabric-client/lib/ChannelEventHub.js:494:21) at Timeout.setTimeout (/home/seeraj/blockchain/blockchainpoc/app/invoke-transaction.js:89:10) at ontimeout (timers.js:498:11) at tryOnTimeout (timers.js:323:5) at Timer.listOnTimeout (timers.js:290:5)  2019-01-01 23:53:32.138   ERROR  invoke-chaincode - Error: ChannelEventHub has been shutdown at ChannelEventHub.disconnect (/home/seeraj/blockchain/blockchainpoc/node_modules/fabric-client/lib/ChannelEventHub.js:494:21) at Timeout.setTimeout (/home/seeraj/blockchain/blockchainpoc/app/invoke-transaction.js:89:10) at ontimeout (timers.js:498:11) at tryOnTimeout (timers.js:323:5) at Timer.listOnTimeout (timers.js:290:5)  2019-01-01 23:53:32.145   ERROR  invoke-chaincode - Failed to invoke chaincode. cause:Error: ChannelEventHub has been shutdown (node:11458) UnhandledPromiseRejectionWarning: Error: Failed to invoke chaincode. cause:Error: ChannelEventHub has been shutdown at Object.invokeChaincode (/home/seeraj/blockchain/blockchainpoc/app/invoke-transaction.js:171:9) at <anonymous> at process._tickCallback (internal/process/next_tick.js:189:7) (node:11458) UnhandledPromiseRejectionWarning: Unhandled promise rejection. This error originated either by throwing inside of an async function without a catch block, or by rejecting a promise which was not handled with .catch(). (rejection id: 5)        ></description> </Issue>
