<Issue id="15198" key="FAB-2631" number="2631" project="10002" reporter="scottz" assignee="ales" creator="scottz" type="10001" summary="need better logs for VSCC authentication failure" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2017-03-03 22:17:17.0" updated="2018-07-20 18:54:14.0" resolutiondate="2018-07-09 18:23:39.0" votes="0" watches="4" workflowId="37686"> <description><! CDATA As a fabric tester or support personnel, it is difficult to understand why a transaction fails validation in the VSCC, even with DEBUG logs, so debugging issues is very time-consuming. At the point of failure, it would be much more helpful to see the following information displayed (maybe at the INFO level?): * the policy being used to validate the identified transaction * the names of the signers (peer name, and associated org name). At one point I saw a log with the hash signature of signer(s), but that is difficult for tester to understand and trace. * the names of signers/orgs that are lacking  For example, if the policy is "AND('OrgRedMSP.member','OrgBlueMSP.member')" then a TX must be signed/endorsed by any one member of OrgRed or any one member of OrgBlue. If peer00 is in OrgRed and peer00 endorses a transaction, and there are no other signatures, then the log could state something to the effect of the first part being satisfied (peer00 = OrgRedMSP.member) however the validation failed due to lacking signatures from any OrgBlueMSP.member.  And I would hope the same information could also be provided to the SDK or any process that registers for event failure notification.  Existing log:  peer2        | 2017-03-02 21:50:57.835 UTC  txvalidator  VSCCValidateTx -> ERRO 001 VSCC check failed for transaction txid=de8c2db2f9bce9be2ab2864339a08862ab9de8280c2c0b919930eb22fbaecf94, error VSCC error: policy evaluation failed, err Failed to authenticate policy peer2        | 2017-03-02 21:50:57.839 UTC  txvalidator  Validate -> ERRO 002 VSCCValidateTx for transaction txId = de8c2db2f9bce9be2ab2864339a08862ab9de8280c2c0b919930eb22fbaecf94 returned error VSCC error: policy evaluation failed, err Failed to authenticate policy   ></description> </Issue>
