<Issue id="15110" key="FABN-229" number="229" project="10604" reporter="jjjjibm" assignee="jimthematrix" creator="jjjjibm" type="10004" summary=" node-sdk  &lt;ip:port&gt;/docs/gen/User.html  identities .. has --&gt; identities .. have, and why call it toString()?" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2017-02-28 18:32:47.0" updated="2018-07-19 00:53:18.0" resolutiondate="2017-04-05 18:39:20.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="33960"> <environment><! CDATA fabric-sdk-node commit d3fcbe2299c840dfd7886076b009b88eb25a7dd8 fabric commit a0d032bc5c4853b43972163f502a03ee7770c1d5 fabric-ca commit c9fb04e0f795589485915883fcbca3ae2fc0aaad  Ubuntu is running on a vlaunch VM   ></environment> <description><! CDATA Generated documentation for class User has these minor grammar errors.  (1)  Is now: User identitie{color:#205081}s{color} represent signing capability because {color:#205081}it has {color}access  Should be: User identities represent signing capability because {color:#205081}they have {color}access ..  Could be:  The user identity represents signing capability because it has access ...  (2)  Is now: Peer identitie{color:#205081}s{color} in the context of the application/SDK only {color:#205081}has{color} the ...  Should be: Peer{color:#205081} identities {color}in the context of the application/SDK only {color:#205081}have{color}  the ...  Could be: The peer identity in the context of the application/SDK only has the ...  If you pick the 'Could be' or similar solution for (1) you should select the 'Could be' solution or similar for (2) for consistent style.  For the same reason, match the 'should be' solution for (1) with a 'should be' solution for (2).   (3) Some method descriptions end with '.', and others do not  (See what I did that?)  Example:  getAffiliation()  Get the affiliation{color:#d04437}. {color} The description ends with a period '.'  Example: fromString()  Set the current state of this member from a string based JSON object  The description does not with a period.  I count 9 descriptions  punctuated standardly,  5 dangling (See what I did with that?)  Solution:  pick one style and use it consistently.   (4)  toString() is defined or named in an unconventional way   These classes in the node SDK have the method toString(): Chain, FabricCAServices, Peer, Remote.  Tt is always defined like this:  _toString()  return a printable representation of this object _  Class User also has a method toString(), defined like this:  toString()  Save the current state of this member as a string   If this method does something that is not identical to what the other class toString() methods do, overloading the name will cause confusion.  The method should be renamed.   If this method does the same thing the other class toString() methods do, this description or the other descriptions need to change.    ></description> </Issue>
