<Action id="44953" issue="30094" author="kithat" type="comment" created="2018-05-23 08:47:28.0" updateauthor="kithat" updated="2018-05-23 08:47:28.0"> <body><! CDATA Implemented in PRs: https://github.com/hyperledger/indy-sdk/pull/780 https://github.com/hyperledger/indy-sdk/pull/787  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="45027" issue="30094" author="kithat" type="comment" body="Build version: master-529" created="2018-05-24 07:32:29.0" updateauthor="kithat" updated="2018-05-24 07:32:29.0"/>
<Action id="45128" issue="30094" author="zhigunenko.dsr" type="comment" created="2018-05-25 11:30:00.0" updateauthor="zhigunenko.dsr" updated="2018-05-25 15:40:06.0"> <body><! CDATA *Environment:* indy-cli 1.4.0-530 (both Win and Ubuntu) libnullpay 1.4.0-530 (both Win and Ubuntu)  *Inconsistencies in libnullpay and CLI:* -1) _payment_address_ as parameter and _payment-address_ as command- Expected behaviour 2) current functionality cannot match link between NYM and internal constant 1 (from _constants.rs_) when user set or get fee (moved to IS-723) {code} Examples: 	ledger set-fees-prepare payment_method=sov fees=NYM:100,ATTRIB:200 {code} 3) fee can be set below zero - if it is valid case, some warning message still needed (Moved to IS-724 -4) no role restrictions for fee setting- It should be checked on ledger side 5) connected pool is not required for fee setting  6) connected pool is not required for token emission 7) token emission has nothing to do with multi-signature (two separate commands, UTXO added to addresses right after emission transaction) 8) connected pool is not required for multi-signature 5-8 are moved to IS-728 9) In _ledger mint-prepare outputs=_ amount can be set below zero, but there is no warning/error message. UTXO with negative amount was not created (moved to IS-725) -10) Double send to single payment address during single mint-prepare transaction has unclear default error message. On the other hand it's possible to send mint-prepare to the same address many times- For now it is expected. We already have a ticket about custom error messages support 11) user can use input UTXO with amount lower than transaction fee requires (moved to IS-726) -12) ledger payment inputs - amount can be set below zero- Recheck -13) ledger payment - *;* separator available in inputs, not in outputs- Recheck 14) ledger payment - there is no local check that UTXO from input is related to wallet (IS-727) -15) double UTXO send in the same payment has unclear default error message- Expected behaviour -16) double usage of the same adresses in payment outputs has unclear default error message- Expected behaviour -17) there is no mechanism to fee withdrawal if during transaction user doesn't set input/output (no default wallet or something else)- Up to ledger -18) ledger nym with outputs bigger than inputs marked as sent without any error (in fact tokens weren't moved)- Recheck -19) unknown behavior of plugin when pool in _read-only_ mode (unable to reproduce sutiation now)- Not in scope of tested tickets   ></body> </Action>
