<Action id="66414" issue="43604" author="vladimirwork" type="comment" created="2019-12-26 13:47:54.0" updateauthor="vladimirwork" updated="2019-12-28 08:32:38.0"> <body><! CDATA *Version Information* indy-node 1.12.1 indy-plenum 1.12.1 sovrin 1.1.67  *Notices for Stewards* Use forced simultaneous pool upgrade. Please be careful with demoting/promoting/adding nodes (see Known Issues for details). There are possible OOM issues during 3+ hours of target load or large catch-ups at 8 GB RAM nodes pool so 32 GB is recommended.  *Major Changes* - Multiple active TAAs implementation - Stability fixes  *Detailed Changelog*  +Major Fixes+ INDY-2303 - Sovrin upgrade fails due to incorrect package dependencies INDY-2306 - GET_CRED_DEF for a Schema with a lot of attributes may fail with Timeout INDY-2024 - Only Trustee or Node owner can be the author of NODE demotion txn regardless of endorsement or auth constraint rules set  +Changes and Additions+ INDY-2302 - Allow multiple active TAAs INDY-2316 - Allow multiple active TAAs: Debug INDY-2313 - Improve TAA acceptance date validation INDY-2297 - Get TAA should return the hash INDY-2304 - Auth_Rules documentation should explain how endorsers work INDY-2138 - Document PBFT view change protocol INDY-2299 - Backups should start ordering in new view only after master instance ordered till prepared cert from NewView INDY-2294 - Get rid of transport batches INDY-2289 - Enable zeroMQ auto-reconnection INDY-2286 - Improve simulation tests to include NODE txns INDY-2280 - Improve BLS signature performance INDY-2263 - Improve simulation tests to include processing of InstanceChanges  +Known Issues+ INDY-2308 - A node lagging behind may not be able to finish view change if nodes have been added/demoted INDY-2319 - Up to F Nodes may not be able to finish View Change if there are uncommitted NODE txns INDY-2318 - A node may start re-sending messages in a loop in case of connection issues INDY-2320 - A lagging node may use wrong N and F quorum values and never finish view change if there are NODE txns being processed   ></body> </Action>
