<Issue id="31908" key="FAB-11169" number="11169" project="10002" reporter="elli-androulaki" creator="elli-androulaki" type="10000" summary="Token (base support) - Life Cycle" priority="2" resolution="10001" status="6" created="2018-07-16 08:43:20.0" updated="2020-01-13 15:12:19.0" resolutiondate="2020-01-13 15:12:19.0" votes="2" watches="9" workflowId="35961"> <description><! CDATA This is one epic from many to follow to allow for token management enablement of Fabric.  Current proposal|https://docs.google.com/document/d/1fzxoQYARFPTTIM-eIw8zs6tYkg6t6uRVI6fmnCQJz9I/edit?usp=sharing  for the higher level design.     *What:* This epic aims at allowing the activation and definition of a channel's FabToken system via transactions submitted to the blockchain, and the subsequent setup of all the involved FabToken entities (i.e., prover/commiting peer, client).   In particular, this epic requires that FabToken system's stakeholders announce the agreed-upon FabToken configuration to the chain, and feed in this way the committing peers of the system that are to process this channel's (FabToken) transactions (see, FAB-11144 for more details on the committing peer processing).   To help out client-setup, prover peers are required to use the chain-advertised FabToken parameters into their responses to the GRPC service.      *Why:* Announcing the FabToken configuration details allows every committing peer in the channel to have a consistent view of the terms under which a FabToken transaction is to be validated against. It also allows for upgrades of the system to be openly and consistently verifiable by all the members of the system. This way of configuring FabToken is consistent to way chaincodes are deployed and configured within the system, and as such there is  well-thought code that can be reused (chaincode lifecycle). Also, allowing the prover peer to return to the client the configuration parameters of FabToken allows for a short and easy to configure FabToken client.     *How:* A potential break-down of this epic into work-items is as follows: # Design - in progress # As a Fabric core developer I would like to setup a prover peer (this is offered to large extend by FAB-11149, item 7) # As  a Fabric core developer I would like to leverage chaincode lifecycle to activate FabToken and configure it # As  a Fabric core developer  I would like to setup the client wallet library with the FabToken (this is offered to large extend by FAB-11153, item 6) # Documentation # Update the e2e test of FAB-11153 to account for configurability aspects of the system     Adding   ~sykesm ,  ~angelo.decaro ,  ~mathiasb303 , @KaoutaEl,   ~jyellick ,  ~denyeart .  ></description> </Issue>
