<Issue id="34208" key="FABN-945" number="945" project="10604" reporter="ratnakar" assignee="harrisob@us.ibm.com" creator="ratnakar" type="10004" summary="Compatibility tests are failing with case 2 of FAB-12001 " priority="3" resolution="10204" status="6" created="2018-09-28 14:13:34.0" updated="2018-11-14 21:26:00.0" resolutiondate="2018-11-14 21:26:00.0" votes="0" watches="2" workflowId="45534"> <description><! CDATA Please Refer the Case 2 of  FAB-12001|https://jira.hyperledger.org/browse/FAB-12001   NodeJs Integration Test Suite /SDK and Fabric-Ca are all at *V1.2.0* , where as Fabric Images are at *1.3.0-rc1*  Refer the case 2 test steps given in *Steps to Reproduce the issue* section.  High level overview of the failures :  {code} not ok 728 Error: Failed transaction ::undefined at Promise.all.then.catch (/Users/ratnakar/workspace/go/src/github.com/hyperledger/fabric-sdk-node/test/integration/invoke.js:293:11) at <anonymous> not ok 729 Failed to invoke transaction chaincode not ok 740 Failed transaction ::undefined not ok 741 Error: Failed transaction ::undefined at Promise.all.then.catch (/Users/ratnakar/workspace/go/src/github.com/hyperledger/fabric-sdk-node/test/integration/invoke.js:293:11) at <anonymous> not ok 836 Problem setting up the event hub :Error: Received status message on the event stream. status:NOT_FOUND not ok 837 Problem setting up the event hub :Error: ChannelEventHub has been shutdown not ok 838 Test failed with Error: Problem setting up the event hub :Error: ChannelEventHub has been shutdown not ok 839 transaction proposal was bad not ok 840 transaction proposal was bad not ok 841 Failed to send invoke Proposal or receive valid response. Response null or status is not 200. exiting... not ok 842 Test failed with Error: Failed to send invoke Proposal or receive valid response. Response null or status is not 200. exiting... not ok 844 Test failed with Error: 2 UNKNOWN: access denied: channel  adminconfig  creator org  Org1MSP  not ok 846 Failed to find our channel in the result list not ok 860 TypeError: Cannot read property 'name' of undefined {code}     ></description> </Issue>
