<Action id="26314" issue="17500" author="nickgaski" type="comment" created="2017-06-14 18:12:33.0" updateauthor="nickgaski" updated="2017-06-14 18:12:33.0"> <body><! CDATA This issue is ostensibly solved through -  https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/#/c/10423/   However, I also have a patch with some more thorough instructions which is -2 right now due to vagrant and compiling from source -  https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/#/c/10295/      ></body> </Action>
<Action id="26539" issue="17500" author="nickgaski" type="comment" created="2017-06-16 13:38:38.0" updateauthor="nickgaski" updated="2017-06-16 13:38:38.0"> <body><! CDATA There is a CR to add orderer and peer to the release directory.  That said, there is currently an unavoidable dependency to, at the very least, clone the fabric directory.  You could download the binaries through getting started, but then you would need to create a build/bin directory in the fabric tree and copy the peer and orderer executables to that dir.  In an ideal world, dev mode would work with the current structure of getting started.  However, we do not have the SingleSampleMSPSolo profile in our configtx.yaml.  Additionally, we dynamically generate new crypto material each time, so the cryptogen utility would need to be exercised OR we need to place some dummy certs and a genesis block into the tar ball (I confess I'm not precisely positive about all the minutiae of how dev mode works with regards to launching the peer and orderer; namely, I don't know the extent of the dependencies).  Lastly, the binaries are placed into a bin folder; not build/bin as they are in the fabric source tree.  Need help here if we do not want a developer to clone fabric and run a make release-all.   ~rameshthoomu   ~ChristopherFerris   ~muralisr   ~mastersingh24      An alternative might be simply having a developer use docker containers in the same fashion as the getting started approach. (This would not be dev mode though).  The only downfall is they have to reinstall, and then either instantiate or upgrade the chaincode.  There are also some requisite steps to generate crypto, artifacts, and bootstrap the orderer, create/join channels, etc...  Happy to hear thoughts and would love to close this ticket  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="26613" issue="17500" author="nickgaski" type="comment" body="Lowering to medium until we decide upon a solution" created="2017-06-16 20:02:59.0" updateauthor="nickgaski" updated="2017-06-16 20:02:59.0"/>
<Action id="26756" issue="17500" author="nickgaski" type="comment" created="2017-06-19 15:03:52.0" updateauthor="nickgaski" updated="2017-06-19 15:03:52.0"> <body><! CDATA adding notes...  when attempting to run the orderer I see {color:#333333}panic: Error while trying to create dir if missing: mkdir /var/hyperledger: permission denied{color}  **{color:#333333}meaning that a user {color}{color:#333333}will have to manually create the /var/hyperledger directory OR set CORE_PEER_FILESYSTEMPATH to a writable directory. {color}     {color:#333333}I also receive a consistent "Killed 9" response unless I set GO_TAGS=nopkcs11 along with my make.{color}  ></body> </Action>
