<Issue id="12648" key="FAB-347" number="347" project="10002" reporter="gauravgiri" assignee="hgabre" creator="gauravgiri" type="10004" summary="Chaincode Deployment Issue using HFC Node SDK with the latest version of Hyperledger" environment="Vagrant Virtual Machine" priority="2" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2016-09-12 07:55:15.0" updated="2018-07-20 14:10:10.0" resolutiondate="2017-04-07 12:49:03.0" votes="0" watches="6" workflowId="36204"> <description><! CDATA Issue related to chaincode deployment using HFC Node SDK with error message: Incorrect number of arguments  Creating this issue for deployment error using HFC https://www.npmjs.com/package/hfc (with both current version 0.5.2, and previous version 0.6.0) on the latest version of hyperledger/fabric from gerrit http://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/fabric This issue has is linked to a previous issue of deployment, but this is specifically related to HFC related deployment: https://jira.hyperledger.org/browse/FAB-208  Steps to reproduce the issue: 1. checked out the latest version of hyperledger fabric source from gerrit repository  2. vagrant up  3. start membersrvc: i) make membersrvc ii) membersrvc 4. start peer node: i) change peer/core.yaml and enable security enabled: true ii) make peer iii) peer node start 4. copy from fabric\examples\chaincode\go\chaincode_example02 to $GOPATH/src/github.com/chaincode_example02 and setup the vendor directory with latest source of hyperledger fabric at  vendor/github.com/hyperledger/fabric 5. try to deploy $GOPATH/src/github.com/chaincode_example02 using the latest version of the hfc node sdk version 0.5.2, using the attachment sample.js using command "node sample.js" 6. check the peer logs for issue related to number of arguments, the number of arguments being recieved by the init method is always coming as 0.  Error messages in peer server logs during chaincode deployment:  chaincode  processStream -> ERRO 031 Got error: Incorrect number of arguments. Expecting 4  chaincode  Launch -> ERRO 032 sending init failed(Error initializing container 9f192841dd07b37f7d95ea364df838b37bc8be29d2babf15f42f478ff395c7cb: Incorrect number of arguments. Expecting 4)  ></description> </Issue>
