<Issue id="19706" key="INDY-518" number="518" project="10303" reporter="avkrishnan" assignee="stevetolman" creator="avkrishnan" type="10001" summary="need a ledger explorer tool" description="I need a tool that allows me to walk through records in the ledger, inspecting them in much the same way that MySQL Workbench would allow me to open a RDBMS, enumerate all the tables, write arbitrary queries, export data, and maybe repair something.This tool addresses multiple important use cases:# As a sysadmin or other technical community member, I need to be able to diagnose problems with corrupt data.# As an Evernym developer or tester, I need to be able to create corrupt ledgers and interact with them to test various failure scenarios. I also need to accept corrupt ledgers and diagnose what went wrong.#  As a Sovrin advocate, I want to be able to demo Sovrin&apos;s behavior with respect to the ledger, without having a UI that necessarily manifests a given feature.# As a developer in the Sovrin ecosystem, I want to be able to study the effects of my code on test ledgers.# As a sysadmin in an ultimate &quot;nuclear failure&quot; scenario where the world ledger is offline and no automated remediation seems possible, I might need to patch a corrupt ledger by following instructions issued by the TGB.I can imagine two different modes of operation for this explorer: one where it talks to a remote ledger via libsovrin, and one where it talks to a local data file.The tool should support all the ledgers used by sovrin (identity, voting, performance, pool, etc).The UI should run on any common desktop OS. It can be relatively primitive and inefficient, as long as it&apos;s easy to understand. We could do a SPA with react/node.js, like the one that  ~andrey.goncharov  wrote for the node admin UI, or we could use java or QT creator, maybe." priority="3" resolution="10200" status="10001" created="2017-08-02 09:27:08.0" updated="2019-03-29 20:33:36.0" resolutiondate="2019-03-29 20:33:36.0" votes="0" watches="2" workflowId="19706"/>
