<Issue id="20532" key="INDY-796" number="796" project="10303" reporter="krw910" assignee="krw910" creator="krw910" type="10001" summary="DOC: Request for release notes on Indy-node 1.1.31" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="10001" created="2017-08-30 17:54:02.0" updated="2019-03-29 20:34:17.0" duedate="2017-08-31 00:00:00.0" resolutiondate="2019-03-29 20:34:17.0" votes="0" watches="2" workflowId="20536"> <description><! CDATA  *Version Information* indy-plenum= 1.1.24 indy-anoncreds= 1.0.9 indy-node= 1.1.31 sovrin= 1.0.4  *Major Fixes  *  INDY-410 - Stewards can now demote and promote their own nodes INDY-466 - Fixed problem with timezones for timestamp in transaction INDY-25 - Limited incoming message size from 128k to 128MB (Temporary solution) INDY-378 - fixed `send CLAIM_DEF` command INDY-725 - mask private info in CLI logs/output INDY-8 - fixes crashes on ubuntu 17.04 INDY-211 - python interpreter is executed in optimized mode INDY-223 - memory leak fixes Some minor stability fixes    Changes and Additions   	* New ledger serialization is supported and Leveldb is used as as a storage for all ledgers : msgpack is used for the ledger serialization (both transaction log and merkle tree) 	*  		*      The new serialization change created changes to the directory structure for the nodes. The directory name changes are located on a node under .sovrin/data/nodes/<node name>/<directories>. The change removes the ledger files as plain text files and creates them as binary files. A new tool was created to view the ledger entries called read_ledger and is described below.  	* Genesis transaction files are renamed adding a _genesis to the end of each file name. 	*   	* Added the commands to the POOL_UPGRADE to support downgrade and re-installation. However both have issues and should not be used at this time (INDY-735 and INDY-755). 	* The tool read_ledger.py was created to allow access to reading the ledger or getting a count of the transactions. You can run read_ledger as the sovrin user with --h to get a list of commands. 	* Fixes to upgrade procedure (in particular and issue which caused an infinite loop INDY-316) 	* CLI Changes 	*  		* New CLI command was added to ease the process of rotating a verification key (verkey). The command is `change current key` or 'change current key with seed xxxxx'.  		* Modified terminology in code, CLI and documentation 		*  			* Changed 'keyring' to 'wallet' 			* Changed 'link' to 'connection' 			* Changed 'invitation' to 'request' 			* Changed 'identifier' to 'DID'   	* Improvements to log messages 	* Publishing only to repo.sovrin.org 	*  		* In your sources.list you only need the entry "deb https://repo.evernym.com/deb xenial stable".    ></description> </Issue>
