<Action id="28058" issue="18752" author="kchristidis" type="comment" created="2017-07-09 21:02:15.0" updateauthor="kchristidis" updated="2017-07-09 21:02:15.0"> <body><! CDATA As best as I can tell, sampleconfig now carries `configtx.yaml`, `core.yaml`, and `orderer.yaml`?  Are we good? If yes, please mark as done.  If not, specify what's still left to do, e.g. * Do one * And two * And three  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="28251" issue="18752" author="scottz" type="comment" created="2017-07-12 15:56:09.0" updateauthor="scottz" updated="2017-07-12 15:56:09.0"> <body><! CDATA sampleconfig is one of many places where those 3 config files are stored in fabric and fabric-samples repositories. In any given instance where one of them (core.yaml, orderer.yaml, configtx.yaml) is mentioned, to which should the users refer? # Where do we define all the +default+ values for all the config parameters? Are the files in the fabric/sampleconfig/ directory the defaults? Or, are those the values to start with, which we recommend and support? All this should be stated somewhere in the docs where we instruct network administrators to get started (BYFN). # Rename sampleconfig as defaultconfig # Search the WYFA and BYFN instructions, and clarify the location of the config files used for those. # Search the rest of the documentation rst and readme.md files for references to the 3 config files and edit to specify the exact location in addition to the name of the referenced config files. For example,  http://hyperledger-fabric.readthedocs.io/en/latest/kafka.html  refers to orderer.yaml. Where do they find the file? Maybe we can consider revising this page, considering the audience to be a system administrator, rather than a developer.   ></body> </Action>
<Action id="28291" issue="18752" author="kchristidis" type="comment" created="2017-07-13 02:52:04.0" updateauthor="kchristidis" updated="2017-07-13 05:22:57.0"> <body><! CDATA Let's start from point 2, which I actually disagree with.  I'll argue that "sampleconfig" _is_ the right name, specifically, because these are just that, _sample_ defaults. A proper config file should have inline comments or an associated doc (as is the case, for example, for Kafka) identifying incorrect values.  Moving on to point 4, there is no hard-coded exact location of config files. (This is, for instance, why I simply refer to "orderer.yaml" in the Kafka guide.) The location of the config files is governed by the following mechanism: if you have the FABRIC_CFG_PATH ENV var set, we (peer|orderer) will look for the config files there:  https://github.com/hyperledger/fabric/blob/master/core/config/config.go#L139  Otherwise, we will look for the files following this list:  https://github.com/hyperledger/fabric/blob/master/core/config/config.go#L147...L149   What we may want to do is simply to create a doc that describes the config-location mechanism?  At any rate, there may still be valid points in this JIRA. (Or hey, every suggestion in your list may be right and I'm wrong.)  My suggestion for this kind of improvement requests that don't go too deep into touching code: submit a changeset that corresponds to your suggested TODO list here. Esp. for doc-related changes, only you know _exactly_ what you have in mind, and it's probably faster to push a changeset out there and give us something concrete to talk about.  As an example:  > Maybe we can consider revising this page, considering the audience to be a system administrator, rather than a developer.   There is a good chance this is an excellent suggestion, but rather than me guessing (and missing) what would make for a good revision, we could use a changeset of yours as a starting basis.  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="28442" issue="18752" author="scottz" type="comment" created="2017-07-14 21:53:22.0" updateauthor="scottz" updated="2017-07-14 21:53:39.0"> <body><! CDATA WIP...  To do:  1. In fabric/orderer/README.md, change this sentence to instead refer to CONFIGTX_ORDERER_ORDERERTYPE:  ```Specifically, the value corresponding to the `ConsensusType` key of the `Values` map of the `Orderer` config group on the system channel should be set to either `solo` or `kafka`.```  2. Maybe add a README.md in fabric/sampleconfig/. , or in docs/source/, which explains of FABRIC_CFG_PATH - how it (and its backup/defaults) is used for finding the configtx.yaml orderer.yaml core.yaml , as suggested by Kostas.  3. In BYFN, provide ptr link to fabric/sampleconfig/README  4. Combine these two sentences in  https://github.com/hyperledger/fabric/blob/release/docs/source/build_network.rst#manually-generate-the-artifacts  :   ```Next, we need to tell the configtxgen tool where to look for the configtx.yaml file that it needs to ingest. We will tell it look in our present working directory:  First, we need to set an environment variable to specify where configtxgen should look for the configtx.yaml configuration file```     ></body> </Action>
<Action id="28443" issue="18752" author="kchristidis" type="comment" body="RE: Point 1 – Why is referring to an ENV var better than actually explaining what is being edited?" created="2017-07-14 21:56:24.0" updateauthor="kchristidis" updated="2017-07-14 21:56:24.0"/>
<Action id="28493" issue="18752" author="scottz" type="comment" body=" ~kchristidis  This being a readme.md inside the fabric folders, and intended for developers as well as users, I will add (so it is more useful to a user) instead of replace what is useful for a developer." created="2017-07-17 13:33:31.0" updateauthor="scottz" updated="2017-07-17 13:33:31.0"/>
<Action id="30592" issue="18752" author="kchristidis" type="comment" body="Just checking - is this on track for 1.1?" created="2017-09-07 01:49:45.0" updateauthor="kchristidis" updated="2017-09-07 01:49:45.0"/>
<Action id="31241" issue="18752" author="kchristidis" type="comment" body="Last bump for updates. Are we doing this for 1.1?" created="2017-09-28 15:41:16.0" updateauthor="kchristidis" updated="2017-09-28 15:41:16.0"/>
<Action id="62759" issue="18752" author="scottz" type="comment" body="This is outdated. These points are addressed in the fabric readthedocs." created="2019-08-09 13:58:13.0" updateauthor="scottz" updated="2019-08-09 13:58:13.0"/>
