<Issue id="28419" key="FAB-8794" number="8794" project="10002" reporter="elli-androulaki" assignee="elli-androulaki" creator="elli-androulaki" type="10000" summary="Chaincode attribute-based access control using channel MSPs" priority="3" status="10000" created="2018-03-12 13:37:37.0" updated="2019-05-13 06:02:21.0" votes="1" watches="6" workflowId="35601"> <description><! CDATA Being able to perform access control on the chaincode side on transaction creator's or other identities is needed in many cases. However it is frequently tedious for the chaincode developer to parse a serialised identity (e.g., the transaction creator's) and to check whether this identity fulfils certain properties. In fact, very often the developer would need to manually extract certain identity's properties, e.g., OU, O field of the certificate, ending up repeating the logic of MSP identity deserialisation and field extractor. At the same time, the developer cannot leverage MSP announcements on CRL updates that take place on the same channel.      This epic aims at offering to a Fabric chaincode the ability to perform (attribute-based) access policy evaluation using the respective channel's MSPs. It also aims at enhancing the existing MSP principal definition to support definition of "attributes", and of the MSPs implementation to account for the new type of principal. The proposed work aims at enhancing the 1.1 capabilities on attribute based authentication in that channel MSPs are used for deserialising serialised identities, and performing the actual policy evaluation (be it attribute-based or OU-based). This gives the advantage that i) chaincodes can directly leverage any MSP reconfiguration on that channel (e.g., peer/client OU, admin OU etc), ii) no code deduplication is required (we would only use the policy manager of the channel, no need to manually perform parts of the policy evaluation on the chaincode side), iii) can allow for attribute-verification where the issuer is not the same as the identity provider (e.g., msp CA).     Preliminary design is listed  here|https://docs.google.com/document/d/1ETeoqfUHMK3sisF0k0IIACLEh3E8eVzMiOWagTAQXio/edit?usp=sharing , but we aim to break this task down to two pieces:  - Performing attribute-based attestation w.r.t. a single MSP's context (e.g., on MSP certifiable attributes) => **1.2**  - Performing attribute-based attestation considering cross-MSP issuers => **post 1.2**     ></description> </Issue>
