<Action id="65193" issue="43043" author="jyellick" type="comment" created="2019-10-30 16:16:10.0" updateauthor="jyellick" updated="2019-10-30 16:16:10.0"> <body><! CDATA As a bit of pre-amble, Fabric logging is not considered to be a stable API. All log messages emitted are subject to change, and although we endeavor not to modify logging formats indiscriminately and without purpose, log messages could be changed in severity, grammar, or structure to improve usability.  As a longer term goal of Fabric, it would be great to move towards a more structured logging format, though I don't think we're there yet.  So, any 'logging events' published by Fabric should only be considered stable down to the Fabric patch level.  That being said, allow me to do a quick first pass on what you've requested. {quote}User or group added User or group deleted User or group modified User password change User role modified {quote} These would be fabric-CA related. {quote}Concurrent user sessions Persistent user session {quote} Although Fabric doesn't really do 'sessions', it's typical for a user to be making multiple authenticated calls (some of which are long lived) at any given time. {quote}User logon failure User logon success System time change {quote} There is no real notion of logon.  And system time changes would be an OS level event, not Fabric related. {quote}Unauthorised activity attempt {quote} I would likely think this falls into a two broad categories.  1) Unauthorized invocation of Broadcast or Deliver on the orderer 2) Unauthorized invocation of Propose or Deliver on the peer {quote}Unauthorised data modification / modification attempt {quote} As Fabric is a blockchain, data modification is done through a consented process.  The closest thing here is probably an endorsement policy failure. {quote}Privileged user commands and activities {quote} What would you consider privileged? Chaincode install jumps to mind, join channel would be another. {quote}Security and audit policy changes {quote} This is a little broad, do you have more specific requirements?  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="65196" issue="43043" author="j.on" type="comment" created="2019-10-30 17:17:53.0" updateauthor="j.on" updated="2019-10-30 17:19:28.0"> <body><! CDATA That's a very helpful pre-amble Jason, thank you.   Looking at unauthorised data invocation and endorsement policy failure, would such events be manifest in logs and how? Aim being capturing through regex.  {{privileged user commands and activities}} and {{security and audit policy changes}} are related. We'd like to understand if the Chaincode contains runtime configuration which may be altered by a privileged user, and if misused, could prove or at least indicate a threat to its integrity, confidentiality, or availability.  The aim again being capturing these events (if such are logged) and parsing with regex.   Concerning:   "User or group added User or group deleted User or group modified User password change User role modified  These would be fabric-CA related"  Should I post these questions under fabric-CA?   Thank you. -Jon  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="68870" issue="43043" author="denyeart" type="comment" body="This is too broad for a story. If you would like to pursue, please only a fabric-rfc with proposal: https://github.com/hyperledger/fabric-rfcs/" created="2020-04-19 04:36:00.0" updateauthor="denyeart" updated="2020-04-19 04:36:00.0"/>
