<Issue id="19849" key="IA-24" number="24" project="10602" reporter="avkrishnan" assignee="avkrishnan" creator="avkrishnan" type="10001" summary="As a CLI user I should be able to approve a connection request" description="Given I&apos;ve received a connection request: 1. I should be able to see that I have a connection request1.1 I should be able to see information about the requester 2. I should be able to approve/accept the connection request3. The requester should be notified that I accepted the connection request. 4. If I &quot;deny&quot; the connection request, nothing should happen.5. If I accept the connection request, I should have a secure connection established between me (the CLI user) and the other Identity (could be another CLI user acting as another institution or individual Identity Owner).Suggested text for incoming connection request: &quot;New connection request from  requester&apos;s DID OR user-friendly name for that DID . Type &quot;approve&quot; to approve or &quot;deny&quot; to deny. Type &quot;request connection help&quot; for more information.&quot;6. Typing &quot;request connection help&quot; should show me some more helpful information about what approving or denying a connection does. Some example explaining text: &quot;Approving a connection request will add the requester to your list of connections. You can message and share verifiable claims and proofs with connections.&quot;&quot;Denying a request will ignore the connection request, and the requester will not be notified.&quot;&quot;You can remove a connection by typing  __________ &quot;*POA*_Assumptions_* Incoming connection request handler add connection request to link in the same way as `load` command adds info to links._POA steps_* Once user sees any incoming connection request in CLI. User can issue an `accept invitation` command.* Check if receiver user is not a SPONSOR, then we can&apos;t add incoming identifier on sovrin, in this case use incoming identifier as it is." priority="3" resolution="10300" status="10001" created="2017-08-02 09:27:23.0" updated="2019-09-18 15:26:22.0" resolutiondate="2019-09-18 15:26:22.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="19849"/>
