<Issue id="30784" key="FABC-232" number="232" project="10607" reporter="pandrejko" assignee="skarim" creator="pandrejko" type="10004" summary="Fix formatting issues with new Fabric-CA content" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2018-05-31 17:33:58.0" updated="2018-07-18 22:03:58.0" resolutiondate="2018-06-06 14:57:56.0" votes="0" watches="2" workflowId="32412"> <description><! CDATA  https://hyperledger-fabric-ca.readthedocs.io/en/latest/users-guide.html#manage-certificates   In the source use double back tics ``x`` to surround text instead of single  or double quotes and it will format. better. For example change:  If the caller possesses the 'hf.Registrar.Roles’ attribute or the ‘hf.Revoker’ attribute with a value of ‘true’, all certificates which belong to identities in and below the caller’s affiliation. For example, if the client’s affiliation is “a.b”, the client may get certificates for identities who’s affiliation is “a.b” or “a.b.c” but not “a” or “a.c"  -to-  If the caller possesses the ``hf.Registrar.Roles`` attribute or the ``hf.Revoker’attribute`` with a value of ``true``, all certificates which belong to identities in and below the caller’s affiliation. For example, if the client’s affiliation is ``a.b``, the client may get certificates for identities who’s affiliation is ``a.b`` or ``a.b.c`` but not ``a`` or ``a.c``     The following information needs to be formatted into a list  ID: List certificates for this enrollment ID Serial Number: List certificates that have this serial number AKI: List certificates that have this AKI Expiration Time: List certificates that have expiration dates that fall within this expiration time Revocation Time: List certificates that were revoked within this revocation time  Suggest adding an asterisk at the beginning (to get a bulletized list): * ``ID``: List certificates for this enrollment ID  * ``Serial Number``: List certificates that have this serial number  * ``AKI``: List certificates that have this AKI  * ``Expiration Time`` : List certificates that have expiration dates that fall within this expiration time  * ``Revocation Time``: List certificates that were revoked within this revocation time     Change:  *There are two other filters that will further filter your results.*  to  There are other filters on the certificate status that will further filter your results: ``expiration `` , ``  notrevoked`` and `` notexpired``.  And maybe say a few words about  usage for each one like you did above.     For the following line, you need a blank line between  (admin):  and  .. code:: bash  And make sure there is a blank line after .. code:: bash  *List all certificates that have not been revoked for an id (admin): .. code:: bash*     Change  A CA name can be specified on the command line of a client command as follows:  to  _A CA name can be specified on the command line of a client command using the_  _``caname`` filter as follows:_     And when they specify the CA name does it have to be in quotes of any kind? (Not sure if a CA name can have spaces or special characters in it? Probably not.)     ></description> </Issue>
