<Action id="39456" issue="27282" author="skarim" type="comment" body="https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/#/c/17387/" created="2018-01-31 19:47:48.0" updateauthor="skarim" updated="2018-01-31 19:47:48.0"/>
<Action id="39848" issue="27282" author="smithbk" type="comment" created="2018-02-08 12:49:15.0" updateauthor="smithbk" updated="2018-02-08 12:49:15.0"> <body><! CDATA Is there a present bug or problem that we are trying to solve?  Supporting multi-valued attributes is I think a good thing, which is what we already do.  Folks could always implement by making the value a comma-separated string for example, but then adding to the list atomically becomes impossible because it requires reading the current value, appending to it, and writing the new value.  There is no way to handle collisions in this case, but by supporting multi-valued attributes, we make it possible to atomically add to a list.  That said, I agree there are holes in the current implementation and we should consider exactly what we support now and how and document it well and what we support in the future.  Consider the following attribute types: single value, list value (which allows duplicate values), or set value (does not allow duplicate values). Then consider how we specify how to add, modify, or delete an attribute of each type. We could allow them to specify the attribute type, or I think perhaps we could do so with modifying only the structure that is passed into the identity modify operation. For example, it could have the following fields for an attribute: name, old_value, new_value, allow_duplicates. If only name and new_value are specified, remove all values for the attribute and add the new_value. If name, old_value and new_value are specified, find the old_value and replace with new_value. if only name and old_value are specified, find the old_value and delete it.  This needs more thought, but hopefully this spurs conversation.  Again, I think we could consider simply documenting the current behavior now and supporting others in the future, unless there is an urgent problem for us to address now.  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="39890" issue="27282" author="skarim" type="comment" body="After talking in person, it was decided that this is not a bug and should be allowed. This behavior will be documented instead. " created="2018-02-08 21:42:23.0" updateauthor="skarim" updated="2018-02-08 21:42:23.0"/>
