<Issue id="33958" key="INDY-1708" number="1708" project="10303" reporter="mgbailey" creator="esplinr" type="10001" summary="POA: Delegate issuance to a processor" priority="2" resolution="10001" status="10001" created="2018-09-20 20:12:35.0" updated="2019-03-29 20:35:51.0" resolutiondate="2019-03-29 20:35:51.0" votes="0" watches="8" workflowId="45275"> <description><! CDATA *Story* As an organization issuing claims on an Indy network, I want to be able to delegate the issuing of credentials to a third party so that I benefit from them simplifying my business processes. Verifiers of those credentials should see that they came from me as the controller, but should also be able to identify the processor for audit purposes.  *Requirements* * The controller should be able to change processors by updating the credential definition, but the history of processors should be retained.  *Acceptance Criteria* * Create a plan * Get architectural review of the plan from stakeholders including Evernym and the Sovrin Foundation * Create the necessary issues  *Possible Approaches*  _Add issuer field to cred def transactions_ When using delegation, where one company (the processor) issues credentials for another (the controller), to the verifier the claims appear to have come from the controller.  This is fine, but we also need to be able to tell that the processor was involved with issuing the claim.   To do this, please add an additional field to cred def transactions called "issuer".  The value of the field will be a DID that will be set by the controller before it is written to the ledger.  In addition it will be necessary for the verifier to be able to determine what cred def was used to make the claim in the proof. In the current proof format, the schema sequence number is provided for each claim, but the cred def sequence number is not. Other than parsing the ledger to find the cred def with a particular "ref" and "identifier", which would be very inefficient, there is not an apparent way for the verifier to find the correct cred def. If indeed there currently is no better way, then please also add a cred def sequence number to the claims in a proof.  It will then be the responsibility of the verifier to retrieve the cred def from the ledger to determine the processor, when needed. Two very key customers currently need this capability, with more to follow.  The additional field in the cred def allows the controller to show that he has delegated proof issuance to the processor who actually holds the private keys to the cred def.  *Notes* This story introduces a new participant in credential verification. The 3-party story (issuer, prover, and verifier) is modified into a 4-party story, where the issuer is split into 2, the controller and the processor. Both will need DIDs on the network, so that the verifier is able to see that the credential is from the controller, by means of the processor.  ></description> </Issue>
