<Issue id="46528" key="FABN-1698" number="1698" project="10604" reporter="JIRAUSER20631" creator="JIRAUSER20631" type="10002" summary="Is it possible to package the Hyperledger Fabric chaincode using the node SDK?" priority="3" resolution="10001" status="6" created="2021-02-01 16:40:23.0" updated="2021-04-23 01:44:42.0" resolutiondate="2021-02-09 14:55:25.0" votes="0" watches="5" workflowId="60471" archived="N"> <description><! CDATA I use hyperledger fabric V1.4.10 I created a deployer app that installs and upgrades my chaincode using the node SDK API and everything works great but I am storing all my project compressed in a zip file as an artifact and I would like to have a smaller artifact to store, off course I'm adding the node modules, the js and the ts files, as I'm not completely sure if they are needed or not during deployment.  I would like to be able to do the same that is done using "peer chaincode package" from my deployer app to be able to package my code in an efficient way.  I have seen in the SDK a  BasePackager|https://hyperledger.github.io/fabric-sdk-node/release-1.4/BasePackager.html#toc0__anchor  class that seems to be able to package the code, but I can´t find any examples of how to use it.  Also looking inside the js code I found that the install method can receive a ChaincodeInstallRequest that can be a ChaincodePackageInstallRequest or a ChaincodePathInstallRequest.  Here's the code inside index.d.ts:   {code:javascript}  export interface ChaincodePackageInstallRequest { targets?: Peer   | string  ; channelNames?: string   | string; txId?: TransactionId; chaincodePackage: Buffer; }  export interface ChaincodePathInstallRequest { targets?: Peer   | string  ; channelNames?: string   | string; txId?: TransactionId; chaincodeId: string; chaincodeVersion: string; chaincodePath: string; chaincodeType?: ChaincodeType; metadataPath?: string; }  export type ChaincodeInstallRequest = ChaincodePackageInstallRequest | ChaincodePathInstallRequest;  {code}  So I was wondering, is it possible to use the SDK to package your code? or should I use the "peer chaincode package" option instead? Also, after packaging my code, can I use the SDK to install it? or do I need to do it using the "peer chaincode install" option better?  Thanks  ></description> </Issue>
