<Issue id="44416" key="IS-1508" number="1508" project="10401" reporter="ashcherbakov" assignee="danielhardman" creator="ashcherbakov" type="10002" summary="Support presentation of W3C credentials in indy-credx" priority="3" status="10200" created="2020-02-26 04:27:55.0" updated="2020-05-21 23:31:22.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="58324" archived="N"> <description><! CDATA *Acceptance criteria* - Implement methods for presentation workflow for W3C credentials with Rich Schema support - Implementation should live in indy-credx (we consider options to do it in aries-credx as well) - This can be a new set of methods (not overriding existing ones) - presentation needs to be in W3C compatible format (see https://www.w3.org/TR/vc-data-model/#zero-knowledge-proofs) - builders for presentation definition are not required (pres def can be passed as a JSON the same way proof request is passed now) - we are going to support Presentation Definition version 0.5 which will have feature parity with existing proof request. Pres Def is going to be evolved, so that needs to be taken into account in implementation (different strategies?) - If we do JSON-LD processing/substitution, then for MVP we may assume that we resolve the contexts (substitute the fields belonging to a context) belonging to the current ledger only. We are not going to resolve other Indy ledger's context, other blockchain's contexts, and Internet contexts.  *HIPEs/RFCs to use* - https://github.com/hyperledger/aries-rfcs/tree/master/features/0037-present-proof (to be updated) - https://github.com/hyperledger/aries-rfcs/tree/master/concepts/0250-rich-schemas, https://github.com/hyperledger/indy-hipe/tree/master/text/0119-rich-schemas - https://github.com/hyperledger/aries-rfcs/tree/master/concepts/0420-rich-schemas-common, https://github.com/hyperledger/indy-hipe/tree/master/text/0120-rich-schemas-common - https://github.com/hyperledger/aries-rfcs/tree/master/features/0249-rich-schema-contexts, https://github.com/hyperledger/indy-hipe/tree/master/text/0138-rich-schema-context (to be updated) - https://github.com/hyperledger/aries-rfcs/tree/master/features/0281-rich-schemas, https://github.com/hyperledger/indy-hipe/tree/master/text/0149-rich-schema-schema (to be updated) - https://github.com/hyperledger/aries-rfcs/tree/master/features/0418-rich-schema-encoding (to be updated) - Mapping (TBD) - CredDef (TBD) - PresDef (TBD) - Credentials format (TBD) - Presentation format (TBD)    ></description> </Issue>
