<Issue id="17337" key="FABN-556" number="556" project="10604" reporter="jimthematrix" assignee="harrisob@us.ibm.com" creator="jimthematrix" type="10004" summary="Code cleanup" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2017-05-31 18:59:15.0" updated="2018-07-19 00:54:30.0" resolutiondate="2017-06-06 02:06:09.0" votes="5" watches="3" workflowId="34287" security="10001"> <description><! CDATA General code clean up. Removing unused methods, properties. Moving internal static methods out of classes and make them module-scoped functions so they don't get exposed.  *Unused methods* - Channel.js - buildChannelConfig(): _*already taken out of documented APIs*_, just remove the actual implementation. this is from the attempt to support channel creation from JSON input without relying on configtxgen. later on we changed direction to only support binary input from configtxgen (FAB-1678) - buildChannelConfigUpdate(): same as above - isReadonly(): meant to indicate if the channel has been terminated (no new blocks), never implemented - Client.js - newMSP(): was used by the JSON-input based create channel and update channel - buildChannelConfigUpdate(): same as the one in Channel.js above - buildChannelConfig(): same as the one in Channel.js above  *Static methods to take out of the class and made module-scoped* These are currently static with a "_" prefix which indicates they are not public API, but they are still exposed by the module because they are part of the class. Would like to move them out of the class and change to functions in the same module, so they would not pollute the API (because client can't call them any longer). - Channel.js - static _sendPeersProposal():  - static _signProposal() - static _checkProposalRequest() - static _checkInstallRequest() - static _buildChannelHeader() - static _buildHeader() - static _buildCurrentTimestamp() - static _translateCCType()  *Unused properties* - Channel.js - _securityEnabled: hold-over from 0.6 concept (used to not require signatures on requests), never used and not applicable anymore  *Unused class* - ChannelConfig.js: not needed any longer because this class is dedicated to JSON-based input for channel creation/update, which we are not doing anymore.   ></description> </Issue>
