<Action id="20181" issue="13875" author="jonathanlevi" type="comment" created="2016-12-21 21:50:21.0" updateauthor="jonathanlevi" updated="2016-12-21 21:50:21.0"> <body><! CDATA Here's the original exchange from Slack:   *#general*  atom  10:01 AM    Well, I just had a nice adventure getting hfc to build on Windows 10...  :disappointed:  jonathanlevi  11:24 AM    @atom: Can you share more details? (say in #fabric-dev or #fabric ?) How was it? :wink:   *#fabric-dev#   atom  12:30 PM    @jonathanlevi  It was kind of rough.  Seems most of the issues revolved around the hashtable package, and the native compiler setup it needs.  As I fought through the errors, *I had to install Python (2.7 version, as the 3.0 version didn't work)*, then I had to* install the Windows 8.1 SDK*, but that doesn't include the compiler that was needed, so I had to* install Visual Studio 2013 Express edition*.  *Previously I had set a npm config setting to try and use VS2015, so I had to reset that to be msvs_version=2015, so i had to reset that to 2013*.  Whew...  Figuring out what was needed at each step consisted of some luck and a lot of google'n.   12:30    oh, btw...  for folks not in the general channel, that's related to installing the hfc package from npm for the SDK-Demo project.  garisingh  12:59 PM    @atom - I guess we need to add https://github.com/felixrieseberg/windows-build-tools  to the docs for hfc.  This makes it a snap to install the prereqs required on Windows for installing / compiling node packages with native code  atom  1:03 PM    I believe I installed those as well :slightly_smiling_face:   1:03    thanks for reminding me so that I can update my notes. :slightly_smiling_face:   1:06    bummer...  Now when I ry to run "node helloblockchain.js" I get the following error:  Error: Cannot find module 'C:\Users\....\...\SDK-Demo\node_modules\grpc\src\node\extension_binary\grpc_node.node'  atom  1:23 PM    Gave a shot at updating to grpc@1.0.1 (latest)..  seemed to get further on the 'node helloblockchain.js', but still threw an error:  Enrolled admin sucecssfully events.js:160 throw er; // Unhandled 'error' event ^  Error at ClientDuplexStream._emitStatusIfDone (C:\Users\...\...\SDK-Demo\node_modules\hfc\node_modules\grpc\src\node\src\client.js:189:19)  jonathanlevi  1:31 PM    @atom First of all, thanks for this. I haven’t used Windows in quite a while, but I agree, we should collect this and document. Shall we try to summarize these steps together? I can give it a shot and run it by you...  And then we’ll get someone else, who’s completely new to this (that would “the old you”, before going through this ;-))… and see if he/she can simply follow these steps.  atom  1:34 PM    @jonathanlevi  Sounds good to me, at least once I get it actually running. :slightly_smiling_face: I'm recording my steps, and I'd like to retry the steps on a fresh machine to make sure I've got it right.  jonathanlevi  1:35 PM    Not a problem. We can iterate on it. I’m just trying to use the “momentum”, while you are at it… and capture this. It’s good feedback. Certainly.  atom  1:36 PM    I've set a reminder to circle back around on this next week (after the holiday and all)  jonathanlevi  1:37 PM    OK. If you don’t mind me Copying & Pasting this, I will quickly open a JIRA item…. (Not legally binding :-))  atom  1:38 PM    not a problem at all.  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="22438" issue="13875" author="christopherferris" type="comment" body=" ~jimthematrix  if this is no longer relevant, please mark WONTFIX and close. Thanks" created="2017-04-14 11:55:23.0" updateauthor="christopherferris" updated="2017-04-14 11:55:23.0"/>
