<Action id="30236" issue="20069" author="troyronda" type="comment" created="2017-08-26 16:47:16.0" updateauthor="troyronda" updated="2017-08-26 17:29:26.0"> <body><! CDATA Regarding the multi-arch discussion initiated in gerrit.  One of the initial thoughts on handling multi-arch was to include cross-compiled versions of all the consortium's supported platforms in the package sent by install. However, it was viewed as less complex to simply include one target architecture.  Since the install command is targeted to a particular peer, the client needs to send the appropriate architecture within each individual call to install@peer. Effectively some of the complexity to the administrative client to select the correct package to send to the peer (and to expose each peer's architecture via config and discovery).  Regarding the llvm discussion initiated in gerrit.  I think that supporting some additional platforms via byte code has merit as additional stories. However the binary approach offers flexibility, less initial complexity, and allows for more obvious (production) support of precompiled Go codebases. So I think the byte code idea doesn't replace the binary option that was done as the first implementation.  Really the platform should simply support the consortium's choices in how to apply their business processes to the current state. Those processes meet an interface and the gears turn :).  It's up to each consortium to determine their own policies around source distribution, code review, implementation certification.  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="55531" issue="20069" author="k.ramankishore" type="comment" created="2019-01-11 12:31:33.0" updateauthor="k.ramankishore" updated="2019-01-11 12:47:44.0"> <body><! CDATA I'm sorry if I'm asking a redundant question.  Was this change implemented? Can users install pre compiled binary chaincode now by adding the flag "-l binary" to peer install command?  Is there any documentation for this?  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="55532" issue="20069" author="k.ramankishore" type="comment" created="2019-01-11 12:52:24.0" updateauthor="k.ramankishore" updated="2019-01-11 12:52:24.0"> <body><! CDATA If this is not implemented, can someone please explain me the thought process behind taking this decision?  Thanks!  ></body> </Action>
