<Action id="49190" issue="32859" author="joe-alewine" type="comment" created="2018-08-21 19:44:36.0" updateauthor="joe-alewine" updated="2018-08-21 19:44:36.0"> <body><! CDATA Comments from  ~EdProsser  and myself about this:     Ed: Basically, if you start a link with a / it starts looking at the root of the tree, but the root in our case would be /en/release-1.2/_static/images/github_button.png At least, from memory it's something like that And then that change would only fix that release.  Edward Prosser  3:52 AM  The core problem is that layout.html is applied to every document when they're resolved to html And because some of the docs are at differing levels in the directory structure, the image link breaks. There are 3 possible fixes that I can see which will also fix for all potential versions and potential translations.  Edward Prosser  3:57 AM  1. Change the build system so that layout.html is resolved first somehow. I don't really know too much about the docs build for fabric, but this might be difficult.  Edward Prosser  3:59 AM  2. Keep the image links as they are, but move all docs into one directory, this would work, but is a little brute force and I'm not a big fan. It is the lowest effort solution though.  Edward Prosser  4:01 AM  3. Make the image links resolve correctly for the docs in subdirectories by adding a `../` to the link. Then move all docs into subdirectories grouped by topic or chapter. This is the middle effort solution but I suspect we'll run into problems with the landing pages for each chapter being outside the folders. I might grab a dev from Hursley to have a look and recommend a solution. (edited)     Me: Personally, #1 is ideal. #2 is a hard no. And #3, while preferable to #2, would still present huge challenges given the upside (making some image icons look better).      ~rameshthoomu , what is the feasibility of ensuring that layout.html resolves first?  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="53299" issue="32859" author="rameshthoomu" type="comment" created="2018-11-12 06:20:04.0" updateauthor="rameshthoomu" updated="2018-11-12 06:20:04.0"> <body><! CDATA  ~pandrejko  This seems fixed with this change  https://github.com/hyperledger/fabric/commit/5d9d96d898d61e9196274388e795e63d30d66ca2   Could you please confirm  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="54044" issue="32859" author="rameshthoomu" type="comment" created="2018-11-30 04:42:05.0" updateauthor="rameshthoomu" updated="2018-11-30 04:42:05.0"> <body><! CDATA This issue is addressed here  https://github.com/hyperledger/fabric/commit/5d9d96d898d61e9196274388e795e63d30d66ca2   Closing this issue. Please open new issue if you see again.  ></body> </Action>
