<Action id="47487" issue="29991" author="smithbk" type="comment" created="2018-07-18 14:07:13.0" updateauthor="smithbk" updated="2018-07-18 14:07:13.0"> <body><! CDATA Here are some notes for things which should be in the doc ... and/or questions to be answered.  1) Overview Why use it?  Benefits: anonymity (within an MSP), unlinkability, ZKP, etc.  2) How to configure MSP a) idemix MSP is not supported for local MSPs, right?  Make sure folks know this means you must use an ecert to do anything that involves local MSPs (install chaincode, join channel, etc).  We ran into this in doing the end-to-end. b) Best practices for how many idemix MSPs you should have per channel.  The current idemix MSP allows only a single IssuerPublicKey which seems to imply that you might have two MSPs per org: one x509 and one idemix.  Or I can imagine a channel with N number of orgs and only one idemix MSP which is cross org.  For example, you could have a channel of companies which allow end users to transact based on their driver's license.  In this case, you would have one x509 MSP per company and one idemix MSP for the DMV.  Anyway, we should discuss MSP configuration in the context of user stories like this.  And I also think we should consider allowing multiple IssuerPublicKeys in a single idemix MSP.  This would allow us to always have a single idemix MSP per channel for anonymity.  We would have to figure out authorization for config updates would work with that model.  3) Java SDK APIs Discuss the HFCAClient.idemixEnroll which gets an idemix credential given an ecert.   Include a code snippet, and reference where this is done in the End2endIT sample.  Is there a java-based fabric sample that could be enhanced to include this?    ></body> </Action>
<Action id="47733" issue="29991" author="smithbk" type="comment" created="2018-07-24 16:18:19.0" updateauthor="smithbk" updated="2018-07-24 16:18:19.0"> <body><! CDATA To elaborate on 2b above ...  Suppose a channel has two orgs (org1 and org2) each with their own fabric CA (CA1 and CA2), Each CA has a unique issuer X509 certificate  as well as a unique idemix IssuerPublicKey. The channel config will have two x509 MSPs, one for org1 and one for org2, but it would be desirable for privacy reasons for the channel to have only a single idemix MSP. This does not appear to be possible today because an MSP can only have a single IssuerPublicKey.  I suggest changing the MSP structure to allow multiple IssuerPublicKeys. In addition, the update policy of the IssuerPublicKey should not allow an admin from org1 to update the IssuerPublicKey from org2.  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="47734" issue="29991" author="clayton sims" type="comment" body="cc&apos;ing   ~pandrejko  " created="2018-07-24 16:57:52.0" updateauthor="clayton sims" updated="2018-07-24 16:57:52.0"/>
<Action id="50843" issue="29991" author="dubovitskaya" type="comment" body="https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/#/c/26382/" created="2018-09-20 14:29:32.0" updateauthor="dubovitskaya" updated="2018-09-20 14:29:32.0"/>
