<Action id="31937" issue="21288" author="dongming" type="comment" created="2017-10-09 15:55:59.0" updateauthor="dongming" updated="2017-10-09 15:55:59.0"> <body><! CDATA # update PTE to work with connection profile (1 week) # test with 2-3 test cases (1 week)  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="32022" issue="21288" author="scottz" type="comment" created="2017-10-11 22:24:46.0" updateauthor="scottz" updated="2017-10-11 22:24:46.0"> <body><! CDATA Revised plan: # add the existing sdk-node TC in CI , but do it while generating artifacts # add a 2nd version of the test, with many different config values # later in v1.1 we will integrate changes into PTE tool (this will take more than 2 weeks), to use this connection profile for numerous tests  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="32106" issue="21288" author="scottz" type="comment" created="2017-10-13 15:35:08.0" updateauthor="scottz" updated="2017-10-13 15:35:08.0"> <body><! CDATA Revised Plan:  This "feature" is really just a tool, consisting of scripts, and a simple test that uses them. The fabric-sdk-node repo contains the developer's test and baked materials to run it as part of the UT. Too many steps are hidden.  The goal of our "testing" this feature should be to ensure its usability. We should review docs, and readme in code source directory. We must ensure directions are clear, step-by-step actions to * prepare artifiacts to bring up network (create a new fixtures directory, edit configtx.yaml in their directory, run cryptogen and configtxgen...to create the output flies with file names as currently used by their existing test, move the mychannel.tx, orgs.genesis.block files to the fabric-sdk-node/test/fixtures/ directories) * when actual commands are not available because of manual reading and editing, explain what corresponding changes must be done - e.g. editing network.yaml and docker-compose.yaml and other connection-profile yaml files, to use the output files generated in prior steps * also explain how to start the new network and run simple test using their test framework; how to run the existing test can be used as a model  Do we want to modify the BYFN instructions to use this???  We can follow those steps ourselves, manually, to test it now, and provide further feedback on the documentation.  Longterm, we could modify test tools to use these templates automatically, in order to run many tests in the CI; but to do that, we need to see how a user would do it each step of the way. But this is not part of the required testing for this feature.  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="35502" issue="21288" author="scottz" type="comment" body="The Composer team is using this heavily and covering the testing required." created="2017-11-27 15:45:20.0" updateauthor="scottz" updated="2017-11-27 15:45:20.0"/>
<Action id="62480" issue="21288" author="scottz" type="comment" body="connection profile is not being used in yaml and json forms." created="2019-08-01 02:12:37.0" updateauthor="scottz" updated="2019-08-01 02:12:37.0"/>
