<Action id="52709" issue="34842" author="kchristidis" type="comment" body=" ~yacovm : Thanks for coming up with this solution and writing it up. I think we should go for it." created="2018-10-27 02:00:00.0" updateauthor="kchristidis" updated="2018-10-27 02:00:00.0"/>
<Action id="52711" issue="34842" author="yacovm" type="comment" body="All right. I&apos;ll put it in the pipeline after my current line of work of FAB-12555" created="2018-10-27 12:42:44.0" updateauthor="yacovm" updated="2018-10-27 12:42:44.0"/>
<Action id="52713" issue="34842" author="yacovm" type="comment" created="2018-10-27 15:29:16.0" updateauthor="yacovm" updated="2018-10-27 15:29:16.0"> <body><! CDATA I thought it over some more, and I just want to mention that there is another way of solving the problem without having a separate listener, - by tweaking the TLS server and give it a split personality - to have 2 certificates instead of 1, and to return to clients the let's-encrypt certificate and to ordering nodes- the "other" certificate. Currently, the TLS CA certificate pool is computed from the union of the local TLS CA certificates and the channel TLS CA certificates.  The problem is that we can't use let's encrypt certificates for intra-cluster communication, and the idea that I proposed it to have a separate listener.  But maybe instead of having 2 TLS listeners with different TLS CA certificate pools, why not just combine the TLS CA pool (the let's encrypt CA certs and the organizational orderer CA certs) into a single pool, and just send different TLS certificates based on the client hello (if applicable)?  This is not obvious, as it is not clear how to classify a TLS client certificate as an orderer node certificate in a way that is generic enough for deployments in environments we don't know, as clients and servers may accidentally have TLS certificates issued by the same CA.   Nevertheless I am still listing this option here, for completeness (or if someone has anything to add/suggest).   ~kchristidis   ~mastersingh24    ></body> </Action>
<Action id="54732" issue="34842" author="yacovm" type="comment" body="https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/#/c/28107/" created="2018-12-12 17:21:27.0" updateauthor="yacovm" updated="2018-12-12 17:21:27.0"/>
