<Action id="39629" issue="27405" author="yacovm" type="comment" created="2018-02-04 22:53:24.0" updateauthor="yacovm" updated="2018-02-04 23:04:37.0"> <body><! CDATA {quote}flexible ways to specify an endorsement policy during instantiation (e.g., "*.Admin" instead of "Org0.Admin or Org1.Admin"... of course this needs dynamic evaluation at commit time){quote}  Well we have these in channel reconfiguration and membership, they are meta-policies (I think).  I don't think it's hard to just have the policy be a marshaled meta-policy instead of a signature policy and it should work I believe.   ~jyellick  could elaborate on this, I believe.  {quote}ability to set the endorsement policy separately. This is trickier as the EP is part of the chaincode fingerprint{quote} If we didn't rollback the resource based lifecycle work, we could have that for free (from v1.2 point of view)... I think we should adopt a similar approach in the long run and take out the policy from the fingerprint. The fingerprint is there to ensure the chaincode of the channel is what you have installed locally, no?   {quote}Named endorsers is brittle wrt adding organizations{quote} What do you mean brittle?  {quote}In the real world endorsement often depends on data content, asset ownership, etc.{quote} Right, but how do you link content and asset ownership to peers? The endorsement is just an attestation of a mandatory witness (peers from the right org) for an execution of a smart contract. In the end, the executor is a peer or a set of peers. How do you link from the business logic point of view, that such and such peers are eligible of endorsing? Peers don't own assets, users own them.  {quote}Current default endorsement policy default is entirely inadequate and allows arbitrary state manipulation even without executing chaincode{quote} What would you suggest the new default to be? Why do we even need a default, by the way? Can't we just not have one? I know we have a pseudo default for SCCs but that's another story...  {quote}Providing a good dynamic default of all orgs is impossible{quote} That's why I think there shouldn't be one :)  {quote}Key based endorsement policies{quote} I guess that means that the peer that endorsed, is the owner? Or is there a different idea?  {quote}Endorsement policies based on preimage and or postimage{quote} Of what function? Can you elaborate? And postimage is just image, no?  Finally, another thing I would like to say is that though it's true that if you add a new org to the channel, and you want the peers of that org to be endorsers - you need to upgrade the chaincode and that's an overhead, but I don't think that just using meta-policies (majority of orgs) is a silver bullet. In fact, the only use case where that is suitable for, is if you have several orgs and you want an endorsement from a majority just to make sure peers are not cheating you about their results.  I'm sure that in many use cases, not all orgs can endorse all chaincodes, because organizations have business meaning behind them, and not all businesses provide the same services.    ></body> </Action>
<Action id="45558" issue="27405" author="ashishkumarlakshmanan" type="comment" body="By &quot;Endorsement policy specified per chaincode function&quot;, the intent is to do this endorsement at the &quot;function&quot; which comes as the o/p of go-shim API, *function, args := stub.GetFunctionAndParameters()* . Correct ?" created="2018-06-06 01:22:27.0" updateauthor="ashishkumarlakshmanan" updated="2018-06-06 01:22:27.0"/>
<Action id="51730" issue="27405" author="denyeart" type="comment" created="2018-10-04 04:57:47.0" updateauthor="denyeart" updated="2018-10-04 05:11:45.0"> <body><! CDATA  ~jyellick  I've added this to the v2.0 lifecycle epic for your consideration. Would you prefer to carry it as a separate epic?  Or split into smaller stories under the existing lifecycle epic?  In my opinion, some progress must be made here and v2.0 would be the logical target to go hand-in-hand with the new lifecycle.  I believe there has been discussion of some improvements such as "instead of named organizations in the endorsement policy, allow any 1 org, any 2 orgs, majority of orgs, etc". FAB-12292 has again highlighted this need.  Anyways, would appreciate your thoughts on which pieces would make the most sense in which timeframe.  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="57988" issue="27405" author="jyellick" type="comment" body="I&apos;m going to close this out, I think we&apos;ve addressed this in the new lifecycle." created="2019-03-07 17:58:51.0" updateauthor="jyellick" updated="2019-03-07 17:58:51.0"/>
<Action id="57989" issue="27405" author="jyellick" type="comment" body="I&apos;m going to close this out, I think we&apos;ve addressed this in the new lifecycle." created="2019-03-07 17:59:06.0" updateauthor="jyellick" updated="2019-03-07 17:59:06.0"/>
