<Issue id="27405" key="FAB-8053" number="8053" project="10002" reporter="muralisr" creator="muralisr" type="10001" summary="Enhancements to endorsement policies" priority="2" resolution="10002" status="6" created="2018-02-04 17:19:44.0" updated="2019-03-07 17:59:41.0" resolutiondate="2019-03-07 17:59:41.0" votes="3" watches="12" workflowId="35518"> <description><! CDATA There are several improvements that can be made to endorsement policies. To start with the simplest, endorsement policy for a chaincode is specified at the time of instantiation. There is no way to update except to do an "upgrade" using a different endorsement policy. This could be a workaround but has the following drawbacks * disrupts service  * user have to go through the instantiation process just to update a policy   One example of need to update the policy is when the channel membership changes. A new member may not have invoke capability based on existing endorsement policy (see --FAB-5893--).   We could consider two types of enhancements just in terms of * flexible ways to specify an endorsement policy during instantiation ** e.g., "*.Admin" instead of "Org0.Admin or Org1.Admin"... of course this needs dynamic evaluation at commit time) ** e.g. instead of named organizations in the endorsement policy, allow any 1 org, any 2 orgs, majority of orgs, etc. (see FAB-12292) * ability to set the endorsement policy separately. This is trickier as the EP is part of the chaincode fingerprint  Beyond the above "update" requirement, there are several other enhancements that can be considered. From a list gathered from elsewhere * Named endorsers is brittle wrt adding organizations * In the real world endorsement often depends on data content, asset ownership, etc. (see FAB-8812) * With multiple similar chaincodes managing endorsement policy individually is painful * Current default endorsement policy default is entirely inadequate and allows arbitrary state manipulation even without executing chaincode * Endorsement policy is tied to chaincode version so modifications require installing a second copy of the chaincode at a new version * Providing a good dynamic default of all orgs is impossible * Endorsement policy specified per chaincode function  Ideas: * Key based endorsement policies (see FAB-8812) * Endorsement policies by reference rather than by literal * Endorsement policies based on preimage and or postimage  ></description> </Issue>
