<Issue id="40205" key="INDY-2113" number="2113" project="10303" reporter="vladimirwork" assignee="vladimirwork" creator="vladimirwork" type="10002" summary="DOC: Request for release notes on Indy-node 1.8.0" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="10001" created="2019-05-29 16:13:44.0" updated="2019-06-01 09:42:08.0" resolutiondate="2019-06-01 09:42:08.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="53108"> <description><! CDATA *Version Information:* indy-node 1.8.0 indy-plenum 1.8.0 sovrin 1.1.45  *Notices for Stewards:* (!) Payment transaction can return NACK from the pool but in fact it will be eventually ordered (see more details below). (!) There are possible OOM issues during 3+ hours of target load or large catch-ups at 8 GB RAM nodes pool so 32 GB is recommended. (!) Pool upgrade to sovrin 1.1.32 and above should be performed simultaneously for all nodes due to txn format changes. (!) Pool upgrade to indy-node 1.8.0 should be performed simultaneously for all nodes due to audit ledger.  *Major Changes* - Add Transaction Author Agreement Acceptance Mechanisms and Transaction Author Agreement support - Configurable Auth rules improvements - Stability fixes  *Detailed Changelog*  +Fixes:+ INDY-2064 - Issues with catch up and ordering under the load INDY-2078 - Editing of CLAIM_DEF uses auth rules for Adding a Claim Def INDY-1709 - Faulty primary can order and write already ordered and written request  +Changes and Additions:+ INDY-2102 - As a Network Admin, I would like to use GET_AUTH_RULE output as an input for AUTH_RULE INDY-2071 - Get Transaction Author Agreement Acceptance Mechanisms from the Config Ledger INDY-2072 - Support Transaction Author Agreement in Write Requests INDY-2073 - Validate transaction author agreement as part of consensus INDY-2066 - Write Transaction Author Agreement to Config Ledger INDY-2067 - Get Transaction Author Agreement from the config ledger INDY-2068 - Write Transaction Author Agreement Acceptance Mechanisms to the Config Ledger INDY-2053 - Catch-up should take into account state of other nodes when sending requests  +Known Issues:+ INDY-2122 - A client may receive NACK for a payment transfer request, but the transaction will be eventually ordered (payment transferred) INDY-2024 - Incorrect auth constraint for node demotion  ></description> </Issue>
