<Action id="55887" issue="36920" author="ashcherbakov" type="comment" created="2019-01-21 07:19:34.0" updateauthor="ashcherbakov" updated="2019-01-21 07:19:34.0"> <body><! CDATA  ~esplinr  I'm not sure that this task is really critical because of 2 reasons: 1) If a Steward changes this flag intentionally, then he or she behaves like a malicious actor. So, if the number of such Stewards is less than F, we are fine. If this number is more than F, then RBFT just doesn't work anymore (the same with any other malicious activity).  2) I'm not sure that we need this flag at all, or at least should keep it working the current way. The new approach for multi-signature support should also provide a lot of flexibility for write authorization policy. So that we can control what's required to write a txn to the ledger just by configuring this policies (in config ledger or just in code for the first phase). For example, Indy code can have some default trust-anchor based policies for every operation. Other deployments (for example Sovrin) can extend/override this policies. Indy may require that only a Trust Anchor can write to the ledger. Sovrin can extend the policy saying that either a Trust Anchor OR a user with tokens can write to the ledger. ANYONE_CAN_WRITE will not be required for this anymore.  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="58088" issue="36920" author="ozheregelya" type="comment" created="2019-03-12 13:57:42.0" updateauthor="ozheregelya" updated="2019-03-12 14:02:20.0"> <body><! CDATA (i) For QA: check that following AUTH_RULE command will be rejected: {code:java} ledger custom {"reqId":101,"identifier":"V4SGRU86Z58d6TV7PBUe6f","operation":{"type":"120","constraint":{"constraint_id":"ROLE","role":"101","sig_count":1,"need_to_be_owner":false,"metadata":{}},"field":"role","auth_type":"1","new_value":"*","auth_action":"ADD"},"protocolVersion":2} sign=true {code} See Case 2 from this comment https://jira.hyperledger.org/browse/INDY-1995?focusedCommentId=57973&page=com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.issuetabpanels:comment-tabpanel#comment-57973 for details.  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="60964" issue="36920" author="derashe" type="comment" created="2019-06-13 13:53:42.0" updateauthor="derashe" updated="2019-06-13 13:53:42.0"> <body><! CDATA Problem reason/description:  - We do not need ANYONE_CAN_WRITE flag anymore  Changes:  - ANYONE_CAN_WRITE flag and according functionality excluded  PR: -  https://github.com/hyperledger/indy-node/pull/1345   Version: - will be marked later     Covered with tests: - Test ref on github  Recommendations for QA - Edit acceptance test cases to exclude ANYONE_CAN_WRITE cases  - Check that manual setting of ANYONE_CAN_WRITE do not make any sense to authorisation  ></body> </Action>
