<Issue id="29201" key="FAB-9383" number="9383" project="10002" reporter="tkuhrt" assignee="christopherferris" creator="tkuhrt" type="10004" summary="Resolve licensing issues discovered by Fossology scan" priority="3" resolution="10002" status="6" created="2018-04-05 16:32:58.0" updated="2019-09-24 16:19:34.0" resolutiondate="2019-09-24 16:19:34.0" votes="0" watches="3" workflowId="35674"> <description><! CDATA h1. Context  Hyperledger Fabric source files (from April 3, 2018) were scanned by The Linux Foundation utilizing Fossology to determine license for files contained in the following repositories: *  https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/fabric   *  https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/fabric-baseimage   *  https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/fabric-ca   *  https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/fabric-chaincode-evm   *  https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/fabric-chaincode-java   *  https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/fabric-chaincode-node   *  https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/fabric-chaintool   *  https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/fabric-docs   *  https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/fabric-samples   *  https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/fabric-sdk-go   *  https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/fabric-sdk-java   *  https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/fabric-sdk-node   *  https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/fabric-sdk-py   *  https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/fabric-sdk-rest   *  https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/fabric-test   *  https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/fabric-test-resources   *  https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/homebrew-fabric            From the Hyperledger Charter ( https://www.hyperledger.org/about/charter ) Section 13, all files that are included in Hyperledger projects should either be licensed with the Apache License, Version 2.0 for source code or Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License for documentation. h1. Expected Behavior  All files should have license text included either directly or via a LICENSE file in the directory for files that cannot be modified to include a comment with the license text (think binary files). h1. Actual Behavior  See attached results of the scan. h1. To Fix  There are now three subdirectories in /fabric/vendor/ github.com/docker/docker/contrib/|http://github.com/docker/docker/contrib/  that contain LICENSE files with copies of the GPL-2.0. These directories don't contain any other code, so I'm not clear why the GPL licenses are being included, but these should be removed promptly if possible.  * Note that these appear to be present in the master branch (see  https://github.com/hyperledger/fabric/tree/master/vendor/github.com/docker/docker/contrib/selinux-fedora-24/docker-engine-selinux  for example) but not in the release-1.1 branch.  The package metadata files (generally bower.json / package.json for NPM) incorrectly describe the Hyperledger Fabric as licensed under ISC, rather than Apache. NPM's default is ISC so this is a common mistake. I've highlighted these instances in the attached reports. These files should be changed from ISC to Apache-2.0.  For new files with Attribution license, ideally, we would replace those with Apache 2.0 files and dependencies; otherwise, we will need to go to the Hyperledger Governing board for an exception.  There is one file that contains incomplete license text. We should either expand that to contain the whole license text or use the SPDX Identifier.  For _ALL_ files that do not have a license included, the first step is to check with the contributor to ensure that the file can be released as Apache 2.0 or CC-BY-4.0. If the contributor agrees, the file should be modified to include the license. You can utilize  SPDX Identifiers |https://spdx.org/ to represent the correct license.  For those non-modifiable files, you will need to include a LICENSE file in the directory containing the license that the files are covered by. Here are a few examples of how this might be done: *  OPNFV Apex|https://github.com/opnfv/apex/blob/master/LICENSE.rst  -- this is an example of explicitly calling out Apache 2.0 for source code and CC-BY-4.0 for docs.  *  containerd|https://github.com/containerd/containerd/blob/master/README.md  -- see notice at bottom. This also calls out the separate Apache / CC-BY-4.0 docs, and explicitly references the "docs" directory. h1. *Before closing this bug, please let me know that you have made the above changes. I will then run the code through Fossology again* *to ensure the changes.*  ></description> </Issue>
