<Issue id="31641" key="CE-408" number="408" project="10200" reporter="luckydogchina" assignee="luckydogchina" creator="luckydogchina" type="10006" summary=" A suggestion of the cello project " priority="4" resolution="10000" status="10001" created="2018-07-04 03:59:37.0" updated="2018-09-11 07:29:14.0" resolutiondate="2018-09-11 07:29:14.0" votes="0" watches="2" workflowId="31655"> <description><! CDATA I think that the current management mode of cello as a baas does not conform to the principle of the fabric-chain : Current workflow: 1.The administrator creates a chain: test-chain, initializes all nodes; 2.Users use this chain: alppy test-chain; 3.User Install and manage smart contracts: install and manage chaincodes;  One chain is managed by the user, This mode is like managing  cloud service.This approach violates the principle of blockchains, which does not take advantage of multiple channels. Take  the bitcoin as an example. One user manages a mining pool or a mining machine, not a chain. Why don't we do like this:  1.Users must first register an organization; 2. Administrator creates peer cluster and CA center for users; 3. The originator of the alliance creates an orderer cluster to invite others to join an channel. 4. Other users choose the channel to join, and add their peer cluster and ca node into the channel. Each user is not oriented to a chain, but to their own cluster, in order to meet the characteristics of one union blockchain.  Baohua Yang Jul 3   #129    Zhipeng  Thanks a lot for your thoughts!  Yes, i agree with you that we may move to that direction.  As you may find in the project proposal, the very initial goal of Cello is to help setup a baas, where all resources are managed by a single vendor.  Recently, people have proposed similar thoughts to expand Cello to a more flexible model, like what you said, each org owns its nodes, and they join together as a consortium. And requirements are reported with that flexible model, too. The team have considered it for quite a while, and now we think it as a long term target, and have started by refining the existing credential generation and providing a user management mechanism.  We would very much welcome you help add ur thoughts into that proposal, and let's well define a new operation model, in order to help people utilize Hyperledger technologies better.  Thanks again!  This is one topic: https://lists.hyperledger.org/g/cello/topic/23022876#128  ></description> </Issue>
