<Action id="26189" issue="17840" author="kchristidis" type="comment" created="2017-06-13 19:26:15.0" updateauthor="kchristidis" updated="2017-06-13 20:23:14.0"> <body><! CDATA Hi Nishi. I see the thinking behind this.  But support should invoke that tool when the brokers stop to figure out what's up.  Adding it to the code (even in the DEBUG level) is expensive.  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="26193" issue="17840" author="nishi" type="comment" created="2017-06-13 19:56:16.0" updateauthor="nishi" updated="2017-06-13 20:25:00.0"> <body><! CDATA Hi Kostas,  Another thing kafka (from my observation) logs do not carry information of who the leader is for a "channel". Thus information we see in kafka logs is not accurate.  If we cannnot get info on leader for a given channel from Kafka logs or Orderer logs would that be costly at times, from support perspective?  What tool did you mean in your comments - for support to invoke? Is there any doc on that?  Thanks! -Nishi  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="26196" issue="17840" author="kchristidis" type="comment" created="2017-06-13 20:24:01.0" updateauthor="kchristidis" updated="2017-06-13 20:54:29.0"> <body><! CDATA Hi Nishi, see comments below:  > Another thing kafka logs do not carry information of who the leader is for a "channel". Thus information we see in kafka logs is not accurate.  The information that you see is accurate, but there is a mixup between what you call the leader of the partition and what the logs show as leader (this is not the leader of the partition, but the controller of the Kafka cluster).  The logs do not carry this information for the same reason as noted above. We could consider it as a low-priority improvement post v1. I will re-open this JIRA and mark it as such.   > If we cannnot get leader info from Kafka logs or Orderer logs would that be costly at times, from support perspective?  It would. There's always a trade-off.  > What tool did you mean in your comments - for support to invoke? Is there any doc on that?  I was referring to the `./kafka-topics.sh` script that's provided by the Kafka folks. There is not and there won't be any doc from us on this front, as we're now deep into pure Kafka territory. Whoever supports the Kafka-based ordering service needs to know how to maintain a Kafka cluster.  ></body> </Action>
