<Action id="39153" issue="27097" author="jyellick" type="comment" created="2018-01-26 02:42:02.0" updateauthor="jyellick" updated="2018-01-26 02:42:02.0"> <body><! CDATA > we have been told that a configAdmin for the OrdererOrg must send a capabilities config update to enable capability v1_1 in group /Channel/Application.  This is incorrect.  The channel creation transaction should encode the /Channel/Application capabilities.  Also, the ordering admin never has anything to do with the /Channel/Application capabillities, only the /Channel and /Channel/Orderer capabilities.  > I sort of understand why this makes sense for the upgrade scenario, but this seems entirely unnecessary in this situation where we are starting the entire network on v1.1.   You might be starting a greenfield network using the v1.1 fabric tools, but you might want to bootstrap it in a way that other organizations who are still running v1.0.x code could join it.  When bootstrapping, if you choose one of the v1.1 profiles, the system will be bootstrapped in v1.1 mode, no updates are necessary.  > Why should we require the network operator to enable a v1.1 capability, for every channel they create? If they didn't want v1.1 capabilities, they would not have installed a v1.1 network.  When creating a channel, you specify the application portion of the channel config.  This includes the organizations, policies, and capabilities for this channel.  > Is there some way to avoid this - maybe with a config parameter in orderer.yaml or configtx.yaml when starting the v1.1 orderer? Please explain.  You can look for example at https://github.com/hyperledger/fabric/blob/master/examples/e2e_cli/configtx.yaml where all of the profiles use v1.1 capabilities.  Note that the e2e never does any configuration updates, but is bootstrapped and creates channels with v1.1 capabilities.   ></body> </Action>
<Action id="39198" issue="27097" author="scottz" type="comment" body="ok. This seems sufficient. We will revise our tests and expectations." created="2018-01-26 19:31:28.0" updateauthor="scottz" updated="2018-01-26 19:31:28.0"/>
