<Issue id="46444" key="FGJ-101" number="101" project="11000" reporter="JIRAUSER20128" assignee="lesleyannj" creator="JIRAUSER20128" type="10004" summary="Security vulnerability found in fabric-sdk-java grpc-netty guava dependency" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2020-12-22 17:16:03.0" updated="2021-03-26 17:06:13.0" resolutiondate="2021-01-22 09:38:15.0" votes="0" watches="2" workflowId="60384" archived="N"> <description><! CDATA IBM MQ currently uses fabric-gateway-java 2.2.0 which pulls in fabric-sdk-java 2.2.3 which has a dependency on grpc-netty 1.31, which has a dependency on guava:jar:29.0-android.  We have been notified of a new security vulnerability  in our ASOC Open Source scan in guava.jar, so *could you please update to grpc-netty 1.31*  ie: Name: CVE-2020-8908 Description: A temp directory creation vulnerability exist in Guava versions prior to 30.0 allowing an attacker with access to the machine to potentially access data in a temporary directory created by the Guava com.google.common.io.Files.createTempDir(). The permissions granted to the directory created default to the standard unix-like /tmp ones, leaving the files open. We recommend updating Guava to version 30.0 or later, or update to Java 7 or later, or to explicitly change the permissions after the creation of the directory if neither are possible. Resolution: Upgrade to version v30.0 URL:  https://vuln.whitesourcesoftware.com/vulnerability/CVE-2020-8908   In addition, our ASOC scans are still complaining about *bcprov-jdk15on.jar* which is still at 1.62 in fabric-sdk-java *(*ASOC scan report says that 1.63 is vulnerable to CVE-2019-17359 (score 7.5)  I notice in the  bouncy-castle latest release|https://www.bouncycastle.org/latest_releases.html  they mention other security vulnerabilities (introduced at 1.65) but fixed in the latest release (1.68), so could you please review whether your back level version 1.62 has any vulnerabilities, and update it if necessary.  Lastly, I notice that a number of other fabric-sdk-java dependencies are now out of date, so could you please review and update any of these as necessary as well, thanks.     Note these fixes will be required early Jan 2021, in time for our legal code scan on 15th Jan, thanks in advance.  FYI  ~andrew-coleman   ~ibmmqmet   ~mcastle   ></description> </Issue>
