<Action id="46984" issue="31298" author="gudkov" type="comment" created="2018-07-06 07:12:10.0" updateauthor="gudkov" updated="2018-07-06 07:12:10.0"> <body><! CDATA Additional notes:  daniel.hardman  4:38 PM  Before I forget, I would like to recommend that the import/export functions for wallets be modified as follows: 1. add a parameter that is a progress callback, so that very large wallets can be handled with some idea of how far into the process we are; 2. Allow the application to bundle other things into the wallet data, besides the data that the wallet knows about (so the application could back up some external files along with the wallet, if needed)   vyacheslav.gudkov  4:50 PM  Hi, What is priority for these improvements? the point 1 seems feasible, but i am not sure that we ready for point 2 right now. We need some generic vision how to reference external data from the wallet that we don't have for the moment.  I can just create Jira stories related to this.  slackbot  4:50 PM  daniel.hardman has snoozed notifications. Send one anyway? Send notification  daniel.hardman  7:01 PM  The goal would be to modify the API quickly, but not implement any functionality for it. In other words, we want to allocate params in the functions, but ignore them, so we don’t have to change the function signature later.  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="47519" issue="31298" author="gudkov" type="comment" created="2018-07-19 09:53:27.0" updateauthor="gudkov" updated="2018-07-19 09:53:27.0"> <body><! CDATA Changed export file format: * Use MsgPack instead of custom entities serialization to be more reliable and allow extend-ability in backward compatible way * Changed header format to be more reliable and allow extend-ability in backward compatible way * Use STOP message to make sure that there was no truncation of export file  Removed EXPERIMENTAL notice for import/export API endpoints.  PR with changes:   https://github.com/hyperledger/indy-sdk/pull/968/files   We found the way for getting progress and cancellation in backward compatible way. There are dedicated stories:  https://jira.hyperledger.org/browse/IS-831 https://jira.hyperledger.org/browse/IS-832  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="47580" issue="31298" author="gudkov" type="comment" body="Experimental warnings were removed" created="2018-07-20 11:38:48.0" updateauthor="gudkov" updated="2018-07-20 11:38:48.0"/>
