<Issue id="36646" key="FAB-13619" number="13619" project="10002" reporter="wenjian" creator="wenjian" type="10001" summary="Java SDK: enhance SDK to support token functions" priority="3" resolution="10001" status="6" created="2019-01-10 16:01:07.0" updated="2019-10-22 10:42:01.0" resolutiondate="2019-10-22 10:42:01.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="48195"> <description><! CDATA Tokens in Fabric represents the assets that can be exchanged in an atomic fashion via Fabric transactions. Tokens in Fabric represents the assets that can be exchanged in an atomic fashion via Fabric transactions. Tokens are assigned to a Fabric network using an issue operation. From the moment token issuing takes place, new tokens are generated to represent the associated assets in Fabric network. Ownership of these tokens can be changed throughout Fabric transactions. The assets (tokens) themselves remain under the custody of Fabric network until when their owner claims the associated assets back via a redeem operation.   SDK needs to be enhanced to support tokens so that applications can call SDK API to perform the following token operations. * issue: creates new tokens to the specified users * transfer: transfers tokens from one user to other users * redeem: redeems existing tokens owned by the user * approve: authorizes to transfer owning tokens to other users * transfer from: transfers tokens that have been approved by the owner * swap: transfers tokens among multiple participants * list: lists unspent tokens owned by the user * allowance: amount of tokens approved by the owner that can be transferred to other users     To implement the above APIs, SDK needs to perform the following: # Communicate to a prover peer (via token.ProverClient grpc client) to get back a token transaction for each token operation mentioned above # Create a transaction envelope for the token transaction (common.HeaderType_TOKEN_TRANSACTION type) and broadcast it to the orderer # Allow the application to register for the transaction event   A token client package has been implemented in go that are used to test e2e token scenarios. This package can be used as a reference implementationfor SDK.  For more details of the token client package, refer to token-client-design.docx under the epic story FAB-11153 and CR https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/#/c/27631/ (see token/client and integration/token)  ></description> </Issue>
