<Issue id="31430" key="FABN-346" number="346" project="10604" reporter="scottz" creator="scottz" type="10002" summary="APIs to provide current discovery layouts from SDK, and to identify signers of TXs" priority="3" resolution="10001" status="6" created="2018-06-27 20:40:51.0" updated="2019-10-29 16:35:28.0" resolutiondate="2019-10-29 16:35:28.0" votes="0" watches="4" workflowId="46808"> <description><! CDATA This is really two requests, things which would make the Service Discovery feature behavior more easily monitored and understood. We think things like these should have been part of the feature deliverable, so I create this as a bug. However, I am open to changing it to an Improvement, and changing FixVersion as necessary, and also feel it may be applicable to a CLI tool implementation or to all SDK's besides node sdk.     1. As a tester, to aid my debugging efforts, I would like to use a tool to call a new API on the node SDK that returns the discovery layout that is currently in use, for a given channel and chaincode. And I would also like to have an API to indicate the exact row (i.e. selection of peer(s)) of the layout to be used by the SDK for the current and/or next transaction proposal. I looked here, but did not see anything of the sort.  https://fabric-sdk-node.github.io/Client.html#updateChannel__anchor   It would be helpful to identify the peers being used, because it would save us time if we know where (which peers) to go look at logs - instead of searching through possibly 100 peers in our network.     2. The above is for realtime examinations. Here is another question, this being for "after-the-fact":  Knowing that we could register for events for the transactions we send, how simple would it be to examine an event to identify which peers actually endorsed and signed a transaction? People (including auditors) will need a way to do that. How can we identify the owner of each signature? Is there an API for that, or is it easy to read from the event? If not, can we provide a way for network operators to do that?  ></description> </Issue>
