<Action id="54378" issue="34957" author="esplinr" type="comment" created="2018-12-05 14:29:50.0" updateauthor="esplinr" updated="2018-12-05 14:29:50.0"> <body><! CDATA Thanks for the issue. We are surprised that you had to use such a complicated command to upgrade. Our intention is for the process is to be as simple as you described.  There are a few reasons why it might be necessary to explicitly list all the version dependencies: * The Sovrin Network often waits to deploy the latest Indy release to complete more testing, and so they are cautious to ensure they don't accidentally grab something newer than they intend. * The Sovrin Test Net and the Sovrin Main Net are frequently running different versions of the Indy code. When a node moves between them, it has to downgrade, so we are careful to explicitly list all version numbers. * During the most recent upgrade of the Sovrin Network, we hit some bugs that took some complicated gymnastics to work through.  Which network are you talking about having to use that command? Where did you receive the instruction to use that command?  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="54390" issue="34957" author="benjsmi" type="comment" created="2018-12-05 17:50:40.0" updateauthor="benjsmi" updated="2018-12-05 17:50:40.0"> <body><! CDATA Thanks for responding! I'll put my responses in-line. * Which network are you talking about having to use that command?  At one point or another for both/either network. * Where did you receive the instruction to use that command?   ~mgbailey   But Mike told me to specify those package that precisely because otherwise my node wouldn't function on the network properly.  The instructions|https://docs.google.com/document/d/1AH618bj4q9U8FS1uyoIgbcvwNzaghBCQ1v44tNpZ2OU/edit#heading=h.a2y2mmlyqj2t  say to just install either the indy-node or sovrin packages. This didn't get my newly-created node into a situation where it could join the network. There were problems reading the genesis transactions document, etc. I had explanations from the Sovrin Slack channels that this shouldn't be a problem because I "should already have certain packages installed." That's not a good way to run an apt repository – especially because given the experience I had, a new Steward who is trying to set up his/her validator would have failed. * The Sovrin Network often waits to deploy the latest Indy release to complete more testing, and so they are cautious to ensure they don't accidentally grab something newer than they intend.  This makes sense and is a standard practice for continuous release cycles. I'm glad Sovrin/Indy does this. However, that's not mutually exclusive to having a stream/branch on the apt repository that would allow a user to pull the exact version that he/she needs to use to join the STN or MainNet. You/devs/release manager would update the packages pointed to/being used by that network when ready. * The Sovrin Test Net and the Sovrin Main Net are frequently running different versions of the Indy code. When a node moves between them, it has to downgrade, so we are careful to explicitly list all version numbers.  Same answer as above. Apt can be configured to allow for these types of situations. In fact, you already have a "stable" and "master" branch... I'm just asking to add "testnet" and "mainnet" and update their version metadata independently based on what's actually running in-network. * During the most recent upgrade of the Sovrin Network, we hit some bugs that took some complicated gymnastics to work through.  Agreed. I'm aware that there are growing pains and I'm sympathetic. I'm actually offering this suggestion/feature request as a way to try to *help* mitigate some of these kinds of gymnastics/issues.  Thank you for taking the time to consider my POV on this and to follow up with thoughtful questions!  Ben  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="59931" issue="34957" author="esplinr" type="comment" created="2019-05-11 02:39:33.0" updateauthor="esplinr" updated="2019-05-11 02:39:33.0"> <body><! CDATA I created a story for this issue in the tracker for issues specific to the Sovrin Network: https://sovrin.atlassian.net/browse/SN-3  Because this isn't expected to require changes to the Indy project, I'll close this issue. All watchers of this issue should subscribe to the new issue.  ></body> </Action>
