<Action id="66124" issue="43512" author="scottz" type="comment" created="2019-12-05 16:06:00.0" updateauthor="scottz" updated="2019-12-05 16:06:00.0"> <body><! CDATA After our discussion about process and AZP pipelines yesterday,  ~rameshthoomu  offered these helpful steps, to help with describing workflow:    1. Remove existing gerrit reference from your local machine 2. Fork fabric-test repository into your GitHub account. (Do this from your GitHub UI) 3. git clone https://github.com/hyperledger/fabric-test 4. git remote add upstream https://github.com/hyperledger/fabric-test.git 5. git checkout -b <branch_name> 6. <add changes> and commit your changes with "git add <list_of_files>" && "git commit -m "Commit Message" or "git commit -s" 7. git push -f origin <branch_name>  Use -f to force push the changes to avoid multiple commits. 8. Submit Pull Request from your GitHub remote repository (forked repository) on upstream remote repository. 9. git pull upstream master (to Pull the latest changes from your upstream repository)   git pull does both fetch and merge   10. git push -f origin master ( To sync your local changes with your forked repository). Use -f to force push the changes to avoid multiple commits. 11. Once PR is merged, if you want, remove branch `git branch -d <branch_name> or git branch -D <branch_name>` 12. To remove from your GitHub remote, use this command to delete from local and push to GitHub remote `git push origin -d <branch_name>`   will keep your branch in local but will delete from GitHub remote   or git push origin -D <branch_name>`   Will delete from local and GitHub Remote   ></body> </Action>
<Action id="66127" issue="43512" author="scottz" type="comment" created="2019-12-05 16:28:46.0" updateauthor="scottz" updated="2019-12-05 16:28:46.0"> <body><! CDATA There is no UI cherry pick like Gerrit had. You just checkout release-1.4 on the CLI and do:    {{git cherry-pick <commit hash>}}  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="67659" issue="43512" author="scottz" type="comment" created="2020-01-24 22:03:41.0" updateauthor="scottz" updated="2020-01-24 22:03:41.0"> <body><! CDATA  https://github.com/hyperledger/fabric-test/pull/71   This update cleans up the Readme files, and refers to the Fabric contribution-guide. Decided not necessary to put the github workflow statements in the previous comment in the Readme.  ></body> </Action>
