<Issue id="32166" key="FABN-834" number="834" project="10604" reporter="rolivieri" assignee="harrisob@us.ibm.com" creator="rolivieri" type="10004" summary="Chaincode events are not received after a client has been idle for several days" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2018-07-24 16:15:03.0" updated="2018-12-07 08:10:10.0" resolutiondate="2018-12-07 08:09:39.0" votes="0" watches="7" workflowId="43395"> <description><! CDATA Fabric version: v1.1.0  Node Fabric Client SDK: v1.1.2  Platform for Node Client: Ubuntu LTS 14.04  Platform for Fabric: IBP on IBM Cloud (starter plan)  From time to time, we have experienced issues with the processing of chaincode events on the client side: Though chaincode events had been fired, these were not received on the fabric client application.  This problem appears to be intermittent and related to the client application (in this case, a Node.js client) has been idle for more than 2-3 consecutive days. In other words, we have seen this issue occur after not firing off any chaincode events for a period of 2-3 days.  Here's a high level description of what we have seen: - Chaincode is successfully deployed and instantiated; Node.js Fabric client is then started and registers to receive events.  - Expected chaincode events are fired from the chaincode and then received in the Node.js Fabric client application. Everything is working fine up to this point.  - The application is not used for 2-3 days, meaning: 1) the Node.js fabric client is running and the Hyperledger Fabric network is up and running,; 2) no chaincode function invocations are made; and 3) consequently no chaincode events are fired for that period (i.e. 2-3 days).  - After the 2-3 days period, we invoke the chaincode and events are fired. However, events are not received any more in the Node.js Fabric client application.  - After restarting the Node.js Fabric client application, then it starts receiving the chaincode events again.  It seems odd that we have to restart the Node.js Fabric clients for events to be received again.  ></description> </Issue>
