<Action id="55394" issue="36522" author="manish-sethi" type="comment" body="https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/#/c/28530/" created="2019-01-08 02:23:26.0" updateauthor="manish-sethi" updated="2019-01-08 02:23:26.0"/>
<Action id="55447" issue="36522" author="mastersingh24" type="comment" created="2019-01-09 16:53:06.0" updateauthor="mastersingh24" updated="2019-01-09 16:53:42.0"> <body><! CDATA  ~jyellick   Probably missing something obvious, but I'm struggling to see the use case / requirement for this?  How will this be used by the lifecycle work?  I always worry with yet another function added to the already overly complicated stub  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="55463" issue="36522" author="jyellick" type="comment" created="2019-01-09 20:54:36.0" updateauthor="jyellick" updated="2019-01-09 20:54:36.0"> <body><! CDATA This is required to address a couple issues and has some other uses the pipeline.  1. Before a peer endorses, it needs to check to see if the definition matches the one defined in its local collection.  Because this introduces a read dependency against the local collection, we would run into mis-matched RW sets unless every implicit collection has the key read in it.  So, this function allows us to introduce a read dependency without having the private data available to us. 2. It's going to be useful to be able to check to see who has agreed to a definition before it's actually defined and written into the world state.  Although we can't actually see the definition in other org's implicit collections, we can look at its hash to see if it matches the definition in ours.  Finally, there are some use cases in the pipeline for standard user chaincodes.  Particularly, imagine a buy/sell case where a buyer agrees to buy something a seller is selling at a given price.  We want the price to be private, and we don't want the seller to be able to mutate it, but, we want the seller to be able to validate that the agreement is to the correct price.  We can use this same function here to validate the agreement without actually having to have the seller be part of the collection distribution.  ></body> </Action>
