<Issue id="44372" key="FAB-17512" number="17512" project="10002" reporter="nkl199" creator="nkl199" type="10004" summary="chaincode stream terminating" priority="3" resolution="10203" status="6" created="2020-02-18 15:54:10.0" updated="2020-11-19 22:16:21.0" resolutiondate="2020-11-19 22:16:21.0" votes="1" watches="6" workflowId="58279" archived="N"> <description><! CDATA Whilst performing some benchmarking we have hit issues within both levelDB and couchDB, whereby the transactions are being rejected. This is repeatable.  This has been found when running benchmarks on a RHEL7 server, using Caliper clients, driving a benchmark that is query heavy. We have witnessed failures in rich queries, range queries and batch retrieval style queries (return multiple items obtained via repeat gets within the same invoke).  In couchDB we appear to be breaking a timeout threshold on connecting through to the database such that the chaincode definition is not obtainable, and in levelDB there is an alternative failure resulting in the error message:  Error: error in simulation: failed to execute transaction ea72d05e2b4a3901e97f27da7a4ee786871522237603f795c09a16ba57340de1: error sending: chaincode stream terminated at self._endorserClient.processProposal (/home/lynn14m/git/caliper/node_modules/fabric-network/node_modules/fabric-client/lib/Peer.js:137:36) at Object.onReceiveStatus (/home/lynn14m/git/caliper/node_modules/fabric-network/node_modules/grpc/src/client_interceptors.js:1207:9) at InterceptingListener._callNext (/home/lynn14m/git/caliper/node_modules/fabric-network/node_modules/grpc/src/client_interceptors.js:568:42) at InterceptingListener.onReceiveStatus (/home/lynn14m/git/caliper/node_modules/fabric-network/node_modules/grpc/src/client_interceptors.js:618:8) at callback (/home/lynn14m/git/caliper/node_modules/fabric-network/node_modules/grpc/src/client_interceptors.js:845:24)  Since the above is repeatable, we can get logs for components involved (and can repeat with varying log level).  Further log will be obtained for the peers (with a different log level) to assist with analysis as soon as they are generated.  ></description> </Issue>
