<Issue id="29186" key="FAB-9371" number="9371" project="10002" reporter="elli-androulaki" creator="elli-androulaki" type="10002" summary="TEST PLAN: Anonymous identities in Policy evaluation" priority="3" resolution="10001" status="6" created="2018-04-05 14:10:16.0" updated="2020-01-22 22:32:23.0" resolutiondate="2020-01-22 22:32:23.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="43256"> <description><! CDATA Orchestrate the tests associated to the code the CRs of this epic include.  Before closing this testplan task, coverage must be reviewed and approved (via upvote or comment) by the epic feature owner and the test leads identified below.  +*Location / Description of*+ docs, APIs, config vars, system configuration (fabric, SDKs, fabric-samples) :     +*Unit Test (UT) leader:*+  ~mathiasb303   Automated unit tests are merged in repo, as go tests or otherwise part of build/verify jenkins jobs. Code coverage tracked in Jenkins:  https://jenkins.hyperledger.org/view/Daily/job/fabric-unit-test-coverage-daily-master-x86_64/   The latest code coverage report for the package with added/modified functionality is the following: {code:java} 00:30:43  unit-tests_1  | ok      github.com/hyperledger/fabric/msp    11.605s    coverage: 84.6% of statements {code}    +*Function Test (FVT) leader*+:  ~elli-androulaki  In v1.2 the peer is not well structured for integration tests, therefore we will compensate with expanded Unit tests and expanded E2E tests using ginkgo. Describe function test coverage approach here:  A.  Expand unit testcases beyond traditional UT coverage, for the following integration scenarios that otherwise might be done using the ginko framework(FAB-10139):  # Have an identity mixer identity be checked against combined principals of "anonymity" and "OrgX.member" where OrgX is the corresponding MSP id # Have an identity mixer identity be checked against combined principals of "NON-anonymity"" and "OrgX.member" where OrgX is the corresponding MSP id  B.  E2E testcases scenarios (Add one individual jira TASK within this feature Epic for each of these): # E2E Test: IdentityMixer Client (CLI) tries alone to reconfigure a system parameter (e.g., add a new MSP) that is governed by a policy that excludes anonymous identities FAB-10119 # E2E Test: Conventional MSP (CLI) tries alone to reconfigure a system parameter (e.g., add a new MSP) that is governed by a policy where explicitly anonymous identities are required FAB-10138  *Note*: For these tests to be implemented using gingko we need an idemixgen runner. This runner is also needed for tests associated to all identity mixer related components. It is not clear if this is to be completed by 1.2 (handled by -FAB-10175-); If not, then FAB-10119, and FAB-10138 will refer to non-gingko e2e tests and new jiras will be created to convert these tests to gingko based ones targeting 1.3.   C.  Other functional testing required: N/A   +*System Verification Test (SVT) leader*+: ???? V1.2 System Test Plan (Epic) FAB-???? Covers stress, load, performance, full system integration, resiliency, recover, etc.  Considering this feature, what scenarios are of particular interest and concern: # Scenario Description X # Scenario Description Y # Scenario Description Z  ></description> </Issue>
