<Issue id="16326" key="FAB-3661" number="3661" project="10002" reporter="nishi" assignee="nishi" creator="nishi" type="10001" summary="Research: Policies and ACL in Hyperledger-Fabric" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2017-05-04 14:31:37.0" updated="2018-07-20 18:53:42.0" resolutiondate="2018-07-09 18:23:24.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="38338"> <description><! CDATA h3. All Questions & very few Answers  h4. Hyperledger-Fabric Policy: {code}  What does one mean by "policy" in Hyperledger-Fabric?  "At its most basic level, a policy is a function which accepts as input a set of signed data and evaluates successfully, or returns an error because some aspect of the signed data did not satisfy the policy. More concretely, policies test whether the signer or signers of some data meet some condition required for those signatures to be considered ‘valid’. This is useful for determining that the correct parties have agreed to a transaction, or change." - doc link below  Few policies I heard about: * Channel Configuration * Signature  * Implicit Meta * Endorsement. Understand how these various policies opearate? If they all fall in the same category? How does an endorsement policy differ from Signature policy say?  Explore what other kind of policies Fabric 1.0 support?  How can rules be defined and enforced around policies? What tools currently support creating and modifying these policies?  Can we have dynamic user defined policies?  Is there a language to define these policies and rules? {code}  h4. ACL {code} What are "Access Control List (ACL)"? How do you associate users and corresponding ACL?  It appears current cryptogen tool does not have the capability to support ACL. How can we achieve defining ACL in Fabric? How does ACL relate to these multiple policies? What exists in default ACL during Channel Creation policy and how is it enforced? {code}  h3. Next Steps To Do:  {code} * Gather input and ideas from development/test on policies and ACL in Hyperledger-Fabric? * Can we test each of the policies listed above? * Document possible tests around policies and ACL. * Automate tests using basic (highly used) policies and verifying their validity. * Understand if CLI testing equipped for this? * Can we leverage behave framework o write automated tests? * What capability does Node SDK offer around this? * Work with documentation enhancements if necessary.  {code}  h3. References: http://hyperledger-fabric.readthedocs.io/en/latest/policies.html  ></description> </Issue>
