<Issue id="28378" key="FAB-8760" number="8760" project="10002" reporter="edluizl" creator="edluizl" type="10004" summary="Error while trying to join Channel using different orderer" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2018-03-09 19:28:45.0" updated="2018-07-20 14:15:58.0" resolutiondate="2018-06-08 13:28:59.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="41488"> <description><! CDATA I'm trying to make a Peer join two channels each with its own Orderer, so I have the following scenario:  - A channel named solochannel with an orderer Solo, using the port 7050 - A channel named kafkachannel with an orderer Kafka, using the port 8050  1- I create the chanels using the command {code:java} peer channel create -o orderer:8050 -c solochannel -f ./channel-artifacts/channelSolo.tx peer channel create -o ordererKafka:8050 -c kafkachannel -f ./channel-artifacts/channelKafka.tx{code}  2- After creating both channels, I start a peer to join them in both channels {code:java} peer channel join -b solochannel.block peer channel join -b kafkachannel.block{code}   This step shows a message saying that the Peer was able to join both channels, and if I try to list all channels using 'Peer channel list', it shows that the Peer joined both channels successfully.  3- I open the Log for the Peer and the peer is trying to send information of the last Channel it joined to the orderer of the First channel.  So for example: If I join the solochannel first, It tries to send information of the kafkachannel to the ordererKafka:8050 and fails with the message Got error &\{NOT_FOUND} If I join the kafkachannel first, It tries to send information of the solochannel to the ordererSolo:7050 and fails with the message Got error &\{NOT_FOUND}  This is the Log from the Peer {code:java} 2018-03-07 16:58:06.071 UTC  deliveryClient  StartDeliverForChannel -> DEBU 6d0 This peer will pass blocks from orderer service to other peers for channel kafkachannel 2018-03-07 16:58:06.074 UTC  deliveryClient  connect -> DEBU 6d1 Connected to ordererSolo:7050 2018-03-07 16:58:06.074 UTC  deliveryClient  connect -> DEBU 6d2 Establishing gRPC stream with ordererSolo:7050 ... 2018-03-07 16:58:06.077 UTC  deliveryClient  afterConnect -> DEBU 6d3 Entering 2018-03-07 16:58:06.078 UTC  deliveryClient  RequestBlocks -> DEBU 6d4 Starting deliver with block  1  for channel kafkachannel 2018-03-07 16:58:06.082 UTC  deliveryClient  afterConnect -> DEBU 6d5 Exiting 2018-03-07 16:58:06.084 UTC  blocksProvider  DeliverBlocks -> WARN 6d6  kafkachannel  Got error &{NOT_FOUND}{code}  This is the Log from the ordererSolo:7050 {code:java} 2018-03-07 16:58:06.076 UTC  orderer/main  Deliver -> DEBU 1f5 Starting new Deliver handler 2018-03-07 16:58:06.076 UTC  orderer/common/deliver  Handle -> DEBU 1f6 Starting new deliver loop 2018-03-07 16:58:06.076 UTC  orderer/common/deliver  Handle -> DEBU 1f7 Attempting to read seek info message 2018-03-07 16:58:06.082 UTC  orderer/common/deliver  Handle -> DEBU 1f8 Rejecting deliver because channel kafkachannel not found 2018-03-07 16:58:06.082 UTC  orderer/main  func1 -> DEBU 1f9 Closing Deliver stream{code}  This keeps happening forever.  While I keep having this error, I cannot instantiate or upgrade a chaincode on the second channel   I'm having this error for both versions 1.0.5 and 1.0.6.     ></description> </Issue>
