<Issue id="34923" key="FAB-12625" number="12625" project="10002" reporter="nileshdeotale" assignee="dongming" creator="nileshdeotale" type="10004" summary="./runPTE.sh failed:    error:  client-utils.js : sendPeersProposal - Promise is rejected: Error: 2 UNKNOWN: chaincode error (status: 500, message: Error installing chaincode code ... chaincodes/sample_cc_ch1.v0 exists))" priority="2" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2018-10-26 16:11:00.0" updated="2018-11-05 22:26:53.0" resolutiondate="2018-11-05 22:26:53.0" votes="0" watches="2" workflowId="46351"> <description><! CDATA          /runPTE.sh --dir connectionprofile -t FAB-3808-2i  ....  ....  ....     PTE@1.0.0 /Users/nileshdeotale/helper-repos/fabric-test-12/tools/PTE  ├─┬ fabric-ca-client@1.2.0  └─┬ fabric-client@1.2.0               *****************************************************************************            *                       connection profile conversion                       *            *****************************************************************************     Error: cannot find adminPrivateKey in org key org1 in connection profile   cProfConversion  Error: failed to execute: node convert.js     USAGE: ./runPTE.sh  options   values      -h, --help View this help message     --no-npm skip npm re-install fabric-client packages     --dir absolute path or relative path from .../fabric-test/tools/networktest/ to the directory that contains the network connection profiles to be converted  (Default: ./connectionprofile/)     --channel <channel name>  (Must match channel name in connection profile. Default: defaultchannel)     --org <list of org names>  (Must match org names in connection profile. Default: org1 org2)     -t, --testcase <list of testcases>     -s, --sanity execute a sanity test of 2 predefined testcases: FAB-3808-2i FAB-3811-2q (~30 min)     -a, --all execute all predefined testcases (~3.5 hrs)     Examples:  ./runPTE.sh --dir connectionprofile -t FAB-3808-2i FAB-3811-2q  ./runPTE.sh -s  ./runPTE.sh -a     Available predefined testcases: FAB-3808-2i FAB-3811-2q FAB-3807-4i FAB-3835-4q FAB-4038-2i FAB-4036-2q FAB-7329-4i FAB-7333-4i  For more details, refer to jira or ../PTE/CITest/.     Notes:  All the listed testcases require only one channel and 2 orgs.  Use options --channel and --org only if your connection profile uses something other than defaultchannel and org1 and org2.  To run additional predefined testcases, or custom testcases, that are not listed here, use care to join peers to all the correct channels as used by the testcases.     The tool installs/instantiates chaincode every time, so you may ignore these errors if the chaincode is already installed/instantiated:         error:  client-utils.js : sendPeersProposal - Promise is rejected: Error: 2 UNKNOWN: chaincode error (status: 500, message: Error installing chaincode code ... chaincodes/sample_cc_ch1.v0 exists))         error:  client-utils.js : sendPeersProposal - Promise is rejected: Error: 2 UNKNOWN: chaincode error (status: 500, message: chaincode exists sample_cc_ch1)     Nileshs-MacBook-Pro:networktest nileshdeotale$  ></description> </Issue>
