<Issue id="42804" key="INDY-2254" number="2254" project="10303" reporter="lbendixsen" assignee="toktar" creator="lbendixsen" type="10004" summary="A new node added to Sovrin MainNet failed to reach consensus" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="10001" created="2019-10-17 23:15:29.0" updated="2019-10-31 15:36:38.0" resolutiondate="2019-10-31 15:36:38.0" votes="0" watches="3" workflowId="55884"> <description><! CDATA _Environment_: MainNet - Sovrin - 1.1.52   Node - 1.9.1  _Steps to Reproduce_:   During the attempt to add sicpa to MainNet, here is the sequence of steps as near as I can recall:  1) Sicpa was on StagingNet, thus needed to downgrade when attempting to switch to MainNet.  2) Stopped Sicpa's indy-node service and did all of the steps to switch them to mainnet. (Downgrade occurred here) All ip addresses, keys and etc stayed the same, just got new genesis files and onboarded them.  (init-indy-node)  3) Sicpa ran the ledger node command to add themselves to MainNet.  4) (Forgot to remove Sicpa from StagingNet before adding them to MainNet) Sicpa restarted indy-node here  5) Consensus would not occur.  Several nodes would not connect (whitelist issues) including the primary, so no primary was selected either.  6) Veridium went out of consensus   7) After running for a few hours, remembered to remove Sicpa from StagingNet  8) Restarted Sicpa and Veridium nodes (about Noon MDT on Tuesday Oct 15)   9) Restart had no noticable effect, so I had Sicpa remove themselves from consensus  10) Thought that maybe out of consensus was due to not being able to connect to enoug hnodes, so I had Sicpa add back in (occurred early Wednesday)  11) IceNode went out of Consensus  12) Fearing that nodes went out because Sicpa added in, I hed them remove themselves again. they removed themselves Wednesday between ~8-10A MDT  13) Icenode regained consensus, Veridium did not.     _Expected Behavior_:    Node should recover when conditions are corrected? (My bad for not removing them from StagingNet where Sicpa was sort of on 2 networks at once?)  _Observed Behavior_:   Node has not recovered.  Will attempt removing data directory to reset ledgers and try again soon (after Mondays MainNet upgrade)  _Notes_:  Logs from Sicpa (noted above) (journal.log) and Ev1 (Never left consensus) are included below.  Will add logs for Veridium (still out of consensus) when received.   ></description> </Issue>
