<Issue id="15163" key="FABN-324" number="324" project="10604" reporter="jjjjibm" assignee="jimthematrix" creator="jjjjibm" type="10004" summary=" node-SDK  http://&lt;ip:port&gt;/docs/gen/CryptoSuite_ECDSA_AES.html  -- describe parameters and results" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2017-03-02 14:18:33.0" updated="2018-07-19 00:53:39.0" resolutiondate="2017-04-05 18:39:49.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="34055"> <environment><! CDATA fabric      commit 39da6d5f263913668567112399c1708e3f87efc3 fabric-ca commit c9fb04e0f795589485915883fcbca3ae2fc0aaad fabric      commit 817fa851931e2614646800bcdd6da75940f85dd8  ></environment> <description><! CDATA The generated documentation for class CryptoSuite_ECDSA_AES has a couple issues.  Mostly I complain the parameters and results aren't described.  But 6a, 8a, and 10 are different issues.  (1) Generated documentation: _decrypt()   /* no parameters */ _Actual code: _+_decrypt(key, cipherText, opts)   /* parameters that should be documented_+_  Documenting the inputs will also help this generated remark make sense: _The opts argument should be appropriate for the algorithm used. _D  (2) Here's another Generated document: deriveKey()   /* incidentally, I like the way the document says To be implemented.  This will help if this method is not implemented by our first release.  Actual code: deriveKey(key, opts)   (3)  encrypt()  vs encrypt(key, plaintext, opts) I like the way it throws an error so users won't be confused if they try this before it is implemented  (4)  generateKey()  vs  generateKey(opts) This one is implemented   (5)  getKey()       vs  getKey(ski)  (5a) Subject Key Identifier ski. --> Subject Key Identifier (ski).  (6)  hash()   vs   hash(msg, opts)  (6a) Hashes {color:#205081}messages msg{color} using options opts. ===>{color:#205081} messages msg {color}needs to be cleaned up, but this may be moot once the parameters are documented.    (7) importkey() vs  importKey(raw, opts)  (8) sign()  vs sign(key, digest, opts)  (8a) in sign() "The opts argument is not needed".   do you mean it is optional, or do you mean it is ignored by this implementation?    The code seems to be ignoring it.   Suggestion: ===> The opts argument is not used by this implementation. ===> The opts argument is not used in this implementation. ===> This implementation ignores the opts argument.  (9) verify() vs verify(key, signature, digest)  (10 Key k is mentioned a lot in this class.  I searched the web to see if key k has a specific meaning.  I didn't find any  mention of it.  Will the meaning be clear to users of this class?  How to recreate: 1.Clone fabric-sdk-node 2.Gulp doc to generate doc 3.python -m SimpleHTTPServer & 4.Use a browser to navigate to <your ip>:8000 5.Navigate to docs/gen/ 6.Select CryptoSuite_ECDSA_AES from the Classes pull down menu.   ></description> </Issue>
