<Issue id="46944" key="FAB-18497" number="18497" project="10002" reporter="JIRAUSER21452" creator="JIRAUSER21452" type="10001" summary="Private Data Collections should be configurable as transfer-only for reducing the requirement of trust" priority="3" status="10100" created="2021-06-15 12:15:38.0" updated="2021-06-15 12:15:38.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="60855" archived="N"> <description><! CDATA As explained in "Hyperledger Fabric: Evaluating Endorsement Policy Strategies in Supply Chains", the data on the blockchain is only as trustworthy as the strength of the endorsement policy. In other words, if a group of adversarial users can satisfy the endorsement policy together, they can change/manipulate the ledger state however they want by crafting custom writesets and signing them.     Recently, Fabric seems to encourage users to create very small private groups due to the higher level of privacy: "consider using a smaller number of private data collections (e.g. one collection per organization, or one collection per pair of organizations)" ( link| https://hyperledger-fabric.readthedocs.io/en/release-2.2/private-data/private-data.html#sharing-private-data )|https://hyperledger-fabric.readthedocs.io/en/release-2.2/private-data/private-data.html#sharing-private-data ).  and hints at using implicit data collections, i.e. 1-organization PDC.      Since a 1-org PDC requires only the endorsement of the single organization, the data in a PDC can typically not be relied upon, as the owner of the PDC can set the values to whatever he wants: a shipment of X KG metals or a vehicle with Y KM in its odometer. Therefore, there should be a warning that if one creates such PDC with a very weak endorsement policy, the information stored should be insignificant, as it could be changed by 1 org. This is especially the case when the information of the PDC is used later with/by other organizations.     An idea to mitigate this issue is to define PDCs as "transfer-only". In such a transfer-only PDC, an entry may only be created if the entry is removed from another PDC. Thus, the value itself is immutable. Such restriction could perhaps be enforced in the VSCC (when the hash is written to the public ledger). A design choice could be to only allow a subset of organizations (manufacturers, miners, harvesters) to create assets, which from that moment on, may only be transferred without changing. Then, we can securely have 1-organizational PDCs of which its data can be trusted. Other ideas may be possible as well here, but this change comes to mind and would not require major overhauls to Fabric's transaction flow.  ></description> </Issue>
