<Action id="49210" issue="33046" author="gudkov" type="comment" created="2018-08-22 08:13:23.0" updateauthor="gudkov" updated="2018-08-22 08:13:23.0"> <body><! CDATA Our chat with  ~ckochenower :  ``` vyacheslav.gudkov  1 day ago  @corin.kochenower It is expected. CLI stores additional metadata to lookup wallets and can find only wallet created by CLI. Indy SDK doesn't store this metadata and relies on application in this.   corin.kochenower  1 day ago  I see. I'm not sure how many users are going to be managing wallets from both Indy SDK AND indy-cli on the same client.  Anyone who knows where the wallets are stored may be confused if they see a ~/.indy_client/wallet/<name> and Indy CLI says the wallet does not exist.   vyacheslav.gudkov  1 day ago  To solve this we can add additional command to indy cli. Like wallet connect that will allow creation of wallet configuration for existing wallet.   corin.kochenower  1 day ago  If we do that, I also recommend that `wallet list` list wallets that exist that are not "connected" (don't have metadata). Otherwise, the user of indy-cli would have to reconcile differences outside of the CLI interface.   corin.kochenower  1 day ago  Maybe a `wallet list all` or something like that.   vyacheslav.gudkov  1 day ago  It is impossible to find unconnected wallets. Wallet can be stored by any path or in MySQL database.   corin.kochenower  1 day ago  Ah! True... Sounds like my suggestion will only work for wallets stored in Indy CLI's default location. (edited)   corin.kochenower  1 day ago  I'm educated and unstuck now. Not sure how many others will get hung up on this. ```  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="50671" issue="33046" author="gudkov" type="comment" created="2018-09-19 14:34:37.0" updateauthor="gudkov" updated="2018-09-19 14:34:37.0"> <body><! CDATA  ~ckochenower   I created the story IS-988 about implementation wallet attach/detach commands that will solve the issue. If wallet was created outside user can call wallet attach and provide configuration. After this wallet will look like created with CLI.   Closing the issue in favor of story as i already implemented these commands.  ></body> </Action>
