<Action id="41385" issue="26265" author="lehors" type="comment" created="2018-03-08 19:22:34.0" updateauthor="lehors" updated="2018-03-08 19:22:59.0"> <body><! CDATA An example of this is shown below where the name is wrong:  {{peer chaincode query -C mychannel -n mywrongcc -c '\{"Args": "query","a" }'}} {{2018-03-08 14:36:39.292 UTC  chaincodeCmd  checkChaincodeCmdParams -> INFO 001 Using default escc}} {{2018-03-08 14:36:39.292 UTC  chaincodeCmd  checkChaincodeCmdParams -> INFO 002 Using default vscc}} {{Error: Error endorsing query: rpc error: code = Unknown desc = make sure the chaincode mywrongcc has been successfully instantiated and try again: could not find chaincode with name 'mywrongcc' - <nil>}} {{Usage:}} {{  peer chaincode query  flags }}  {{Flags:}} {{  -C, --channelID string   The channel on which this command should be executed}} {{  -c, --ctor string        Constructor message for the chaincode in JSON format (default "\{}")}} {{  -x, --hex                If true, output the query value byte array in hexadecimal. Incompatible with --raw}} {{  -n, --name string        Name of the chaincode}} {{  -r, --raw                If true, output the query value as raw bytes, otherwise format as a printable string}} {{  -t, --tid string         Name of a custom ID generation algorithm (hashing and decoding) e.g. sha256base64}}  {{Global Flags:}} {{      --cafile string                       Path to file containing PEM-encoded trusted certificate(s) for the ordering endpoint}} {{      --certfile string                     Path to file containing PEM-encoded X509 public key to use for mutual TLS communication with the orderer endpoint}} {{      --clientauth                          Use mutual TLS when communicating with the orderer endpoint}} {{      --keyfile string                      Path to file containing PEM-encoded private key to use for mutual TLS communication with the orderer endpoint}} {{      --logging-level string                Default logging level and overrides, see core.yaml for full syntax}} {{  -o, --orderer string                      Ordering service endpoint}} {{      --ordererTLSHostnameOverride string   The hostname override to use when validating the TLS connection to the orderer.}} {{      --tls                                 Use TLS when communicating with the orderer endpoint}} {{      --transient string                    Transient map of arguments in JSON encoding}} {{  -v, --version                             Display current version of fabric peer server}}  There is no reason to display the usage message in this case. It is actually a distraction that is more confusing than helpful.  ></body> </Action>
