<Action id="55402" issue="36020" author="davidkhala" type="comment" body="+ 1 but looks overlap functionality of hyperledger/caliper" created="2019-01-08 13:37:09.0" updateauthor="davidkhala" updated="2019-01-08 13:37:09.0"/>
<Action id="55593" issue="36020" author="vramaiitkgp" type="comment" created="2019-01-14 07:05:49.0" updateauthor="vramaiitkgp" updated="2019-01-14 07:05:49.0"> <body><! CDATA  ~davidkhala  Sorry for the late response. You are right about there being some overlap with Hyperledger Caliper (which we have been following keenly), as there is bound to be; both Caliper and STE are measuring the performance (throughput, latency, etc.) of Fabric applications.  We feel STE fills a niche by providing a customizable and easy-to-use testing and analytics engine for applications developed on DLTs like Fabric. It supports out-of-the-box measurements using realistic and meaningful benchmark applications (listed above.)  Caliper is itself very useful and easy to use, and does some things that STE doesn't do yet (like run comparative measurements on different blockchain platforms: Sawtooth and Iroha in addition to Fabric), but STE also supports the dynamic provisioning of arbitrary networks (we have a proof-of-concept built for a particular cloud platform) and a completely automated end-to-end testing pipeline for any chaincode application a user would like to calibrate. STE is modular in terms of network topology, application, and workload, and in the future, we envision it supporting different DLT platforms in a modular way.  We are trying to figure out where a toolkit like STE ideally fits in the Hyperledger source. Thus far, we have targeted `hyperledger/fabric-test`, as STE currently only supports the testing of Fabric chaincodes. STE also depends on PTE, the core measurement engine within `fabric-test`, as well as adapted forms of `hyperledger/fabric-test/tools/ATD` and `hyperledger/cello`. Therefore, `fabric-test` seemed like a natural place to house STE, at least for the immediate future. In the longer run, we would be happy to consider integration with Caliper or any other measurement platform; whatever turns out to be most useful to the community.  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="55662" issue="36020" author="davidkhala" type="comment" body=" ~vramaiitkgp Great for your observation. It could be much better if your team can collaborate with Caliper " created="2019-01-15 06:22:46.0" updateauthor="davidkhala" updated="2019-01-15 06:22:46.0"/>
<Action id="67571" issue="36020" author="sykesm" type="comment" body="Stale" created="2020-01-22 22:33:38.0" updateauthor="sykesm" updated="2020-01-22 22:33:38.0"/>
