<Action id="52799" issue="34623" author="latitiah" type="comment" created="2018-10-31 13:15:26.0" updateauthor="latitiah" updated="2018-10-31 13:15:26.0"> <body><! CDATA This epic still needs a test plan summary associated with it. Here is a quick guide for what the summary should contain. Thanks! {code} Functional Tests: - FAB-XXX1: Make sure config is accepted and turns on feature (Integration) - PersonA - FAB-XXX2: What happens when config is set wrong (unit) - PersonA - FAB-XXX3: When FeatureX is turned on in both ComponentA and ComponentB (End-to-end) - PersonB - FAB-XXX4: When FeatureX is turned on in ComponentA and not ComponentB (End-to-end) - PersonA  System Tests: - FAB-XXX5: How is performace impacted when sending 5 packets per second for 3 hours? - PersonC * Be sure to set the following config values on ComponentA as such: - FEATUREX=true - FEATURE_PATH=/some/path/for/my/feature * Be sure to send the messages using the foo SDK - FAB-XXX6: Is the feature and component stable when executing 10 packets per second for 1 week? - PersonC * Be sure to set the following config values on ComponentA as such: - FEATUREX=true - FEATURE_PATH=/some/path/for/my/feature {code}  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="53573" issue="34623" author="denyeart" type="comment" body=" ~sstone1  Is this planned for v1.4?" created="2018-11-19 06:03:20.0" updateauthor="denyeart" updated="2018-11-19 06:03:20.0"/>
<Action id="53901" issue="34623" author="mbwhite" type="comment" body=" ~awjh-ibm  is currently working this; though understand that there is some work under way by  ~mastersingh24  that overlaps with this?  I can&apos;t find the Jira for that other work." created="2018-11-28 13:09:46.0" updateauthor="mbwhite" updated="2018-11-28 13:09:46.0"/>
<Action id="53922" issue="34623" author="awjh-ibm" type="comment" created="2018-11-28 15:21:36.0" updateauthor="awjh-ibm" updated="2018-11-28 15:21:36.0"> <body><! CDATA Current Status: * *fabric-baseimage* (ready to CR once fabric-chaincode-node updated, relies on release as uses npm pack on shim): ** Dockerfile defined ** Shell script added to setup node environment ** Setup.sh modified to remove node from baseimage ** Makefile updated to include nodeenv * *fabric-chaincode-node* (writing tests to cover few changes made and then will be in CR by tomorrow): ** Updated contract to include function for checking if instance of contract since instance of no longer works ** Updated start script to run file to determine startup for contract and included import of fabric-contract-api in package.json ** Added startup.sh to determine whether contract is in new format and can be started using fabric-contract-api or to call npm start on the contract ** Updated chaincodefromcontract to use new method of determining if instance of * *fabric* (ready to CR once fabric-chaincode-node and fabric-baseimage updated): ** Updated platform.go to put chaincode in new location for node to avoid merging with fabric-shim code in docker image ** Updated simpleconfig/core.yaml to use fabric-basenode in node chaincode  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="54030" issue="34623" author="denyeart" type="comment" body=" ~sstone1   ~awjh-ibm   ~mastersingh24  The cross repo changes always take longer than expected to settle out and test. Given we have a release candidate in a week and are now entering stabilization period, it seems the Inversion of Control epic and nodeenv image updates will have to be deferred to the next release." created="2018-11-29 22:41:16.0" updateauthor="denyeart" updated="2018-11-29 22:42:21.0"/>
