<Issue id="12620" key="FAB-319" number="319" project="10002" reporter="dinghaiyang84" creator="dinghaiyang84" type="10001" summary="Plan on consensus protocol improvement." priority="5" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2016-09-08 09:32:26.0" updated="2018-07-20 18:55:30.0" resolutiondate="2016-10-04 14:13:23.0" votes="0" watches="5" workflowId="36182"> <description><! CDATA Hi folks, I am new to the community and I started this issue to have a discussion over the consensus design & planning in Fabric. Hopefully people can share some insights, in any form, so that I (as well as other potential readers) could have a better view about the consensus in Fabric. My colleagues and I, we are trying to build a blockchain system with Fabric. Our business scenario requires the TPS to be at least 10k/s, however our current test on Fabric shows that it only supports a TPS of around 100/s (built-in pbft, 4 nodes). I know that there are some consensus algorithms that are able to reach several k/s TPS or even higher, e.g. Tendermint, Ripple, Aliph (in “The Next 700 BFT Protocols”), XFT (in “XFT: Practical Fault Tolerance Beyond Crashes”), to name a few. Here is my question:  *How the Fabric community thinks about improving the throughput of the consensus algorithm?*  To be more specific, it would be great if people could discuss about the following (or just give me some links/refs): 1.	Are we going to adopt other high performance consensus protocols in Fabric’s community version? If yes, which protocols? Is there a milestone? 2.	If there is no plan to adopt high performance consensus protocols in the community version, is there going to be a commercial version that adopts them? There is rumor saying that IBM has an internal consensus protocol which reaches over 100k/s. Given the many publications done by IBM researchers, I’d personally think this rumor is not far from reality. 3.	Any other insights are welcome as well, including but not limited to those like, “100k/s is a lie, not theoretically possible”, “I’d like to hear other’s options” and so on. Or just giving me some other references is great!  FWIW, I have read the issue  Consensus endorsing, consenting, and committing model (https://jira.hyperledger.org/browse/FAB-37?jql=text%20~%20%22consensus%22), and I have read a doc of “Next-Consensus-Architecure-Proposal” when Fabric was hosted at Github, but I cannot find it anymore. It said that Fabric is going to adopt XFT and Aliph, but since I cannot find it, I am not sure if it still counts.  Thanks for reading the post, please leave your comments.   ></description> </Issue>
