<Issue id="16111" key="FAB-3514" number="3514" project="10002" reporter="jjjjibm" assignee="nickgaski" creator="jjjjibm" type="10004" summary=" doc   Is BIOS Enabled Virtualization really needed by fabric?" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2017-04-28 21:05:31.0" updated="2018-07-20 14:12:27.0" resolutiondate="2017-06-02 19:03:33.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="38226"> <environment><! CDATA fabric-sdk-node: commit caaf3c0dc78da7f6fa21521e872a4b0de752a292 (but probably not important for this defect).   ></environment> <description><! CDATA On this web page:  http://hyperledger-fabric.readthedocs.io/en/latest/dev-setup/devenv.html  I was reviewing the list of pre-requisites:   Prerequisites •Git client •Go - 1.7 or later (for releases before v1.0, 1.6 or later) •For macOS, Xcode must be installed •Docker - 1.12 or later •Docker Compose - 1.8.1 or later •Pip •(macOS) you may need to install gnutar, as macOS comes with bsdtar as the default, but the build uses some gnutar flags. You can use Homebrew to install it as follows:  brew install gnu-tar --with-default-names  •(only if using Vagrant) - Vagrant - 1.7.4 or later •(only if using Vagrant) - VirtualBox - 5.0 or later •BIOS Enabled Virtualization - Varies based on hardware •Note: The BIOS Enabled Virtualization may be within the CPU or Security settings of the BIOS  At the very end, note that BIOS enabled virtualization is listed unconditionally as a pre-requisite.  Enabling BIOS Virtualization is painful to say the least.  I am not sure it is mandatory unless you plan to use Vagrant/Virtualbox.  We should not require enabling BIOS virtualization unless it is absolutely required.  I made a query on RocketChat: https://chat.hyperledger.org/channel/fabric-questions?msg=soj9d55kj6D2BrjaC but have received no answer.  Quality team believes it is not needed but no one will commit :-).    Keep watching that space!  So the first destination of this issue  is the fabric dev team to confirm BIOS enabled virtualization is needed if and only if you intend to use Vagrant/Virtualbox.   If that is the case, the doc needs to be updated to say only Vagrant/Virtualbox users need to enable BIOS virtualization.  If all users need to enable BIOS virtualization, the bullet item should be moved above the Vagrant-only bullets.   ></description> </Issue>
