<Action id="61156" issue="40396" author="mattp" type="comment" created="2019-06-20 16:46:23.0" updateauthor="mattp" updated="2019-06-20 16:46:23.0"> <body><! CDATA As I'm trying to use the documentation guide, I'm struggling with understanding the guide in the context of the decision maker role.  Basically I'm looking at this subset of info from  the guide|https://docs.google.com/document/d/11rgfuRu7c-tzcsSzsVQAoCgWBGrt6jEWzO-b_txi_hs/edit?ts=5cf68be6#heading=h.j8j13kuztut4  |https://docs.google.com/document/d/11rgfuRu7c-tzcsSzsVQAoCgWBGrt6jEWzO-b_txi_hs/edit?ts=5cf68be6#heading=h.j8j13kuztut4  as it relates to the decision maker role.      The basic subset of info I'm trying to follow from the guide:     Entry Template  The entries for the following role sections should follow one of the following templates:     A *_decision maker_* must understand *_the intent and scope of Hyperledger Grid._*  A _*decision maker*_ must be able to follow a procedure to do *_<task to be documented>_*   A *_decision maker_* must understand how to *_<do task>_* using the *_<Grid component>._*  A *_decision maker_* must understand how to *_<do task>._*  A _*decision maker*_ must be able to troubleshoot problems with to *_<task to be documented>_*.     Where *_<role>_* is a member of the audience the documentation is for.     For example:     A *_decision maker_* must understand *_Grid at a very high level._*     The entry should be short and specific. If a procedure is large, split it into subtasks. Use this format:    * A *_decision maker_* must understand how to *<do task>* using *<Grid component>*_._              *<subtasks>* * A *_decision maker_* must understand *_<information that must be documented>_*. * A _*decision maker*_ must be able to follow a procedure to *_<task to be documented>_*. * A _*decision maker*_ must be able to troubleshoot problems with *_<task to be documented>_*.    h2. Decision maker (“business stakeholders”)  This user decides whether to use Grid for a POC or production network and directs a team of project leaders (architects), sysadmins, network/smart contract admins, and application developers.  Tasks: * Understand Grid at a very high level (with beautiful diagrams) * Decide if their team should try Grid * Determine the general resources for a POC (people)        If the decision maker is trying to decide to try Grid (as mentioned above), you don't actually decide to try Grid given that Grid is positioned as a framework and not an application.  However, a decision maker may decide to use Grid Product or one of the other Grid applications being built on top of the framework.  In addition, a decision maker may also decide to develop an application on top of Grid or while using the Grid framework, but that would be dependent on the context of their use case, applicability to Grid, and state of development of other functions, components, and primitives within the Grid framework.   For this story specifically, it might be best to lay out the differences here between the framework and applications being built on top, and rationalize the difference between them, and curate a 1 page summary (providing visual and context) of the value prop for both layers (framework and application).  Thoughts here?  Looking for feedback on my approach and if I'm heading astray from the spirit of this story.   ~agunde   ~amundson   ></body> </Action>
<Action id="61400" issue="40396" author="mattp" type="comment" body="I think we should create stories for the intended platform where the documentation would reside.  For example, I think we should have separate stories for what documentation would be on the project webpage, grid developer documentation, and handout or summary info for marketing purposes.  I&apos;ve created a bunch of offline documentation but struggle where to put it for feedback.  I can dump it here, but think it&apos;s more applicable for feedback and iteration in the context of the location in which it would reside." created="2019-07-01 21:07:24.0" updateauthor="mattp" updated="2019-07-01 21:07:24.0"/>
<Action id="61461" issue="40396" author="mattp" type="comment" body="Hey  ~agunde  - I updated the documentation plan document and included my initial thoughts as previously discussed. Let me know what feedback you or others have.  Thanks!" created="2019-07-03 22:20:13.0" updateauthor="mattp" updated="2019-07-03 22:20:13.0"/>
