<Issue id="34243" key="FAB-12247" number="12247" project="10002" reporter="altharp" creator="altharp" type="10001" summary="Use message code taxonomy in log messages" priority="2" resolution="10001" status="6" created="2018-10-01 15:47:43.0" updated="2020-01-22 22:32:26.0" resolutiondate="2020-01-22 22:32:26.0" votes="0" watches="2" workflowId="45569"> <description><! CDATA There is a need to more easily locate specific log messages and know what potential actions to take based on the messages. Log messages should include a message code so that they can be uniquely identified. This will facilitate problem investigation and will make it easier to identify symptoms of certain types of problems that are often indicated by a certain set of log messages.     Following are suggestions for organizing message codes. * Identify all Hyperledger Fabric logical components and subcomponents and create a message code prefix for each logical component (or a grouping of smaller related subcomponents). This message code prefix could be a unique string of a short sequence of letters with a name that relates to the component. * For each component, define groups of the possible types of messages and reserve ranges of message codes for each type of message. For example, messages in one area could be assigned a range of 1-999 and messages in another area could be assigned a range of 1,000-1,999, etc. A reason for creating ranges is to allow for future addition of message codes. * Include within the code whether the message is informational, warning, error, etc. Current messages are prefixed with this information, but if a message code approach is adopted, then this information could be included within the message code.     For example, a message code could look something like ENDORSER00123I. This has the component (ENDORSER), a message code of 00123, and a suffix of `I` for an informational message.     A current message looks like this:  {{2018-08-23 07:05:42.789 UTC  kvledger  CommitWithPvtData -> INFO 115  0m Channel  channel1 : Committed block  39236  with 1 transaction(s)}}     With a message code included, it would look something like this:  {{2018-08-23 07:05:42.789 UTC  kvledger  CommitWithPvtData -> KVLEDGER00115I  Channel  channel1 : Committed block  39236  with 1 transaction(s)}}  ></description> </Issue>
