<Action id="52807" issue="15754" author="latitiah" type="comment" created="2018-10-31 13:20:54.0" updateauthor="latitiah" updated="2018-10-31 13:20:54.0"> <body><! CDATA This epic still needs a test plan summary associated with it. Here is a quick guide for what the summary should contain. Thanks! {code} Functional Tests: - FAB-XXX1: Make sure config is accepted and turns on feature (Integration) - PersonA - FAB-XXX2: What happens when config is set wrong (unit) - PersonA - FAB-XXX3: When FeatureX is turned on in both ComponentA and ComponentB (End-to-end) - PersonB - FAB-XXX4: When FeatureX is turned on in ComponentA and not ComponentB (End-to-end) - PersonA  System Tests: - FAB-XXX5: How is performace impacted when sending 5 packets per second for 3 hours? - PersonC * Be sure to set the following config values on ComponentA as such: - FEATUREX=true - FEATURE_PATH=/some/path/for/my/feature * Be sure to send the messages using the foo SDK - FAB-XXX6: Is the feature and component stable when executing 10 packets per second for 1 week? - PersonC * Be sure to set the following config values on ComponentA as such: - FEATUREX=true - FEATURE_PATH=/some/path/for/my/feature {code}  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="67011" issue="15754" author="sykesm" type="comment" body="Stale" created="2020-01-22 19:05:28.0" updateauthor="sykesm" updated="2020-01-22 19:05:28.0"/>
<Action id="67614" issue="15754" author="nyet" type="comment" body="Re-opened, this is important to us, TIA" created="2020-01-22 22:56:29.0" updateauthor="nyet" updated="2020-01-22 22:56:29.0"/>
<Action id="67620" issue="15754" author="sykesm" type="comment" created="2020-01-23 13:52:21.0" updateauthor="sykesm" updated="2020-01-23 13:52:21.0"> <body><! CDATA > Re-opened, this is important to us, TIA  Thanks for the feedback.  This issue has been open for more than 9 months without an update. There are currently no plans to deliver this item in v2.0.0 (despite the fix version) and we have moved to an RFC process for feature proposals.  If you are interested in advancing this feature, we welcome your contribution. Please create the necessary RFC by following the process documented here: https://github.com/hyperledger/fabric-rfcs/tree/master  Thanks.    ></body> </Action>
<Action id="67621" issue="15754" author="sykesm" type="comment" body="Closing with request to follow-up with an RFC using the processes that proposed and accepted last year." created="2020-01-23 13:53:08.0" updateauthor="sykesm" updated="2020-01-23 13:53:08.0"/>
