<Action id="33021" issue="20353" author="techwritingwhiz" type="comment" created="2017-10-23 21:55:34.0" updateauthor="techwritingwhiz" updated="2017-10-23 21:58:10.0"> <body><! CDATA  ~ashcherbakov  - I'm reviewing this ticket again.   Here are my questions:  *  Indy's GitHub page: which page is this? Is the Hyperledger Wiki-Indy page? * "Necessary docs".: what documents exactly should be included? Where are they located? Should the docs themselves be migrated or simply referenced via Link? * "docs in Githubs project's wiki" : What is the "github project" wiki? Is this the same as the Hyperledger Wiki-Indy page? docs in the Hyperleger wiki": Which docs need to be here and where can I find each of them? I've added some recently to this page (the Hyperledger Wiki-Indy page)  https://wiki.hyperledger.org/projects/indy  * "reference to other Google docs": Which docs are these and where can each of them be found?  * Where are the current CI/CD instructions?     Also:   In slack you mentioned that you wanted to create placeholder for some of these items in the current documentation. Which documents am I supposed to be creating placeholders in and where can they be found?   ></body> </Action>
<Action id="33152" issue="20353" author="ashcherbakov" type="comment" created="2017-10-25 09:06:50.0" updateauthor="ashcherbakov" updated="2017-10-25 09:06:50.0"> <body><! CDATA  ~TechWritingWhiz  I've started working on this task, so I'm going to send PR with updated documentation, and you can review it.  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="33396" issue="20353" author="techwritingwhiz" type="comment" body=" ~ashcherbakov  In your last comment, you said you be doing a pull request so I could review it. When that is done, will that pull request be placed here in the comments? I&apos;m only asking because I&apos;m not sure where I would be watching for that to come through. If you haven&apos;t done it yet, that is fine. I&apos;m just following up since it&apos;s on my radar. " created="2017-10-30 22:29:57.0" updateauthor="techwritingwhiz" updated="2017-10-30 22:29:57.0"/>
<Action id="33602" issue="20353" author="ashcherbakov" type="comment" created="2017-10-31 08:20:37.0" updateauthor="ashcherbakov" updated="2017-10-31 08:20:37.0"> <body><! CDATA  ~TechWritingWhiz  I'm still working on it. I will let you know (both here and in Slack) when I'm done.   ></body> </Action>
<Action id="33622" issue="20353" author="ashcherbakov" type="comment" created="2017-10-31 15:51:53.0" updateauthor="ashcherbakov" updated="2017-10-31 15:51:53.0"> <body><! CDATA  ~TechWritingWhiz  This is not a final version of a PR, but close to it: https://github.com/hyperledger/indy-node/pull/427 I think it will give an overview about the changes and structure I propose.  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="33649" issue="20353" author="techwritingwhiz" type="comment" body=" ~ashcherbakov  Thanks. I&apos;ve reviewed the changes. I&apos;m wondering how much of this information needs to referenced from the Hyperledger Wiki-Indy page. I&apos;m still confused as I haven&apos;t had my questions answered. In other words, I can see how some of these changes you made fulfill some of the bullet items of the ticket. However, I&apos;m not seeing how they fulfill the rest. I&apos;m also still unsure as to what it is exactly I need to be doing at this point. I&apos;m genuinely seeking clarification. " created="2017-10-31 20:31:15.0" updateauthor="techwritingwhiz" updated="2017-10-31 20:31:15.0"/>
<Action id="33666" issue="20353" author="ashcherbakov" type="comment" created="2017-11-01 08:19:36.0" updateauthor="ashcherbakov" updated="2017-11-01 08:19:36.0"> <body><! CDATA  ~TechWritingWhiz  Thanks for review.  {quote} I'm wondering how much of this information needs to referenced from the Hyperledger Wiki-Indy page. {quote} I think we can discuss it with  ~nage   ~SeanBohan_Sovrin   ~stevetolman .  Personally, I would prefer to have all information available on GitHub, so that we someone clones the project it has all required information embedded. I think we can duplicate some information in two places (GitHub and Indy Wiki). It will mean that we should take care of making the information in sync.  {quote} I'm also still unsure as to what it is exactly I need to be doing at this point {quote} I think we can merge my changes (after review of the content from other engineers). Then our QA can test the doc and scripts. And then you can take care of proper style, grammar, vocabulary, etc. if needed. Also you can extend/add more documentation if you think it's necessary. Would you agree with that plan?  {quote} In other words, I can see how some of these changes you made fulfill some of the bullet items of the ticket. {quote} -  Indy's GitHub page: which page is this? Is the Hyperledger Wiki-Indy page? I'm assuming this is https://github.com/hyperledger/indy-node - "Necessary docs".: what documents exactly should be included? Where are they located? Should the docs themselves be migrated or simply referenced via Link? I've asked a question in architecture channel about what docs can be shared and what docs can not.  I think it should be fine to reference the docs by links. Actually most of the design docs are rather some design/discussion docs, which are not very good for public. But probably we can still share them (better than nothing). Let's discuss this item in Slack in more details. Probably we will need to create a separate ticket to find out what docs we have, and what can be shared. Please find some links in the ticket description.  - "docs in Githubs project's wiki" : What is the "github project" wiki? Is this the same as the Hyperledger Wiki-Indy page? docs in the Hyperleger wiki": Which docs need to be here and where can I find each of them? I've added some recently to this page (the Hyperledger Wiki-Indy page) https://wiki.hyperledger.org/projects/indy There is also a wiki page on GitHub (for example, https://github.com/hyperledger/indy-plenum/wiki). So, as an option, we could put some documentation here as well. I think it's better to put documentation to either Hyperledger's Indy or into code instead.  As for the docs, the same answer as above. It's not clear and needs to be defined. Please find some links in the ticket description.  - "reference to other Google docs": Which docs are these and where can each of them be found?  The same, it needs to be find out what docs we may share. Please find some links in the ticket description.  - Where are the current CI/CD instructions There is (quite outdated) doc here:  Releases and CD pipelines architecture and Guides|https://docs.google.com/document/d/1gKf3F_r7WamoIYS_-ts2nruB2VIuiIpjmzPIVNf2VK0/edit#heading=h.sgv0qe7trz1p  Also I added this information to https://github.com/hyperledger/indy-node/blob/improve-doc/docs/ci-cd.md   ></body> </Action>
<Action id="33802" issue="20353" author="ashcherbakov" type="comment" created="2017-11-01 12:35:52.0" updateauthor="ashcherbakov" updated="2017-11-01 12:35:52.0"> <body><! CDATA PR: https://github.com/hyperledger/indy-node/pull/427 It doesn't contain yet all references to docs/designs, as we need to figure out what we can share.  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="34200" issue="20353" author="techwritingwhiz" type="comment" created="2017-11-01 19:17:32.0" updateauthor="techwritingwhiz" updated="2017-11-01 19:17:32.0"> <body><! CDATA  ~ashcherbakov .   _Personally, I would prefer to have all information available on GitHub, so that we someone clones the project it has all required information embedded._  _-_ This is fine. It just is not clear from the Hyperledger Wiki Indy page, that this is where the bulk of the info can be found. To fix that, I will simply mention it on that page as a note so at least the reader has a better idea of where to look for it. This will satisfy that need. There won't be a need to synchronize data at that point.   _Also you can extend/add more documentation if you think it's necessary._ _Would you agree with that plan?_  - Yes, that is fine. I agree with that.  _There is also a wiki page on GitHub (for example,  https://github.com/hyperledger/indy-plenum/wiki )._  _-_ This highlights why we are trying to streamline where documentation can be found, should be housed etc. I didn't know this existed until you mentioned it here. I know from discussions in the past the Hyperledger Wiki-Indy page should be the main "Hub" as a starting off jump point for all things Indy. There should only be one Wiki page. I propose that the information found in the wiki you mentioned above either be moved into a separate doc within the docs folder or be migrated to the main Wiki. If it has to do with the code, then it should stay in the "docs" folder for its repo.  _Probably we will need to create a separate ticket to find out what docs we have, and what can be shared._  _-_ I agree.   The rest of what you did, has been answered now. (Had to go through it a few times). :D   The Hyperledger Wiki-Indy page should be the main "hub" and all documentation related to the code, how the code works, etc... should be kept in the "docs" folder of the individual repos.      I'll put this ticket on the "back burner" for now, until I hear from someone they need me again.      ></body> </Action>
<Action id="34757" issue="20353" author="lovesh" type="comment" body=" ~TechWritingWhiz  The doc Anoncreds in Sovrin has been updated." created="2017-11-20 10:25:45.0" updateauthor="lovesh" updated="2017-11-20 10:25:45.0"/>
<Action id="35674" issue="20353" author="krw910" type="comment" created="2017-11-30 16:00:03.0" updateauthor="krw910" updated="2017-11-30 16:00:03.0"> <body><! CDATA  ~ashcherbakov  after discussing this with Misty we found the documents do not seem to be in the correct location.  Misty's instructions: The Hyperledger Wiki-Indy page should be the main "hub" and all documentation related to the code, how the code works, etc... should be kept in the "docs" folder of the individual repos.   We should not be adding information to the Hyperledger GitHub wiki, they should be in the correct docs folder for the repo they belong to. Please correct this and provide updated links when this is done.  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="35675" issue="20353" author="ashcherbakov" type="comment" created="2017-11-30 16:05:07.0" updateauthor="ashcherbakov" updated="2017-11-30 16:05:07.0"> <body><! CDATA  ~krw910  There is no new documentation added to Hyperldeger GitHub Indy. All new docs are added as .md in the source code. The only doc in GitHub wiki is a Plenum doc, but this is pretty old, not new, and not in the scope of this ticket. Moreover, this wiki in plenum will be deprecated soon.  I think we need to create a new ticket if we see some old documentation that needs to be moved. This task was about adding new docs.  ></body> </Action>
