<Issue id="33369" key="FAB-11807" number="11807" project="10002" reporter="pandrejko" assignee="joe-alewine" creator="pandrejko" type="10100" summary="Create a fabric deployment guide" priority="2" resolution="10002" status="6" created="2018-08-30 15:38:42.0" updated="2018-08-30 15:52:33.0" resolutiondate="2018-08-30 15:52:33.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="44657"> <description><! CDATA Here are my notes from the meeting with Gari and Chris:  Customers want to know how to deploy an e2e fabric solution, using the fabric CA client to generate their certs.  How to set things up?  How to modify the network?  Describe `here are the things you need to do...` - * What info do you need and how do you get it? * You need an ordering service then you Stand up peers that may or may not be connected. How to set it up incrementally? * Where is the ordering service, how do I set up the ordering service? How to bring it up? *  How do I create the genesis block?  * When you setup a peer/here are things you need to know to setup a peer * Now that I have a remote peer, what can I do with it? * Where am I connecting it to - an anchor peer in another org? What info do you need to connect it.  * How do I setup an anchor peer * If you want to use TLS, what do you need to do? How to get the TLS cert? * How do you configure peers and get them to work together? * How do I create a channel? * What info do I need from the orgs (msps) * How to use Join channel api on the peer? * How to fetch the genesis block? * How to install & instantiate chaincode? * How to use the fabric-ca vs embed own cryptographic material externally * Guidance on setup for HA * What monitoring do I need to do?Here’s the processes you need to be monitoring. Here’s your log files….. * There’s a network running over here - how do I connect to that network? * We support Kafka - recommended config is: Min 4 Kafka brokers, replica config of 3. Get the Orderer config info from your kafka cluster * Message hub - Kafka as a service in blue mix - ibm event streams = message hub for icp - need to document - use this for 6 months and then switch over to RAFT     ></description> </Issue>
