<Issue id="24633" key="FAB-7226" number="7226" project="10002" reporter="jeffgarratt" assignee="jeffgarratt" creator="jeffgarratt" type="10002" summary="Governance model for New Feature/Improvement process" priority="3" resolution="10001" status="6" created="2017-11-30 14:58:54.0" updated="2020-01-22 22:17:40.0" resolutiondate="2020-01-22 22:17:40.0" votes="0" watches="2" workflowId="42722"> <description><! CDATA h1. Proposing this model as a mechanism for governance with respect to New Features and Improvements.     Acknowledgement:      originator:  ~jeffgarratt     h2. Architecture Definition and Component Model   I would propose the following definitions for architecture for the purposes of discriminating which proposals comprise an architectural impact (Hence forth labeled ARCH).  The components of the fabric system are illustrated along with their relationships.  This is of importance as the labeling of changes having an architectural impact will be a condition of the proposed governance model.     !gov_components_and_arch_def.png|thumbnail!    h2.  Fabric Community Governance Model   Below is a class diagram depicting the proposed governance model for the fabric community.   It conveys the concepts of voting and the variant Roles participants can have, as well as the type of Votes that can be made.  The key concept is the 'GoverningArtifact' which includes at the highest level the New Feature and Improvement JIRA types, and the secondary level, Analysis and Design (A&D) issues as JIRA Tasks.  I propose that these issues utilize Gherkin syntax (or at least be written without technical details) as to allow for the greatest level of comprehension across participants and to force the verbalization of the actual value before delving into technical details.     !gov_fabric_community_model.png|thumbnail!       h2. Governing Artifact State Machine (Voting Workflow)  Below is a state machine indicating the workflow of GoverningArtifcats (e.g. New Feature/Improvement and A&D documents).     !gov_state_machine.png|thumbnail!     ></description> </Issue>
