<Action id="65470" issue="42998" author="andrew-coleman" type="comment" created="2019-11-12 13:40:27.0" updateauthor="andrew-coleman" updated="2019-11-12 13:40:27.0"> <body><! CDATA Not sure I fully understand this.  The network config doesn't require any channel information for this to work (as is the case with IBP2).  As a minimum, there needs to be information on the Org and at least one peer (the gateway peer) in order to invoke discovery.  From that it can access multiple network channels.  Please could you post your sample config json and client code that you believe demonstrates this problem?  Thanks.  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="65472" issue="42998" author="aatkddny" type="comment" created="2019-11-12 13:58:39.0" updateauthor="aatkddny" updated="2019-11-12 13:58:39.0"> <body><! CDATA It's pretty simple to understand.  I'll use the IBP2 example since it's the one I'm having an issue with.  You'll forgive me if I don't post real connection profiles on a public stage.   Imagine a consortium with 4 orgs A,B,C,D and two channels I and J. I has parties A,B,C and J has parties A,B,D  For simplicity we will consider only User X at org A. Extrapolate for the rest. There exists two sets of returned channel config json for Org A.  One for I listing peers for A,B,C and one for J with info for A,B,D.   It used to be that you'd put all the consortium orgs into the network config and the channel piece would say which were members of this channel. Now only members of this channel are returned.    As written, UserX needs two gateways if they want to interact with both I and J.  One to interact with I and one to interact with J. There's no supplemental #loadFromNetworkConfig that I can find to add a second channel to the gateway. This is going to lead to an unneeded proliferation of gateway objects when the client (HFClient) already supports multiple channels.     ></body> </Action>
<Action id="70749" issue="42998" author="lesleyannj" type="comment" body="Closing - intended to be addressed under new Fabric Gateway work - see https://github.com/hyperledger/fabric-rfcs/pull/32" created="2020-11-19 15:51:07.0" updateauthor="lesleyannj" updated="2020-11-19 15:51:07.0"/>
