<Issue id="42383" key="IS-1377" number="1377" project="10401" reporter="esplinr" creator="esplinr" type="10000" summary="LibVCX support for Aries protocols" priority="3" status="10200" created="2019-09-17 17:26:30.0" updated="2019-12-24 11:04:55.0" votes="0" watches="2" workflowId="55439"> <description><! CDATA *Story* As a developer of an application using LibVCX for credential exchange, I want my application to be interoperable with Aries agents.  Specifically, applications built on LibVCX should be able to hold credentials issued by ACA-py or by Evernym's Verity, and issue credentials to StreetCred / OSMA or Connect.Me.  *Acceptance Criteria* * In addition to the current protocols it supports, LibVCX needs to support the following Aries protocols: ** connect (DID Exchange) ** issuance ** proving * LibVCX needs to be tested for compatibility against the Aries Cloud Agent Python, and mobile agents such as StreetCred and OSMA. * LibVCX should also past the Aries protocol test suite, in whatever state it is at the time this work is done. * The LibVCX application API should change as little as possible so that client applications receive the benefits of the Aries protocols with minimal additional effort.  *Limitations* * *LibVCX should use Dummy Cloud Agent (or proprietary implementation) as a mediator to have an endpoint* ** There will be custom protocol between VCX and mediator for initial implementation to support DID Exchange with Aries-compatible agent.  * *To keep LibVCX API current public states of protocols would be kept. It means that libvcx would make some decisions to process more granular steps from community protocols* * LibVCX currently expects that *all connections are started by the issuer agent, not by the mobile agent*. This could make it *difficult to pass both directions* of the connection test. It may be necessary to raise a separate issue for implementing the connections initiated by the mobile agent.  *Note* * *IS-1392 IS-1180 IS-1393 and IS-1394 are required for MVP* * The Evernym agency should be updated to be a mediator as well (similar to IS-1392) and for proprietary implementation more (against dummy) changes are expected * This effort for LibVCX will make the transition to Aries easier, but will not need to be maintained long term because the Aries architecture will be significantly different. Completing the effort quickly is more important than a flexible architecture. * Test coverage should be improved right after publishing the MVP version * The Aries Interop Profile V1 shown in RFC 302 should include all the work needed for interoperability in Credential Exchange, but practical interop is more important than RFC compliance: https://github.com/hyperledger/aries-rfcs/tree/master/concepts/0302-aries-interop-profile ** The following modifications are expected to RFC0302 *** Exclude: Basic Message, Timing, Transport Return Route, Trust Ping only needs to respond *** Also might include: Please-ACK, Service Decorator (for the ephemeral proofs use case) *** We will not support the deprecated v1 cred exchange in RFC0303  ></description> </Issue>
