<Issue id="14148" key="FABN-175" number="175" project="10604" reporter="jjjjibm" assignee="jimthematrix" creator="jjjjibm" type="10004" summary=" fabric-SDK  chain.setPreFetchMode() takes an undocumented parameter" priority="2" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2017-01-18 03:06:13.0" updated="2018-07-19 00:53:07.0" resolutiondate="2017-04-05 18:43:13.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="33906"> <environment><! CDATA Fabric-node-SDK cloned yesterday.   ></environment> <description><! CDATA The implementation of setPreFetchMode in chain.js is this:  /** 	 * Set prefetch mode to true or false. 	 */ 	setPreFetchMode(preFetchMode) { 		this._preFetchMode = preFetchMode; 	}  Clearly, setPreFetchMode() takes a parameter.   However, the generated documentation does not mention the parameter:  setPreFetchMode()  Set prefetch mode to true or false.   Here's another:  code :  /** 	 * Set the tcert batch size. 	 */ 	setTCertBatchSize(batchSize) { 		this._tcertBatchSize = batchSize; 	}  docs/gen:   setTCertBatchSize()  Set the tcert batch size.  Example of method with documented inputs:  From class Client  setUserContext(user, skipPersistence)  Sets an instance of the User class as the security context of self client instance. This user’s credentials (ECert), or special transaction certificates that are derived from the user's ECert, will be used to conduct transactions and queries with the blockchain network. Upon setting the user context, the SDK saves the object in a persistence cache if the “state store” has been set on the Client instance. If no state store has been set, this cache will not be established and the application is responsible for setting the user context again if the application crashes and is recovered. Parameters: Name 	Type 	Description user 	User 	  An instance of the User class encapsulating the authenticated user’s signing materials (private key and enrollment certificate) skipPersistence 	boolean 	  Whether to skip saving the user object into persistence. Default is false and the method will attempt to save the user object to the state store.  How to recreate: 1.Cllone fabric-sdk-node 2.gulp doc from <fabric-sdk-node> 3.cd to fabric-sdk-node/docs 4.python -m SimpleHTTP  /* start HTTP server on your VM */ 5.In a browser, <your VM  ip>:8000 and follow the bouncing ball.     ></description> </Issue>
