<Issue id="14591" key="FAB-2088" number="2088" project="10002" reporter="elli-androulaki" assignee="jimthematrix" creator="elli-androulaki" type="10001" summary="As an infrastructure developer I want to be able to perform proper access control on event registration upon received requests" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2017-02-07 10:56:08.0" updated="2018-07-20 18:55:34.0" resolutiondate="2017-04-19 22:07:30.0" votes="0" watches="2" workflowId="37327"> <description><! CDATA As per today's discussion with  ~jimthematrix ,  ~binhn ,  ~muralisr :  Ultimately, this issue aims at the implementation of a channel-basis access control check upon an event registration request. Currently event infrastructure does not support per-chain requests. Therefore we can identify the following steps towards enforcing access control at event registration.  1. Treat the event registration as a chain-free request, and request that the creator of an event registration request is a member of the same organisation as the peer the request is submitted to. Limitations: (i) requires an one-to-one mapping between MSPs and organisations (also considered by current gossip protocols), (ii) cannot accommodate cases of applications that do not own their own peer.   2. Ensure that the creator of the event registration request is allowed to read all the channels the peer (the request is submitted to ) has joined. This assumes a static channel configuration and the check is needed to be repeated each time the peer joins a new channel.   3. Ensure that the creator of the event registration request is allowed to read all the channels the peer (the request is submitted to) has joined. This assumes a dynamic channel configuration, and the check needs to be repeated each time a new (valid) config block is received.   4. The creator registers on events on a per-channel basis, and read policies of the intended channel are checked. This check needs to be repeated each time that channel's is reconfigured.   ></description> </Issue>
