<Issue id="19397" key="INDY-446" number="446" project="10303" reporter="slafranca" assignee="danielhardman" creator="slafranca" type="10004" summary="Node promotion failed if pool is restarted and the primary node does not start." priority="3" resolution="10000" status="10001" created="2017-07-20 22:26:31.0" updated="2019-03-29 20:32:46.0" resolutiondate="2019-03-29 20:32:46.0" votes="0" watches="3" timeoriginalestimate="10800" timeestimate="10800" workflowId="19397"> <description><! CDATA I have 7 nodes, the primary node is node 1, backup nodes are node 2 and 3.  I simultaneously turned the sovrin service off on all 7 nodes.  I started the sovrin service for the nodes in reverse order.  The service started for nodes 7,6,5,4,3.  {color:#205081}The sovrin service is running on nodes 3-7{color}   When I look at the log to see which node is the primary node, it still says {color:#14892c}node 1 is the primary{color} with node 2 and 3 as the backup.  I waited a few minutes to see if the nodes would promote a new primary node since nodes 1 and 2 are offline.  They did not.  I sent a NYM transaction to the pool, waited a few minutes and checked the log again to see if a new primary node was promoted.  The primary node was still set to 1, with a backup of 2 and 3 and the NYM transaction did not get processed.  At this point, {color:#205081}the sovrin service is running on nodes 3-7{color}.  I started the service on node 2 and sent another transaction after waiting for a few minutes for the node to come back online.  The primary node is still set to 1.  {color:#205081}The sovrin service is running on nodes 2-7{color}.  I started the sovrin service on node 1.  As soon as the sovrin service came online for node 1, the NYM transactions were processed and the primary node was node 1.  {color:#205081}The sovrin service is running on all 7 nodes{color}.  *Expected results:* When I started the last five nodes, I expected the nodes to start the process of promoting a new primary node with 2 backup nodes.    ></description> </Issue>
