<Issue id="44401" key="FAB-17529" number="17529" project="10002" reporter="caod" assignee="caod" creator="caod" type="10004" summary="Cleanup config package" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2020-02-24 20:18:49.0" updated="2020-03-16 19:23:28.0" resolutiondate="2020-03-03 15:52:01.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="58309" archived="N"> <description><! CDATA Comments * * TH *  #761| https://github.com/hyperledger/fabric/pull/761   Comments should be clarified (ex. Policy "encodes") * * TH *   #761| https://github.com/hyperledger/fabric/pull/761   Add comments to fields in exported structs * * TH *   #761| https://github.com/hyperledger/fabric/pull/761   Resources.DefaultModPolicy comments (describe options) * Skip as foreign comment mentions instance plus additional clarification on what the field actually means/does * * TH *   #761| https://github.com/hyperledger/fabric/pull/761   Better comments around addValue * Comments for functions in general should consider potential failure paths/behavior and options for parameters or various paths (what does the consumer expect to be returned in various cases)  Errors * -* TH *  #742| https://github.com/hyperledger/fabric/pull/742   Fix errors to be more clear (ex. profile's channel ID is empty), use required over "is empty"- * -* TH *  #742| https://github.com/hyperledger/fabric/pull/742   Potentially reword some of these errors to be less verbose. See os package errors for examples, try to lessen the amount of chaining of "failed to ..."-  General * -* CL * Consortium should just have a name field instead of consortiums being a map from name to consortium- * -* DC * ( #754|https://github.com/hyperledger/fabric/pull/754 ) use generateOrgConfigGroup for orderer/application/consortium org config groups (remove existing functions for new___OrgGroup)- * -* DC * ( #754|https://github.com/hyperledger/fabric/pull/754 ) generateOrgConfigGroup should also have logic for anchor peers- * -* CL * Compute should become ComputeConfigUpdate,-  * -* CL * Consistent naming for params (if we call a config "profile" we should keep calling it that etc), or clearer naming on what the config applies to- * -* CL * Consistency and clarity on function names (create vs make vs new vs generate). Consider whether we even need the "create" at the beginning of the function- * -* CL * Use MatchJSON in tests instead of comparing string representation- * -* DC * ( #754|https://github.com/hyperledger/fabric/pull/754 ) Group imports (standard library at top), editor should handle this if you save after removing whitespaces between package imports-  Signing * * WL * CreateSignatureHeader should not be on the SigningIdentity (just put it in the config package and pass it the identity), same for Serialize * * WL * Don't export most of the signing stuff * Confirm whether we need toLowS for signatures * * WL * SigningIdentity does not implement crypto.Signer (Sign function parameters are missing) * * WL * SigningIdentity does not need 3 instances of public key (get from private) * * WL * NewSigningIdentity constructor does not need to exist * * WL * Modify types on SigningIdentity (no more pem cert, just provide the x.509) * * WL * Remove methods for decoding pem * * WL * MSPId() should be MSPID() * * WL * SigningIdentity should implement crypto.Signer (add Public() function) * * WL * Don't need nil check for interfaces (ex. Sign's reader io.Reader) * * WL * Support handling specific types of identities for signing (ecdsa vs rsa, etc) * What does 24 bytes for the nonce mean? * * WL * Fix spelling of Serialize error * * TH *  - #742| https://github.com/hyperledger/fabric/pull/742   Remove nil checks in CreateSignedConfigUpdateEnvelope- * -* CL * createSignedEnvelopeWithTLSBinding channelHeader timestamp might want to use  https://github.com/golang/protobuf/blob/d23c5127dc24889085f8ccea5c9d560a57a879d8/ptypes/timestamp.go#L103 -  ></description> </Issue>
