<Issue id="16435" key="FAB-3714" number="3714" project="10002" reporter="mbwhite" creator="mbwhite" type="10001" summary="Provision of scripts to enable start/stop of Fabric instances for dev/test usage" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2017-05-08 08:49:17.0" updated="2018-10-01 13:11:24.0" resolutiondate="2018-07-09 18:23:26.0" votes="1" watches="3" workflowId="38381"> <description><! CDATA *Premise:* For developers using Fabric or any other tools/systems, eg Composer they really get benefits testing their applications/scenarios using as real a backend system as possible.  Both functional and non-function behaviours are important.   The great power of Fabric comes at the price of having many configuration options to start a specific set of peers, ca etc. But for developers they would like to have a small set of good practice setups they can start/stop/teardown.    This means that in development/test phases they can focus on their application/scenario - and in production, they can call upon admins or other online services to actually run correct Fabric setup.      *Scripts:*  As part of the Composer project, we wanted to give a developer a simple place to start with a Fabric instance. Therefore we took some of the Fabric system tests scripts and put them together in an easy to consume manner.   The current culmination of these in the repo..  https://github.com/mbwhite/fabric-dev-servers   At present these are focused around the node.js centric world of the Composer developer.  However they are not specific to Composer - but they do use node and npm to control the scripting. (as well as BASH).     *Requirements:*  The aim is to have a setup of very simple *start, stop, teardown, download* scripts that a developer can call. They should know the absolute minimum of Fabric configuration. Defaults should be assumed for everything.  At present, the only choice is 0.6 or 1.0 with 1.0 being the default.   As a developer becomes more confident or knowledgeable in Fabric they can take the scripts and modify them if they wish. However, this job would ideally be the job of a Fabric Admin Role.   Not all app devs will want/wish to be Fabric admins.         ></description> </Issue>
