<Action id="35894" issue="24806" author="danielhardman" type="comment" created="2017-12-06 00:46:32.0" updateauthor="danielhardman" updated="2017-12-06 00:47:42.0"> <body><! CDATA Chat transcript between Andy T and Daniel H:     Andy T @danielh Does the Getting Started guide work? Some clear and loud feedback from here in Finland that developers who are interested in Sovrin are getting turned off because Getting Started does not work. Feedback is that this "hello world" stuff must work to keep developers engaged. They try it, it doesn't work, they ditch it and never come back, but they don't say anything about it so we never found out that they try. To ensure we get developer support, we need a slick Getting Started that *just works*. So, could you please check and let me know if Getting Started works, and if not can we get it working reliably and consistently please Thanks!     danielh We test that Getting Started works, before every release. However, it is possible that the people who are reporting failure are trying to go through the tutorial differently from our testers. I am asking Kelly to do some fact-finding.     danielh Response from Kelly: In this next release of Stable we have rebranded from Sovrin to Indy so all the commands that were sovrin are now indy. The Guide has been updated to reflect the new commands, but the build is still in RC waiting for TGB approval before moving to the Stable repo. So we have a guide that does not match the current code. At least that is the working theory without knowing more.     danielh I recommend that you connect the people reporting trouble directly to Kelly Wilson, so he can compare their workflow to what we are testing. Do we have the names of the people who are failing?  Here is what sovrin support had to say about it: I think it will work for them if 1) they are on stable 2) the link to the vagrant setup is corrected to “ https://github.com/evernym/sovrin-environments/blob/stable/vagrant/training/vb-multi-vm/TestSovrinClusterSetup.md ” GitHub evernym/sovrin-environments sovrin-environments - Environments for standing up Sovrin for different use cases.     Andy T Hi Daniel - thanks for the input. I will be with some of the guys that have tried this today here in Finland so will point them at Kelly. Ideally I’d like something more definitive than “I _think_ it will work”. If there are tweaks or workarounds that are needed, these should be clear in the instructions. Unfortunately I’m at a bit of a disadvantage as I don’t have the technical know-how these days to try it myself otherwise I’d be rather more helpful in my feedback!     Andy T Another observation. That link that support provided doesn’t shout “Getting Started Guide” all over it, and it’s in Evernym’s github. There was a getting started in the Indy github but I can’t seem to find it. Any other devs will have similar trouble I imagine. Is there a way to clearly signpost the getting started from the Indy repos?  Looking at the Hyperledger Indy Wiki, it points me to this page, which is different to the one that Mike Bailey pointed to above:  https://github.com/hyperledger/indy-node/blob/stable/getting-started.md . If there are multiple versions it will be easy to get out of sync.  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="37028" issue="24806" author="ashcherbakov" type="comment" body=" ~krw910  Who should start working on this task? Is it  ~TechWritingWhiz ?" created="2017-12-13 08:07:13.0" updateauthor="ashcherbakov" updated="2017-12-13 08:07:13.0"/>
<Action id="37069" issue="24806" author="ozheregelya" type="comment" created="2017-12-13 18:30:55.0" updateauthor="ozheregelya" updated="2017-12-19 16:34:10.0"> <body><! CDATA INDY-1056: Document *Running a Simulation of a Indy Cluster and Agents* ( https://github.com/hyperledger/indy-node/blob/stable/docs/cluster-simulation.md ): {code:java} $ pip install -U --no-cache-dir indy-client{code} {code:java} >>> from indy_client.test.training.getting_started import * {code} indy-client does not exist. It should be indy-node or sovrin instead of indy-client.   INDY-1059: Document *Indy – Running the Getting Started tutorial locally* ( https://github.com/hyperledger/indy-node/blob/stable/docs/indy-running-locally.md  ) Script _setupEnvironment.sh_ is not actual after file/folder changes (INDY-831 - INDY-833). Node data are placed in /var/lib/indy, not in ~/.indy.  INDY-1059: Document *Indy – Running the Getting Started tutorial locally* ( https://github.com/hyperledger/indy-node/blob/stable/docs/indy-running-locally.md  ) {code:java} python /usr/lib/python3.5/site-packages/indy_client/test/agent/faber.py --port 5555 python /usr/lib/python3.5/site-packages/indy_client/test/agent/acme.py --port 6666 python /usr/lib/python3.5/site-packages/indy_client/test/agent/thrift.py --port 7777{code} Paths to agent scripts are wrong, network parameter is absent. Correct commands: {code:java} python /usr/local/lib/python3.5/dist-packages/indy_client/test/agent/faber.py  --port 5555 --network <network_name> python /usr/local/lib/python3.5/dist-packages/indy_client/test/agent/acme.py  --port 6666 --network <network_name> python /usr/local/lib/python3.5/dist-packages/indy_client/test/agent/thrift.py  --port 7777 --network <network_name>{code} INDY-1060: Document *Setting Up a Test Indy Network in VMs* (master, stable) Broken link  https://github.com/evernym/sovrin-environments/blob/stable/vagrant/sandbox/DevelopmentEnvironment/Vagrantfile  here: "...you may continue setting up an actual Developer Environment connected to a sandbox by following these {color:#d04437}instructions{color}."  INDY-1060: Document *Setting Up a Test Indy Network in VMs* (  https://github.com/evernym/sovrin-environments/blob/master/vagrant/training/vb-multi-vm/TestIndyClusterSetup.md  ) Wrong formatting: !formatting.jpg|thumbnail! As far as I understand, text marked with red arrows should be formatted as text, not as code.   INDY-1060: Document *Setting Up a Test Indy Network in VMs* Mixed up links. Master version of this document  https://github.com/evernym/sovrin-environments/blob/master/vagrant/training/vb-multi-vm/TestIndyClusterSetup.md  links to stable version of GST  https://github.com/hyperledger/indy-node/blob/stable/getting-started.md    INDY-1062: Document *Getting Started with Indy*  broken link  https://github.com/evernym/sovrin-environments/blob/stable/vagrant/sandbox/DevelopmentEnvironment/Vagrantfile  here: Note: If you're looking to create an actual Developer Environment connected to a sandbox, please visit this _{color:#d04437}guide{color}_ instead.   INDY-1062: Document *Getting Started with Indy* Wrong output of command _load sample/faber-request.indy_ in example: ALICE> load sample/faber-request.indy {color:#d04437}New wallet Default created{color} {color:#d04437}Active wallet set to "Default"{color} 1 connection request found for Faber College. Creating Connection for Faber College.   Try Next:     show connection "Faber College"     accept request from "Faber College"   New wallet Default will not be created because wallet Alice was created manually on one of previous steps.    INDY-1062: Document - *Getting Started with Indy* Links to vagrant instruction ( https://github.com/evernym/sovrin-environments/blob/stable/vagrant/training/vb-multi-vm/TestIndyClusterSetup.md ) are still broken for both of stable and master versions. These links also should accord to master/stable instruction version.  INDY-1060: Need to document that vagrant instruction does not work on host ubuntu system due to vagrant issue:  https://github.com/hashicorp/vagrant/issues/7155  (see comments below).  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="37554" issue="24806" author="ozheregelya" type="comment" created="2017-12-17 17:02:28.0" updateauthor="ozheregelya" updated="2017-12-17 17:02:28.0"> <body><! CDATA  ~krw910 ,  ~danielhardman ,  One major problem was noticed during verification of documentation. Vagrant installation is impossible on host ubuntu system due to Vagrant issue:  https://github.com/hashicorp/vagrant/issues/7155   Should this information be included to Vagrant instruction?  For host windows system all works well.  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="37555" issue="24806" author="ozheregelya" type="comment" body="Problem in Vagrant script for validator: INDY-1046 (actual only for master version, stable works well)." created="2017-12-17 17:09:57.0" updateauthor="ozheregelya" updated="2017-12-17 17:34:00.0"/>
<Action id="37570" issue="24806" author="ozheregelya" type="comment" body="Problem in Vagrant script for agent: INDY-1048 (actual only for master version, stable works well)." created="2017-12-18 11:43:01.0" updateauthor="ozheregelya" updated="2017-12-18 11:43:01.0"/>
<Action id="37590" issue="24806" author="krw910" type="comment" body=" ~ozheregelya  On Vagrant and Ubuntu lets go ahead and make sure that gets documented and you can provide the link to the vagrant ticket from hashicorp." created="2017-12-18 16:14:20.0" updateauthor="krw910" updated="2017-12-18 16:14:20.0"/>
<Action id="37652" issue="24806" author="ozheregelya" type="comment" body="New tickets for documentation problems were created (INDY-1056, INDY-1059, INDY-1060, INDY-1062), so this one can be closed." created="2017-12-19 22:19:37.0" updateauthor="ozheregelya" updated="2017-12-19 22:19:37.0"/>
<Action id="38206" issue="24806" author="techwritingwhiz" type="comment" body="Tickets INDY-1059, INDY-1060, and INDY-1062 have all had pull requests submitted. Still waiting on clarification on INDY-1056. " created="2018-01-04 23:01:34.0" updateauthor="techwritingwhiz" updated="2018-01-04 23:01:34.0"/>
