<Issue id="46325" key="FAB-18342" number="18342" project="10002" reporter="joe-alewine" creator="joe-alewine" type="10100" summary="Remove references to system channel" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2020-11-16 14:14:37.0" updated="2021-02-03 21:55:00.0" resolutiondate="2021-02-03 21:55:00.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="60241" archived="N"> <description><! CDATA Documentation of the requirement for a system channel exists in the following locations and must be changed to reflect the participation API process:  Key concepts: - xMembership membership/membership.md - xBlockchain network network/network.html - xPolicies policies/policies.md - xCapabilities capabilities_concept.md  Arch ref: - xDefining capability requirements capability_requirements.rst  Command ref: - (not required) Configtxgen commands/configtxgen.md  Tutorials - xUpdating a channel configuration config_update.md - xCreating a channel create_channel.md (must wait for test network updates) - xUsing configtx.yaml to build a channel configuration create_channel_config.md - xUsing the Fabric test network test_network.md (must wait for update to samples) -  Operations Guides - xChannel configuration (configtx) configtx.rst - Migrating from Kafka to Raft kafka_raft_migration.md (potentially won't do — remove doc?) - xMembership service providers msp.rst - xSetting up an ordering node orderer_deploy.md - xConfiguring and operating a Raft ordering service raft_configuration.md -  Upgrading to the latest release - xUpgrading to the latest release upgrade.rst - xEnabling the new chaincode lifecycle enable_cc_lifecycle.md - xUpdating the capability level of a channel updating_capabilities.md - xConsiderations for getting to v2.x upgrade_to_newest_version.md     FAQ *  h6. xFabric-FAQ.rst  I would recommend that, in general, we do not refer to the participation as "new", but instead just refer to it as "the process". That will future proof these changes for when the participation API is not quite so new anymore.  ></description> </Issue>
