<Action id="52022" issue="32884" author="adnanchoudhury" type="comment" created="2018-10-10 15:14:16.0" updateauthor="adnanchoudhury" updated="2018-10-10 15:14:16.0"> <body><! CDATA With the CC-only Endorsement policy:  {code:java} =======  CONSTANT INVOKE Overall Performance Summary  ======= CONSTANT INVOKE Overall number of PTE: 2 CONSTANT INVOKE Overall processes: 2 CONSTANT INVOKE Overall transactions: sent 100000 received 100000 CONSTANT INVOKE Overall failures: proposal 0 transactions 0 CONSTANT INVOKE Overall event: received 100000 timeout 0 unreceived 0 CONSTANT INVOKE Overall time: start 1537465708507 end 1537468760911 duration 3052404 CONSTANT INVOKE Overall CONSTANT INVOKE *TPS 32.76* CONSTANT INVOKE Overall latency summary CONSTANT INVOKE Overall proposals latency 100000 min 7 ms max 988 ms avg 49.97 ms CONSTANT INVOKE Overall transactions latency 100000 min 5 ms max 13339 ms avg 9.81 ms CONSTANT INVOKE Overall events latency 100000 min 5 ms max 27493 ms avg 2852.52 ms  {code}    With each SBEP for all keys,  {code:java} =======  CONSTANT INVOKE Overall Performance Summary  ======= CONSTANT INVOKE Overall number of PTE: 2 CONSTANT INVOKE Overall processes: 2 CONSTANT INVOKE Overall transactions: sent 100000 received 100000 CONSTANT INVOKE Overall failures: proposal 0 transactions 0 CONSTANT INVOKE Overall event: received 100000 timeout 0 unreceived 0 CONSTANT INVOKE Overall time: start 1539179385679 end 1539182501350 duration 3115671 CONSTANT INVOKE Overall CONSTANT INVOKE TPS *32.10* CONSTANT INVOKE Overall latency summary CONSTANT INVOKE Overall proposals latency 100000 min 7 ms max 1143 ms avg 51.24 ms CONSTANT INVOKE Overall transactions latency 100000 min 5 ms max 5289 ms avg 9.66 ms CONSTANT INVOKE Overall events latency 100000 min 751 ms max 8226 ms avg 2808.69 ms CONSTANT INVOKE Overall TEST RESULTS PASSED {code}  From the TPS and other metrics, The SBEP does NOT seem to change the Invoke performance. This specific run saw only a 2% performance change, within the margin of error.   Tested on a Vlaunch server, will be re-tested on a cluster.   ></body> </Action>
<Action id="52633" issue="32884" author="adnanchoudhury" type="comment" body="https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/#/c/27034/" created="2018-10-25 13:34:39.0" updateauthor="adnanchoudhury" updated="2018-10-25 13:34:39.0"/>
