<Action id="36608" issue="25408" author="ales" type="comment" body=" ~jyellick ,  ~elli-androulaki ,  ~angelo.decaro ,  ~yacovm  pls weigh in. Thx!" created="2017-12-12 08:19:59.0" updateauthor="ales" updated="2017-12-12 08:19:59.0"/>
<Action id="36616" issue="25408" author="yacovm" type="comment" created="2017-12-12 10:53:15.0" updateauthor="yacovm" updated="2017-12-12 10:53:56.0"> <body><! CDATA {quote}However this might not be desirable, {quote} Why? I think that since we discuss an action item we would want to elaborate on the reasoning.     The way I see it, having a read set in the transaction has 2 uses: * It has the versions, and MVCC uses this to enforce writes based on old reads * You may want to record a read into the ledger, without it impacting the state.  Now, recall that the goal of the endorsement policy is to enforce that the simulation of a transaction has enough attestations from principals that the channel trusts.  After verifying that, and assuming the MVCC versions are correct - the channel now can trust that a chaincode has been executed correctly on up-to-date data.  Now: * You don't use the endorsement policy for MVCC checks of reads, since there is no write set. * Having a read recorded into the ledger doesn't change the state     So, as I see it - the only use of having a read set pass an endorsement policy check, is for: * Clients receiving the transaction as events and seeing the transaction is invalid (i.e it would not only catch endorsement thresholds, but also incorrect signatures) * Auditors that audit the validated ledger seeing that a read-only transaction is invalid.  I don't think the 2 use cases above are enough to justify this: * I don't think the client should care about read-only transactions sent via the events * I think that an auditor can just verify the signatures himself/herself, and just deduce from the last endorsement policy if the read was simulated on enough peers if he/she needs to do so.     Now, transaction that is a read-only is marked valid via VSCC even though it hasn't passed the endorsement policy. Right? So I think for this, is it possible that we'd want to add a new flag that says - "it's a read only, we don't know" since the policy isn't actually evaluated?  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="67201" issue="25408" author="sykesm" type="comment" body="Stale" created="2020-01-22 22:21:07.0" updateauthor="sykesm" updated="2020-01-22 22:21:07.0"/>
