<Action id="20734" issue="14334" author="wlahti" type="comment" body="We need more details of the information that should be logged for each of the actions listed. I&apos;m also not clear on the add/modify/delete user portion... Is that for users in the fabric-ca (formerly known as cop)?" created="2017-02-07 20:46:46.0" updateauthor="wlahti" updated="2017-02-07 20:46:46.0"/>
<Action id="20758" issue="14334" author="ptippett" type="comment" created="2017-02-08 14:19:34.0" updateauthor="ptippett" updated="2017-02-08 14:19:34.0"> <body><! CDATA Hi Will.  Saw your slack message but was in the middle of something and never got back.    In general, the purpose of the audit log is of course to keep track of which users are performing which actions, so if something bad/unexpected happens, you can go back and figure out if someone did something they shouldn't have, or if they did something that should have worked, but didn't, or if say a bunch of channels got deleted or you suspect a breach, you can see if there's a particular account that's doing things it shouldn't be, maybe it was hacked, and turn off that account.  I think for the add/delete it's simply:  Timestamp - UserID - Created/deleted channel/user <name or ID or whatever>.  For modifications, it's maybe a bit more complicated since it's not clear to me how much information we can and should report. IMO, minimally, it's: Timestamp - UserID - Modified channel/user <name or ID or whatever>.  With a more ideal solution (that if necessary we could move to over time I think) of something like:  Timestamp - UserID - performed action "add user Paul" or "modified channel batch size from 10 to 20" on channel <name or ID or whatever>.  In other words, the closer we can get to the exact modification/operation they performed, the better, with the desired solution being able to say exactly what they did.  The first example helps with "this account is modifying stuff they shouldn't be, we should turn them off" but doesn't help as much with "we had an outage around the time Paul modified some things, but he doesn't remember exactly what he did in what sequence to help us figure out what happened".  That's where the 2nd more specific example comes in.  As for the membership question, given that, at least now, membership is at an org level and a "member" is represented by a root cert which can come from our fabric CA or one they provide (via verisign or another fabric CA or whatever), I expect the requirement is to audit any change of those members.  Either adding, removing, or modifying.  It might be worth a conversation with Jason Yellick or Keith Smith to make sure they have a similar opinion.  I'll also forward this to Angel who is the one that gave me the requirement to see if he has any other thoughts or had more specific info from the users asking for this.  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="22722" issue="14334" author="binhn" type="comment" created="2017-04-19 17:22:44.0" updateauthor="binhn" updated="2017-04-19 17:37:09.0"> <body><! CDATA  ~ptippett   ~wlahti  Why would we want another log when we already have the ledger, which is the transaction log that contains this info, including MSPs.  Note that add/modify/delete user is not a concept in Fabric, but Fabric CA, so we should open a request there.   ></body> </Action>
<Action id="62324" issue="14334" author="mastersingh24" type="comment" body="No activity for around a year .... cleanup time" created="2019-07-30 02:47:06.0" updateauthor="mastersingh24" updated="2019-07-30 02:47:06.0"/>
