<Issue id="45665" key="FABN-1607" number="1607" project="10604" reporter="bestbeforetoday" assignee="harrisob@us.ibm.com" creator="bestbeforetoday" type="10004" summary="EventService start fails with future start block" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2020-07-21 17:08:58.0" updated="2020-08-19 14:47:29.0" resolutiondate="2020-08-19 14:47:29.0" votes="0" watches="3" workflowId="59573" archived="N"> <description><! CDATA It looks like the EventService start may fail due to a timeout before data is received on the gRPC stream in cases where a future start block is specified. Assuming this is the case, suggest resolving the EventService start promise at the point where the gRPC stream to the peer is established and do not use the data received timeout _only_ in the case where a start block has been explicitly specified.  Re-attaching a checkpoint listener may result in a future start block being specified. For example: # Register checkpoint listener # Remove checkpoint listener (at the point where it is up-to-date with currently committed blocks) # Re-register the checkpoint listener # The checkpointer's _next_ expected block is used as the start block when starting the EventService  Problem was reported on RocketChat by  ~braduf  - fabric-sdk-node (9th July 20). Text from RocketChat is below.  We are using the node sdk version 2.1.0 and when using a checkpointer for a contract listener or starting the listener from the latest block, the event service times out and we can't start the listener. If we start from older blocks, the listener starts without problems, but since it repeats the newer blocks, it is not what we need. Does anyone knows why this might be happening only when starting the EventService from the latest block?  This is the error log we get:  {noformat} 2020-06-25T15:49:21.600Z - error:  EventService : EventService peer0.*.com.co:9051  timed out after:3000 2020-06-25T15:49:21.601Z - error:  EventService : send peer0.*.com.co:9051  - #1 - Starting stream to peer0.*.com.co:9051 failed 2020-06-25T15:49:21.601Z - error:  BlockEventSource : Failed to start event service message=Event service timed out - Unable to start listening, stack=Error: Event service timed out - Unable to start listening at Timeout._onTimeout (*/node_modules/fabric-common/lib/EventService.js:40 {noformat}   ></description> </Issue>
