<Issue id="34747" key="FAB-12507" number="12507" project="10002" reporter="pandrejko" assignee="denyeart" creator="pandrejko" type="10100" summary="Questions around private data architecture" priority="2" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2018-10-17 13:41:23.0" updated="2019-07-15 11:29:57.0" resolutiondate="2018-10-20 20:08:57.0" votes="0" watches="3" workflowId="46157"> <description><! CDATA  docs/source/private-data-arch.rst|https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/#/c/26992/3/docs/source/private-data-arch.rst  Line  33|https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/#/c/26992/3/docs/source/private-data-arch.rst@33 : For example, in a channel with ten organizations, five of the organizations might be included in a private data collection distribution policy, but the endorsement policy might call for any three of the organizations to endorse. could we write it as - the endorsement policy might call for any three out of the five organizations to endorse.   Line  36|https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/#/c/26992/3/docs/source/private-data-arch.rst@36 : ``requiredPeerCount``: Minimum number of peers that the endorsing peer must successfully disseminate private data to before the peer signs the endorsement and returns the proposal response back to the client. Why do we need to distribute the private data before the peer signs the endorsement? The same is not the case for stateDB transactions.  Does it mean that every endorsing peer must send to #requiredPeerCount peers within the org?   Line  40|https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/#/c/26992/3/docs/source/private-data-arch.rst@40 : ``requiredPeerCount`` is ``0``, it means that no distribution is **required**, but there may be some distribution if ``maxPeerCount`` is greater than zero. A ``requiredPeerCount`` of ``0`` would typically not be recommended, as it could lead to loss of private data. Typically you would want to require at least some distribution of the private data at endorsement time to ensure redundancy of the private data on multiple peers in the network. In the private data tutorial( https://hyperledger-fabric.readthedocs.io/en/release-1.2/private_data_tutorial.html ), the collection policy states requiredPeerCount:0 and maxPeerCount:3; whereas the network has 2 peers per org. Endorsement Policy is default  Does the endorsing peer (peer0.org1) distribute the private data to peer1.org1, peer0.org2 and peer1.org2?  Peers in org2 do not have access to all the private collections; how does the endorsing peer decide which private data to distribute?  ></description> </Issue>
