<Action id="40987" issue="26979" author="lordgoodman" type="comment" created="2018-02-28 05:13:20.0" updateauthor="lordgoodman" updated="2018-02-28 05:13:20.0"> <body><! CDATA Hi baohua, I'm almost finished the deployment of this feature,  this comment is meant to briefly describe my work.  There are three kinds of images under the hyperledger/composer dockerhub repo, names and functions are listed below: # Composer-playground: Dashboard of Composer. # Composer-cli: Command line client of Composer. # Composer-rest-api:  RESTful API of Composer.  I only integrated the playground into cello, and Composer has an important concept named "card" which is used to import existing Fabric network, user can create and import cards manually through the playground, however, I prefer pre-create cards and import it into playground container, so that user can operate Fabric network directly once playground is running rather than create card files at first, but the generation of card files need the certificate of org's admin user, which means we need to regenerate the cards once crypto-config dir is updated.  I also have a concern,  Composer-playground need logs of memory and CPU resources to run, multiple playground containers running on the same docker host might cost a large performance degradation, maybe we should disable playground by default, and provide an option to set up playground while user creating chain.  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="40988" issue="26979" author="baohua" type="comment" created="2018-02-28 07:07:18.0" updateauthor="baohua" updated="2018-02-28 07:07:18.0"> <body><! CDATA  ~LordGoodman , thanks so much for your design.  I agree with your concern.  And would suggest:  1) We can use existing/pre-created credentials since the crypto-config is static now. We may change it to dynamic way later.  2) Yes, it costs resources, we may introduce some new network type/option in the dashboard to indicate whether wanna a composer. But i'm fine if you wanna make it by default and have a quick implementation. We can do the optimization later.  Thanks!  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="46928" issue="26979" author="baohua" type="comment" created="2018-07-05 01:49:26.0" updateauthor="baohua" updated="2018-07-05 01:49:26.0"> <body><! CDATA  ~LordGoodman  are u still working on this? Thanks!  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="46936" issue="26979" author="lordgoodman" type="comment" body="Yes I still working on this, I also welcome to any assistance." created="2018-07-05 10:21:18.0" updateauthor="lordgoodman" updated="2018-07-05 10:29:42.0"/>
