<Issue id="26609" key="FAB-7612" number="7612" project="10002" reporter="elli-androulaki" assignee="angelo.decaro" creator="elli-androulaki" type="10001" summary="Extension of MSPPrincipal proto to consider identity anonymity property" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2018-01-05 13:03:49.0" updated="2020-06-11 15:30:34.0" resolutiondate="2018-05-16 19:10:02.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="40885"> <description><! CDATA Identity Mixer supports anonymous identities. Therefore, a way to tell apart anonymous MSP identities from nominal needs to be introduced.   In order to do so, the following method is introduced in the MSP Identity interface:  {code:java} 	// Anonymous returns true if this is an anonymous identity, false otherwise 	Anonymous() bool {code}  The x509-based MSP Identities will always be nominal.  In order to allow the policy framework to reason about the anonymity of an identity, a new MSP Principal classification is introduced as follows:  {code:java} enum Classification { ROLE = 0;  // Represents the one of the dedicated MSP roles, the // one of a member of MSP network, and the one of an // administrator of an MSP network ORGANIZATION_UNIT = 1; // Denotes a finer grained (affiliation-based) // groupping of entities, per MSP affiliation // E.g., this can well be represented by an MSP's // Organization unit IDENTITY  = 2;    // Denotes a principal that consists of a single // identity        ANONYMITY = 3; // Denotes a principal that can be used to enforce an identity to be anonymous or nominal. } {code}  When the ANONYMITY classification is used, the MSPPrincipal#Principal must be the serialisation of the following protobuf message: {code:java} // MSPIdentityAnonymity can be used to enforce an identity to be anonymous or nominal. message MSPIdentityAnonymity {  enum MSPIdentityAnonymityType { NOMINAL = 0; // Represents a nominal MSP Identity ANONYMOUS = 1; // Represents an anonymous MSP Identity }  MSPIdentityAnonymityType anonymityType = 1;  } {code}   ></description> </Issue>
