<Issue id="15085" key="FABN-431" number="431" project="10604" reporter="jjjjibm" assignee="jimthematrix" creator="jjjjibm" type="10004" summary=" node-sdk  https://github.com/hyperledger/fabric-sdk-node -- Pluggability" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2017-02-27 22:53:05.0" updated="2018-07-19 00:54:03.0" resolutiondate="2017-04-05 18:38:30.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="34162"> <description><! CDATA In the readme at https://github.com/hyperledger/fabric-sdk-node in the section{color:#205081} Pluggability{color},    .. For each abstract class, a built-in implementation is included with the ability to load alternative implementations via designated environment variables: (a numbered list follows)  Items 1 and 2 in the list correlate an abstract class to an environment variable, as we would expect from the sentence prefacing the list.   a)  Item 3 does not mention an abstract class, or an environment variable.  Is something missing here about  how to plug in an alternate member service?  Or does this item belong outside the list?  b) The list is numbered, not bulleted.  For items that do not need to be in any particular order,  use a bulleted list.    c) To replace FileKeyValueStore with a different implementation  Should FileKeyValueStore be KeyStoreValue?  Should it be 'replace FileKeyValueStore.js with a diffferent  keyValueStore implementation'?   d) In the Modules pull down menu on this page, select api.  The description reads:   This module defines the API for the{color:#205081} pluggable {color}components of the node.js SDK.  Seeing the word pluggable, a reader will want to correlate this with the Pluggability section.  These classes are listed in the menu:  CryptoSuite, Key, and KeyStoreValue.  CryptoSuite and KeyStoreValue are mentioned in the numbered list in this Pluggability section.   Should Key be mentioned as well?  Or have pluggable components nothing to do with Pluggability as described in this section?  Or does the description for 'api' need to change ?     ></description> </Issue>
