<Action id="40454" issue="27314" author="denyeart" type="comment" body=" ~jyellick  What do you think?" created="2018-02-20 20:29:54.0" updateauthor="denyeart" updated="2018-02-20 20:29:54.0"/>
<Action id="40567" issue="27314" author="jyellick" type="comment" created="2018-02-22 14:48:27.0" updateauthor="jyellick" updated="2018-02-22 14:48:39.0"> <body><! CDATA This issue highlights a difference between how we treat native deployments and docker from a release perspective.  If users deploy using our docker images, then they get not only the correct binaries for the processes, but they also get updated base configuration files for those binaries, such as `orderer.yaml` and `core.yaml`. From a viper perspective, it's fairly imperative that these files are kept up to date. If a variable is not present in the yaml file, then it cannot be overridden in the environment, and it is a support nightmare if we cannot rely on env overrides to affect configuration.  For v1.1, `orderer.yaml` has a total of 40 new lines, including 6 new variables.  For `core.yaml` the total is 240 new lines, including 35 new variables. This excludes the nesting structure required for these new variables, as well as the inline documentation, and changed defaults. It is likely a futile goal to document each of these new variables in an effort to get users to add them to their files manually.  Instead, it makes the most sense that a user should start with the new config file, and using a tool like diff, port their changes from their old config file to their new one.  We can document this procedure, but this raises a question, where should the user get these configuration files from?  After discussion on #fabric-maintainers, there seemed to be a consensus that we must support non-docker deployments.   ~ChristopherFerris  Pointed out that we also do installations via go get and Mac homebrew.  He is interested especially in a consistent approach to dealing with the config files.   ~yacovm  Thought we should include the config files along side the release artifacts.  Personally, I'm in favor including the config files along with the release artifacts, as it is a sticking point for documenting upgrade at the moment.  Then, we can look at bringing the other installation methods into parity, but I welcome other opinions.  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="40577" issue="27314" author="mastersingh24" type="comment" body="I&apos;d vote for including them.  It&apos;s good to have them as reference in any case and better than having to keep updating the download link" created="2018-02-22 17:46:19.0" updateauthor="mastersingh24" updated="2018-02-22 17:46:19.0"/>
<Action id="40582" issue="27314" author="christopherferris" type="comment" created="2018-02-22 18:23:13.0" updateauthor="christopherferris" updated="2018-02-22 18:23:13.0"> <body><! CDATA ok, chatted with Gari, let's include them in the tarfile that we publish the binaries under config/ directory sibling of bin/  Chris  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="40616" issue="27314" author="rameshthoomu" type="comment" body="https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/#/c/18221/" created="2018-02-23 03:01:17.0" updateauthor="rameshthoomu" updated="2018-02-23 03:01:17.0"/>
