<Issue id="41246" key="FAB-15985" number="15985" project="10002" reporter="saikumar3349" creator="saikumar3349" type="10004" summary="Kafka and Zookeeper were not working after a restart in  Hyperledger Fabric Production Network?" priority="1" resolution="10203" status="6" created="2019-07-17 06:28:33.0" updated="2019-07-29 10:20:30.0" resolutiondate="2019-07-24 07:02:41.0" votes="0" watches="5" workflowId="54250"> <description><! CDATA I had created a multinode setup as follows:  system-1(zookeeper0,kafka0,orderer0)  system-2(zookeeper1,kafka1,orderer1)  system-3(zookeeper2,kafka2,orderer2)  system-4(kafka3,orderer3)  Persistence volumes has been created for orderer,peer,couchdb.  The network is running successfully with 5 channels and added huge data on one channel.  suddenly one system has been crashed due to insufficient resources. with this impact we tear down the whole network and we haven't removed the persistent volumes.  After that we had restarted the network once again by using the persistence of orderere,peer,couchdb.  we are able to see the channel list and chaincode list installed on the peers and also instantiated on channel. But when we are invoking any transaction on the channel. It is throwing an error as "Backing Kafka cluster has not completed booting.". when we check the topics on the kafka brokers, we are able to see the topics.  when we checked the orderer logs in DEBUG in mode. we have noticed the following error:  2019-07-16 19:04:28.646 UTC  orderer.consensus.kafka  try -> DEBU 14bf  channel:<channel_name>  Need to retry because process failed = kafka server: The requested offset is outside the range of offsets maintained by the server for the given topic/partition. 2019-07-16 19:04:28.646 UTC  orderer.consensus.kafka  startThread -> PANI 14c0  channel: <channel_name>  Cannot set up channel consumer = kafka server: The requested offset is outside the range of offsets maintained by the server for the given topic/partition.     Would be great if anyone help us.  ></description> </Issue>
