<Issue id="37268" key="FAB-13966" number="13966" project="10002" reporter="latitiah" assignee="latitiah" creator="latitiah" type="10101" summary="Negative Path: Different orgs use different version label during upgrade (org approval step)" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2019-01-30 15:07:56.0" updated="2019-04-02 23:51:37.0" resolutiondate="2019-04-02 23:51:37.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="48859"> <description><! CDATA Upgrade different chaincode versions on same channel.   Org1 executes “peer chaincode defineformyorg --channelID mycc --name mychan --version 1.5 --hash 1234567890abcdef --sequence 1 --policy All”   Org2 executes “peer chaincode defineformyorg --channelID mycc --name mychan --version 2.0 --hash 1234567890abcdef --sequence 1 --policy All” - should error on defineformychannel.  *Proposed Steps:* {code} Given I have a bootstrapped fabric network of type solo And I want to use the new chaincode lifecycle When an admin sets up a channel  And an admin builds a chaincode package And the organization admins install the built chaincode package on all peers Then a hash value is received on all peers When the organization admins approve the chaincode package on all peers And an admin commits the chaincode package to the channel And a user invokes on the chaincode with args  "init","a","1000","b","2000"  When a user queries on the chaincode with args  "query","a"  Then a user receives a success response of 1000  When an admin builds chaincode at path "github.com/hyperledger/fabric/examples/chaincode/go/example02/cmd" as version "2" with args  "init","a","1000","b","2000"  with name "mycc2" on all peers And the organization admins install the built chaincode package on all peers Then a hash value is received on all peers When an admin approves the upgraded to version "1.5" chaincode package on peer "peer0.org1.example.com" When an admins approve the upgraded to version "2.0" chaincode package on peer "peer0.org2.example.com" And an admin commits the chaincode package to the channel Then an admin receives an error response containing "<Error Message>" {code}  ></description> </Issue>
