<Action id="56984" issue="37649" author="denyeart" type="comment" created="2019-02-13 16:26:38.0" updateauthor="denyeart" updated="2019-02-13 16:26:38.0"> <body><! CDATA The client only submits one write-set (it chooses from one of the N peer responses), and then attaches the N endorsement signatures that it received from peers.  If any of the signatures do not match the write-set (actually the whole proposal response), you receive the error "The signature is invalid".  At validation time, the peer cannot distinguish whether the endorsing peer returned a different proposal response than the one that was ultimately submitted with the tran, or if it returned the same proposal response but somehow provided a bad signature for it.  All the validating peer knows is that the signature does not match the proposal response that was ultimately submitted.  That being said, I agree the message "The signature is invalid" could be improved to indicate that the signature does not match the proposal response, rather than being invalid for some other reason.  I was actually more confused by the message "identity 1 does not satisfy principal: the identity is a member of a different MSP (expected *************MSP, got *******MSP)".  I think both messages should be clarified with additional context.  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="56985" issue="37649" author="denyeart" type="comment" body="I&apos;ve tagged for v2.0.0 as well as v1.4.1 (assuming the cherry pick is simple, it makes sense to backport to the v1.4 LTS release)." created="2019-02-13 16:27:37.0" updateauthor="denyeart" updated="2019-02-13 16:27:37.0"/>
<Action id="56987" issue="37649" author="jlcs" type="comment" created="2019-02-13 16:34:17.0" updateauthor="jlcs" updated="2019-02-13 16:34:17.0"> <body><! CDATA Thank you for the explanation. It makes so much sense now. Indeed, the tx from the orderer only needs to include once the read/write set.  The "expected *************MSP, got *******MSP" message is altered because the MSP names relate to internal information. You could read it as "expected MSP1, got MSP2". It is expected, as during the validation the peer compares the endorsing signature MSP to the endorsing policy MSP.  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="60785" issue="37649" author="denyeart" type="comment" body=" ~angelo.decaro  Could you help to improve the message for v1.4.2?" created="2019-06-09 07:48:03.0" updateauthor="denyeart" updated="2019-06-09 07:48:03.0"/>
