<Issue id="20798" key="FAB-6144" number="6144" project="10002" reporter="rameshthoomu" assignee="rameshthoomu" creator="rameshthoomu" type="10002" summary=" CI  - fabric release process" priority="3" resolution="10002" status="6" created="2017-09-13 11:57:52.0" updated="2018-07-27 06:43:21.0" resolutiondate="2018-07-27 06:43:21.0" votes="0" watches="3" workflowId="35326"> <description><! CDATA fabric-release process:  *Current Release Process from CI:* In the current release process from CI, we follow the steps mentioned in the below document  https://github.com/hyperledger/ci-management/blob/master/docs/Release_Process.md  but CI team has to manually trigger the release (tests) job to verify the published docker images, binaries and npm modules. If the tests are failed, it's not easy to revert the release tag from all the repositories (fabric, fabric-ca, fabric-sdk-java and fabric-sdk-node). To fix these issues,  *proposing* below release process to overcome above mentioned issues..  1) Decide what release tests have to include in fabric-release job. 2) If release tests are based on fabric and fabric-ca tests, then commit merge fabric-ca release commit (don't create tag) then fabric release commit (don't create tag). Once release commits are merged, CI triggers release-tests job based on the IS_RELEASE=TRUE condition. 3) if the release tests are based on fabric-sdk-node and fabric-sdk-java, then commit fabric-sdk-node, fabric-sdk-java, fabric-ca and fabric release commits. Once the release commits are merged, trigger release job to kick off release tests which assumes and pull release commits and trigger all the release tests.  Once the release tests are successfully executed, Release Engineer has to create a release tag and which triggers release jobs to publish docker images, binaries, java jar and npm modules. Once the build artifacts are published, trigger Post QA release job which pull all released docker images, binaries, npm and java jar files and execute tests.  ></description> </Issue>
