<Action id="53189" issue="34618" author="ryanwest" type="comment" created="2018-11-08 06:30:49.0" updateauthor="ryanwest" updated="2018-11-08 06:30:49.0"> <body><! CDATA *Research report copied over from #ledger_2_0 Slack channel:*  Exonum is like Tendermint’s protocol but with a few tweaks, all written in Rust. It initially looked great, with good documentation and runs well on my computer, but I learned a few unfortunate things when looking through their chat:  I came across a comment on their chat (on Gitter, similar to Rocket.Chat) saying that a reasonable upper bound “for the number of validators would be around 8-15. 16 nodes is maximum for anchoring service”.  And also this: “We’re aiming at private networks, so more than 16 validators will not bring much benefits, but will drastically decrease network performance.” I’m under the impression that we’re hoping to have 25-30+ validator nodes, so that might be an issue. Of course, @alexander.shcherbakov pointed out to me earlier that “this is rather a question whether PBFT-like protocols (in general) are suitable for Sovrin if Sovrin wants to have 25+ Nodes.”  Another comment from their chat: “Additionally, you cannot add new validators easily hence public blockchain is nearly impossible.”  *Responses:*  alexander.shcherbakov I agree with what Sergey said below. There is no actualy limitations for the number of nodes, this is just a question of performance (throughput VS latency). Another question is whether Exonum is well-tested on 25 node pools, because our experience showed that behavior in case of 25 nodes and in case of 9 nodes is very different.   alexander.shcherbakov  Private blockchain is a goal for almost all existing frameworks (Tendermint may be the only exception), so this can also be not a real limitation. But we need to check what features a framework has to support a public one (for example, some analogue of Observer nodes out of the box). The architecture (client-to-node communication in particular) and scalability is important here. Also the question of deployment is very important.   alexander.shcherbakov So, I still think that Exonum is a good candidate and worth further researches.     ></body> </Action>
<Action id="53190" issue="34618" author="ryanwest" type="comment" created="2018-11-08 06:31:25.0" updateauthor="ryanwest" updated="2018-11-08 06:31:25.0"> <body><! CDATA *Relevant comment by Sergey Khoroshavin* - number of validator nodes - yes, documentation states that number of validators should normally be in 8-15 range (https://exonum.com/doc/advanced/network/), however it's not clear for which case this assumption is made. Exonum uses tendermint protocol under the hood, and there was a thesis from one of major tendermint contributors which included test results of as many as 64 nodes. Probably developers had some specific use case in mind with some performance requirements which prohibited use of more than 15 nodes. Sovrin most likely have very different performance requirements, so number of nodes will be different. I don't see any hard cap here. - concerning "you cannot add new validators easily" - in fact there is whole chapter in documentation on how to change pool configuration including validator set (https://exonum.com/doc/advanced/configuration-updater/), and there is corresponding source code in their repo (https://github.com/exonum/exonum/tree/master/services/configuration)  ></body> </Action>
