<Issue id="42351" key="FAB-16599" number="16599" project="10002" reporter="sykesm" assignee="jyellick" creator="sykesm" type="10001" summary="As an implementor of the external launch contract, I want to be able to provide index metadata for the ledger component to the peer" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2019-09-13 15:55:17.0" updated="2019-10-21 17:21:22.0" resolutiondate="2019-10-21 17:21:22.0" votes="0" watches="2" workflowId="55406"> <description><! CDATA The existing chaincode platforms can package, carry, and extract _metadata_ associated with a chaincode. The ledger component uses this to documents necessary to create couch DB indexes.  The {{release}} or {{build}} phase of an external builder should be responsible for providing this information to the peer by populating a directory with the metadata documents. These documents must then be saved and provided to the ledger (where appropriate).  The current proposal reads like this:  {quote} * Chaincode /bin/release (optional)  `release` is called to generate metadata necessary to control how the peer starts the application.  The executable is called with two arguments:  - the directory that was populated by `build` with the artifacts required to run the chaincode - a directory to be populated by `release` with a metadata and assets  The details have not been worked out but there are two kinds of information we're expecting:  - metadata like CouchDB indices that have been extracted from chaincode to be consumed by the peer - information about the location and assets necessary for a peer to connect to running chaincode that will not be started by the peer {quote}  In retrospect, some of that seems a bit wrong. I believe we could actually use {{build}}/{{compile}} (whatever it's called) to populate the metadata as well as the runtime assets. That would mean that {{release}} is truly optional and only necessary to provide assets necessary for the peer to connect to chaincode.  Acceptance: The build script is provided a fourth directory to (optionally) populate with metadata. Upon completion of the build process, this metadata is captured and made available to the ledger. An existing chaincode that requires a CouchDB index can be deployed and executed using the external builder.  ></description> </Issue>
