<Issue id="12907" key="FAB-605" number="605" project="10002" reporter="joshhus" assignee="nickgaski" creator="joshhus" type="10002" summary="Hyperledger Fabric v1.0 Preview doc review" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2016-10-05 13:30:11.0" updated="2018-07-20 14:10:24.0" resolutiondate="2016-10-05 14:09:30.0" votes="0" watches="2" workflowId="36389"> <description><! CDATA Edits and clarifications, which would benefit readers of the v1.0 Preview Doc.   For 1.0 Preview doc: http://hyperledger-fabric.readthedocs.io/en/latest/abstract_v1/   (Line #s are approximate)  Line 1: "They" typo (The) Hyperledger Fabric ... Line 1: It's not a "platform" right-it's agnostic to OS and HW. So "architecture", perhaps. Line 1: I like the word "robust" personally, but it can imply different/subjective things; high-performance, reliable, scalable, are possibly more descriptive/accurate. Line 2: "Byzantine" capitalized. Is it PBFT specifically, or any "byzantine fault tolerant" protocol? ... And is HL v1.0 no longer agnostic / modular wrt consensus protocol? - it's "byzantine" only now? (no PoET, PoW, PoS) ... and add "protocol" after consensus. Line 3: "throuh" typo (through) Line 3: "v0.6-preview" 2x - what does "preview" mean to a reader wrt v0.6 - from an IBM Bluemix is concerned, v0.6 is planned to be a "GA" release of HL.  Paragraph 2:  Line 1: adding "and organizations" to "businesses" might be more welcoming to gov., non-profits, etc. Line 3: "FOREX" markets is lowercase - "forex". (The web site URL advertises FOREX.com all caps for some reason.)  WHERE WE ARE: Parag. 3:  Line 1: Add (v0.6) after "current implementation" ...   WHERE WE'RE GOING: Parag. 4:  Line 1: Add (v1.0) after "new architecture" ...  Line 2: "... the peers are diverged into two distinct roles" could be read as each peer is diverged to handle both roles. Try, "Each peer is assigned one of two distinct roles - " assuming that's correct. Likewise, use "As an endorser, the peer" only if each peer performs both roles; assuming each peer only does one of the two roles, use "Endorser peers" and "Committer peers" instead, or similar. Line 5: "deterministic and stable." ("or" raises questions.) ... alternatively, if deterministic is being explained here: "deterministic (stable/reliable)." Line 6: I would delete, "without the network being made cognizant of the transaction." Specific peers are part of the network, and the network would become cognizant of it through replication of the ledger. What's meant here is all network peers aren't required to be available to participate in consensus for this transaction, I think.  Line 8: Here we go back to endorsement and "validation" rather than the new "commitment" concept. If we're getting rid of "validation" use "commitment" here. Line 9: "thrown out" is English jargon. Use international "deleted" or "discarded" or "ignored" or "omitted", whichever is most accurate. Line 10: Change "possibility" to "capability" or "potential"   parag. 5. Line 1: Start with "In Hyperledger Fabric v1.0, the consensus process ..."  Line 5: Some readers might want more explanation of this: "Now networks can grow dynamically (i.e. add endorsers and committers) without having to add corresponding consenters, ..." ... Because endorsers and committers are the consenters in 1.0, this feels like a semantic twist. What are we actually saying here about dynamic growth? PBFT will still require one less than one-third of all network nodes to agree (reach consensus) on the order of transactions. ... How many endorser adds are required per committer add, or vice versa. Line 9: this "Moreover..." comment is interesting, but could use some clarification: The "liberated" networks are still blockchain networks right, or not? Are we saying a "liberated" blockchain network can exist without any endorsers or committers. Or is the "consensus cloud" network doing the commitment part of consensus only? ...   parag. 6: Where is the "high-level overview" - did it not build?  HOW TO CONTRIBUTE: 1. Gerritt typo - Gerrit ...  2. period at end of all list items, or not. 3-5. All of these JIRA links are problematic - they take me to JIRA, which then blocks the browser Back button - so I'm stuck at JIRA and can't get back to the preview doc. So use a target=new for a a new tab for all JIRA links.  (Change the all caps headings to initial caps to match the rest of the site.)     ></description> </Issue>
