<Issue id="40818" key="INDY-2159" number="2159" project="10303" reporter="vladimirwork" assignee="vladimirwork" creator="vladimirwork" type="10002" summary="DOC: Request for release notes on Indy-node 1.9.0" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="10001" created="2019-06-27 14:39:56.0" updated="2019-07-08 08:16:04.0" resolutiondate="2019-07-08 08:15:41.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="53774"> <description><! CDATA *Version Information* indy-node 1.9.0 indy-plenum 1.9.0 sovrin 1.1.50   *Notices for Stewards* There are possible OOM issues during 3+ hours of target load or large catch-ups at 8 GB RAM nodes pool so 32 GB is recommended. Some nodes can fail to send a REJECT or REPLY to client under specific network conditions. See Known Issues for more details.  *Major Changes* - Pluggable Request Handlers have been implemented  *Detailed Changelog*  +Major Fixes+ INDY-2144 - Propagates with invalid requests can lead to node crashes INDY-2142 - There is no validation of the ISSUANCE_TYPE field for the transaction REVOC_REG_DEF INDY-2083 - Reduce CONS_PROOF timeout to speed up catchup under the load  +Changes and Additions+ INDY-2087 - As a Trustee(s), I need to have a way to set multiple AUTH_RULES by one command INDY-2127 - Make more system tests to be ready for Indy Node CD pipeline INDY-1861 - Integrate new handlers into the codebase INDY-1338 - Define Interfaces needed for View Change Service INDY-1950 - Rename TRUST_ANCHOR to ENDORSER INDY-2134 - Update PBFT view change plan of attack INDY-2131 - Apply a new Docker-in-docker approach for system tests INDY-2108 - More tests for pluggable request handlers INDY-1956 - Remove ANYONE_CAN_WRITE INDY-1290 -  Design  ViewChange protocol must be as defined in PBFT INDY-1405 - Batch containing some already executed requests should be applied correctly INDY-2097 - Update Pluggable Req Handlers INDY-2077 - As a Network Admin, I need to be able to forbid an action in AUTH_RULE, so that no changes in code are needed INDY-1860 - Create Builders for handlers  +Known Issues+ INDY-2164 - Incorrect request validation  ></description> </Issue>
