<Issue id="19850" key="IA-23" number="23" project="10602" reporter="avkrishnan" assignee="danielhardman" creator="avkrishnan" type="10001" summary="As a CLI user I should be able to send a connection request to another Identity Owner (institution or individual)" description="Given I am a CLI user, I should be able to: 1. Sent a connection request to another Identity Owner (either an individual or organization).So that I can start having Sovrin Connections.Examples: -Joe requests to have a connection with Alice-A bank requests having a connection with Alice-Susan sends a connection request to Alice.Alice just a very popular person.*POA*_Assumptions_* Sender knows receiver&apos;s endpoint (for example: If Joe want to send connection request to Alice, then Joe already knows endpoint of Alice&apos;s agent)_POA Steps_* CLI user can add endpoint, identifier and other information with name to whom it wants to send connection request. Add a command in sovrin cli. In file sovrin/cli/cli.py, add regex to interpret cli command, add it to lexers and completers. Add command action handler.* In add connection name command handler, save data in available connections variable along with endpoint data. This will be used to send invitation to connections available.* Add `send invitation to &lt;connection name&gt;` command. Add a command in sovrin cli. In file sovrin/cli/cli.py, add regex to interpret cli command, add it to lexers and completers. Add command action handler.* In `send invitation` command handler, generate a unique nonce, save this nonce so that once other cli user accepts invitation, we can match it up. Generate an invitation file on runtime and send it to endpoint provided.* Add handler in agent which listens for incoming invitations. Allow CLI to register to this event, so that agent can forward this request to CLI running and CLI can print it out, so that user can take an action." priority="3" resolution="10300" status="10001" created="2017-08-02 09:27:23.0" updated="2019-09-18 15:26:21.0" resolutiondate="2019-09-18 15:26:21.0" votes="0" watches="2" workflowId="19850"/>
