<Issue id="19505" key="FAB-5482" number="5482" project="10002" reporter="mastersingh24" creator="mastersingh24" type="10003" summary="Document the connectivity requirements for a Hyperledger Fabric network" priority="2" resolution="10001" status="6" created="2017-07-26 17:51:40.0" updated="2020-01-22 21:56:35.0" resolutiondate="2020-01-22 21:56:35.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="35264"> <description><! CDATA Here's an example of Q&A around this:  _+Question:+  I apologize in advance if this is a bit of a noob question ... but what is the typical backplane for orgs on completely separate networks/providers to be able to connect to the same Fabric network? ... are the peer nodes internet-connected? is there some sort of site-to-site VPN connectivity between the orgs? do we have any best practices/samples that show this as the current docker-compose samples are designed for running the entire network on a single host_  _+Answer:+  It's a good question although I think the answer is fairly simple if you think about it this way:_  _1) Peer nodes host and run chaincode_ _2) Client applications submit proposals to one or more peer nodes in order to obtain endorsements_ _3) Client applications package signed proposals together and submit them to ordering nodes_ _4) Peer nodes connect to ordering nodes in order to receive batches (blocks) of transactions which they then commit and validate_ _5) Peer nodes can communicate with peer nodes from other organizations via the gossip protocol_  _So in the end, that leaves you with the following:_  _1) Peer nodes must expose endpoints which are accessible from client applications (and from peers from other orgs if gossip is enabled)_ _2) Ordering nodes must expose endpoints which are accessible from client applications and peer nodes_  _Fabric supports TLS for client apps, peer nodes and ordering nodes. So it will all depend on the security requirements of the various organizations which are part of a Fabric network as to whether to connect solely using TLS over the public internet or whether they need a VPN / private network / leased line / etc_     ></description> </Issue>
