<Issue id="42748" key="FAB-16828" number="16828" project="10002" reporter="sykesm" creator="sykesm" type="10001" summary="Create configuration package of structures that represent the current contents of core.yaml" priority="3" status="10100" created="2019-10-14 18:59:46.0" updated="2019-10-24 11:34:58.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="55828"> <description><! CDATA Create a {{peerconfig}} package that holds structures that {{core.yaml}} can be decoded into. Several small structures will be required to hold the elements that are aggregated in stanzas.  The godoc for each field will become the user consumable documentation (where the field name is rewritten to the configuration key) so care should be taken to make it as clear as possible.  Each field needs yaml, default, and example tags as appropriate.   The {{yaml}} tag controls the yaml encoding and decoding process as documented by go-yaml. The {{default}} tag determines the default configuration value. When omitted, the zero value for the field is the default value for the element. The {{example}} tag determines the value to provide in the example configuration document. If the value is not specified, the default value will be used in the example document. If the example should show the field as commented, the specification can end with a {{,comment}} flag.  An example:  {code} // Peer holds the peer confguration. type Peer struct { 	// ID provides a name for this peer instance. When docker is used to build 	// and host chaincode, the ID is included as part of the name. 	ID string `yaml:"id,omitempty" example:"jdoe"`  	// NetworkID is used to enable logical seggregation of netorks. It is only used 	// when naming docker resources. 	NetworkID string `yaml:"networkId,omitempty" example:"dev"`  	// ListenAddress controls the network address (and interface) the peer 	// listens on. By default, the peer will listen on all local interfaces. 	ListenAddress string `yaml:"listenAddress,omitempty" default:":7051"`  	// ChaincodeListenAddress controls the address (and interface) the peer 	// listens on for chaincode connections. If omitted, ListenAddress is used. 	ChaincodeListenAddress string `yaml:"chaincodeListenAddress,omitempty" example:"0.0.0.0:7052,comment"` ... {code}  A {{defaultValue}} tag can be used to reference an exported var that holds the default structure by providing the name of the variable. The variable must be in the same package.  ></description> </Issue>
