<Issue id="28302" key="FAB-11237" number="11237" project="10002" reporter="jyellick" assignee="ales" creator="jyellick" type="10000" summary="Chaincode lifecycle - 2.0 improvements" priority="1" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2018-03-08 16:25:18.0" updated="2021-07-29 12:22:51.0" resolutiondate="2021-01-11 05:32:20.0" votes="4" watches="33" workflowId="43244"> <description><! CDATA The new v2.0 chaincode lifecycle introduces decentralized governance for chaincode, with a new process for installing a chaincode on your peers and starting it on a channel. The new Fabric chaincode lifecycle allows multiple organizations to come to agreement on the parameters of a chaincode, such as the chaincode endorsement policy, before it can be used to interact with the ledger.  Specifically, the new model offers several improvements over the previous lifecycle: * *Multiple organizations must agree to the parameters of a chaincode:* In the release 1.x versions of Fabric, one organization had the ability to set parameters of a chaincode (for instance the endorsement policy) for all other channel members. The new Fabric chaincode lifecycle is more flexible since it supports both centralized trust models (such as that of the previous lifecycle model) as well as decentralized models requiring a sufficient number of organizations to agree on an endorsement policy before it goes into effect. * *Safer chaincode upgrade process:* In the previous chaincode lifecycle, the upgrade transaction could be issued by a single organization, creating a risk for a channel member that had not yet installed the new chaincode. The new model allows for a chaincode to be upgraded only after a sufficient number of organizations have approved the upgrade. * *Easier endorsement policy updates:* Fabric lifecycle allows you to change an endorsement policy without having to repackage or reinstall the chaincode. Users can also take advantage of a new default policy that requires endorsement from a majority of members on the channel. This policy is updated automatically when organizations are added or removed from the channel. * *Inspectable chaincode packages:* The Fabric lifecycle packages chaincode in easily readable tar files. This makes it easier to inspect the chaincode package and coordinate installation across multiple organizations. * *Start multiple chaincodes on a channel using one package:* The previous lifecycle defined each chaincode on the channel using a name and version that was specified when the chaincode package was installed. You can now use a single chaincode package and deploy it multiple times with different names on the same or different channel.  ></description> </Issue>
