<Issue id="15115" key="FABN-130" number="130" project="10604" reporter="jjjjibm" assignee="jimthematrix" creator="jjjjibm" type="10004" summary=" node-SDK  http://&lt;ip:port&gt;/docs/gen  documented but not implemented" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2017-02-28 19:15:32.0" updated="2018-07-19 00:52:57.0" resolutiondate="2017-04-05 18:39:29.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="33861"> <environment><! CDATA fabric-sdk-node commit d3fcbe2299c840dfd7886076b009b88eb25a7dd8 fabric commit a0d032bc5c4853b43972163f502a03ee7770c1d5 fabric-ca commit c9fb04e0f795589485915883fcbca3ae2fc0aaad  Ubuntu is running on a vlaunch VM   ></environment> <description><! CDATA In my review of generated documentation I see  a couple functions which are documented, but not implemented.  Here is an example from class Chain.  updateChain()  Calls the orderer(s) to update an existing chain. This allows the addition and deletion of Peer nodes to an existing chain, as well as the update of Peer certificate information upon certificate renewals.  Returns:  Whether the chain update process was successful.  Type boolean   I was surprised to see no input parameters, so I looked at the code.  ** 	 * Calls the orderer(s) to update an existing chain. This allows the addition and 	 * deletion of Peer nodes to an existing chain, as well as the update of Peer 	 * certificate information upon certificate renewals. 	 * @returns {boolean} Whether the chain update process was successful. 	 */ 	updateChain() { 		//to do 	}  As you can see, it is not actually implemented.   Here is an example of an unimplemented function which could actually be harmful:  isReadonly() { 		return false;//to do 	}  A user might trust the result of this function call, not realizing it has not actually been implemented.    Possible solutions for 'to do' functions: - implement all 'todo' methods before code cut-off - throw new Error("this function is not fully implemented yet") until method is implemented.  -  log.error('Method x is not yet implemented');  until method is implemented     ></description> </Issue>
