<Action id="52643" issue="34887" author="harrisob@us.ibm.com" type="comment" created="2018-10-25 15:22:38.0" updateauthor="harrisob@us.ibm.com" updated="2018-10-25 15:22:53.0"> <body><! CDATA I think a "preferredOrgs" option would help, then the actual peer names would not have to be known     ></body> </Action>
<Action id="53839" issue="34887" author="harrisob@us.ibm.com" type="comment" created="2018-11-27 14:16:10.0" updateauthor="harrisob@us.ibm.com" updated="2018-11-27 14:16:10.0"> <body><! CDATA How about these options for peer selection within a group, layouts will always be chosen randomly.  The application is able to have specific peers or peers in a specified organization chosen before other peers or not be chosen at all for endorsements.  *required*: An array of strings that represent the names of peers. Peers named in this list will be the only peers to be sent a proposal request.  *preferred*: An array of strings that represent the names of peers that should be given priority by the endorsement handler if their block height is up to date ignored: An array of strings that represent the names of peers that should be ignored by the endorsement handler.  *requiredOrgs*: An array of strings that represent the MSP ids of organizations. Peers in the organizations named in this list will be the only peers to be sent a proposal request.  *preferredOrgs*: An array of strings that represent the MSP ids of organizations that should be given priority by the endorsement handler if their block height is up to date.  *ignoredOrgs*: An array of strings that represent the MSP ids of organizations that should be ignored by the endorsement handler.  *preferredHeightGap*: An integer representing the maximum difference in the block height of a preferred peer and the highest block height found in a group of peers within an endorsement plan allowed to be a priority peer. A peer will not be given priority if it's block height is less than the highest block height by an amount greater than this value. There is no default, if this value is not provided the block height of the peer will not be considered when being added to the preferred list.  *sort*: A string value that indicates how the peers within groups should be chosen. "{color:#FF0000}ledgerHeight{color}", sort the peers descending by the number of blocks on the channel ledger. "{color:#FF0000}random{color}", pull the peers randomly from the list, the preferred will be pulled first. The default is to sort by ledger height.  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="53983" issue="34887" author="harrisob@us.ibm.com" type="comment" body="https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/#/c/27795/" created="2018-11-29 03:33:36.0" updateauthor="harrisob@us.ibm.com" updated="2018-11-29 03:33:36.0"/>
<Action id="54176" issue="34887" author="denyeart" type="comment" body=" ~harrisob@us.ibm.com  Looks like this one was merged... anything remaining or can it be closed?" created="2018-12-03 06:49:57.0" updateauthor="denyeart" updated="2018-12-03 06:49:57.0"/>
