<Issue id="34217" key="INDY-1734" number="1734" project="10303" reporter="esplinr" creator="esplinr" type="10002" summary="Triage old bug reports 2" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="10001" created="2018-09-28 23:28:39.0" updated="2019-03-29 20:33:51.0" resolutiondate="2019-03-29 20:33:51.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="45543"> <description><! CDATA The Evernym Indy Node team will be closing old bug reports that are unlikely to be reproducible on the current release.  *Acceptance Criteria* Overall: * Each engineer will spend one day of the sprint in this activity. * The goal is to review at least 8 issues (less than 1 hour per issue).  For each issue: * Read the issue and the comments. * Briefly investigate the issue using the current code base (not the code base where the issue was found). * Close the issue as "Done" if: ** It appears to be something that we tested as part of our most recent release, and we didn't see the issue. ** You try to reproduce the issue, and didn't see the issue. ** A corresponding task/story exists (or created by the engineer) that addresses the same issue. Make sure that the task/story is linked to the bug. * Keep the issue open if you are able to reproduce it or suspect that it is a real issue after your brief investigation. * Include a comment documenting: ** why you closed the issue, ** or what you found during your investigation, including your current environment, symptoms observed, and steps to remediate. * Create any related tickets that your investigation shows are necessary. * If you think any of these issues should be immediately addressed, please escalate to  ~ashcherbakov  and  ~esplinr   *Notes* * Close the issue as "Done" if you are at least 80% confident that the issue does not exist in the latest code base. The goal is to separate important issues from unimportant issues, and real issues will surface again at some point in the future. * If during your investigation you see that you can fix the issue quickly (only a couple of hours), proceed to fix the issue.  ></description> </Issue>
