<Issue id="31450" key="FABC-571" number="571" project="10607" reporter="smithbk" creator="smithbk" type="10000" summary="Support identity revocation for channel and peer" priority="2" resolution="10001" status="6" created="2018-06-28 15:49:26.0" updated="2019-07-04 11:26:23.0" resolutiondate="2019-07-04 11:26:23.0" votes="0" watches="2" workflowId="34531"> <description><! CDATA CRL (Certificate Revocation List) is the X509 way of revoking credentials. CRI (Credential Revocation Info) is the idemix way of revoking credentials. We don't support CRI updates currently, and although CRL updates are supported via a channel config, we need to make it easier and more automated, and we also need to support update of CRL for local MSPs. This epic includes all of the above. The design should not only support automated CRL updates from fabric CA, but also improve the user experience of CRL updates when fabric CA is not being used.  A proposed high-level design is as follows. More detail is needed, but this is the basic thought.  For CRL updates, add support to the peer for a peerUpdateCRL API which is passed a new CRL and updates the local MSP and optionally also updates all channels of which the peer is a member. The peerUpdateCRL can only be invoked by a peer admin. The fabric-ca-server is enhanced to allow configuration of the peer endpoints. When a certificate is revoked, the revocation request supports an option (enabled by default) to call peerUpdateCRL on all of the configured peer endpoints. The option to update all channels is true only on the first peer called. (NOTE: this assumes all peers are members of the same channels. Consider how to handle when this is not the case.)  For CRI updates, similarly add support to the peer for a peerUpdateCRI API. It should operate the same as peerUpdateCRL, except of course that it updates idemix MSPs instead of x509 MSPs.  *Design Doc:* https://docs.google.com/document/d/1_pm-i6WuTMGG59UygSmL0ik1sZKpRaqmIaLmeExmjfc/edit?usp=sharing  ></description> </Issue>
