<Issue id="26110" key="FABN-881" number="881" project="10604" reporter="sarithaarun" creator="sarithaarun" type="10001" summary="Use of the node SDK integration code with Gemalto HSM on we.trade project" priority="1" resolution="10200" status="6" created="2017-12-15 19:55:54.0" updated="2018-08-19 13:02:53.0" resolutiondate="2018-08-19 13:02:53.0" votes="0" watches="4" workflowId="35470"> <description><! CDATA This issue is mainly to see how the new code that has been developed by Gemalto HSM team can be integrated into Hyperledger Fabric code base and used for we.trade project.   A bit of background on this :   The  Europe Gemalto team have demoed us some key code changes to Fabric SDK connecting to Gemalto HSM. The video of the demo is in the link below.  https://ibm.box.com/s/hqdecqu7tzvx421wtiwqha20gmkjme32   I had a call with Emmanuel Bout, Gemalto Director for Business Dev in Europe and there are some key points that he conveyed to me which I would like to share with all of you and also plan the next steps.  1) The changes made to the code as shown to us in the demo will be put into the Hyperledger Fabric opensource code, but the timeframes for this are still unknown as it depends on the release cycle. But Emmanuel mentioned that Jonathan P ( who demoed and developed the code) can make the code available to us for the we.trade project and help us integrate it. They are also happy to work with the IBM Fabric team closely in order to achieve this. The team is having a meeting with Jon's manager to understand his bandwidth and to make him available to help us. Hence the immediate step from Gemalto is to make the code available to us while trying to get it in the open source code base in parallel.     2) In the meantime, Emmanuel also highlighted that if we are keen to get that code integrated to Hyperledger Fabric opensource code base, we should push it from our end too. He suggested that I mention this specially to you *Nitin*. I am not sure what the options are for us to push the new changes into the code base at the earliest so we can then use it for we.trade project.      We have to get started with developing the code and integrating it with Fabric composer and build any additional custom code that would be needed to connect our Bank's client application to Gemalto HSM in order to initiate/sign/encrypt the transaction. The deadline for this is Jan 15th and hence worrying.   The support from the Gemalto team in helping us understand about HSM and giving us demo/answering our queries  has been much more than any help that we have received from Faleel Mohideen(who is our IBM contact on Cloud HSM).      The Fabric Client and composer teams are both waiting for this new code so they can start using it on we.trade project. Who do I need to talk to in order to make progress here. Do we continue to work directly with the local Gemalto team here in Europe and make progress or do we have someone else I should be working with ?      ></description> </Issue>
