<Issue id="12508" key="FAB-208" number="208" project="10002" reporter="jamesyu" assignee="hgabre" creator="jamesyu" type="10004" summary="Unable to do query on a deployed chaincode" priority="2" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2016-08-21 09:23:07.0" updated="2018-07-20 14:10:04.0" resolutiondate="2017-04-02 12:35:30.0" votes="0" watches="6" workflowId="36113"> <environment><! CDATA Vagrant: 1.8.5 Virtualbox: 5.0.4 Hyperleger: commit 5cb39849ec2adc35055e5233556848eb7370cc85, Date:   Tue Aug 16 14:33:26 2016 -0400  ></environment> <description><! CDATA I successfully deployed and invoked chaincode, but not query. Following is the CLI command I entered and the response I got: {color:#14892c}$ peer chaincode deploy -p github.com/hyperledger/fabric/examples/chaincode/go/chaincode_example02 -c '{"Function":"init", "Args":  "a","100", "b", "200" }'{color} a5389f7dfb9efae379900a41db1503fea2199fe400272b61ac5fe7bd0c6b97cf10ce3aa8dd00cd7626ce02f18accc7e5f2059dae6eb0786838042958352b89fb {color:#14892c}$ peer chaincode invoke -n a5389f7dfb9efae379900a41db1503fea2199fe400272b61ac5fe7bd0c6b97cf10ce3aa8dd00cd7626ce02f18accc7e5f2059dae6eb0786838042958352b89fb -c '{"Function": "invoke", "Args":  "a", "b", "10" }'{color} c6c63b02-829f-4511-ab11-b77ee3b9abf5 {color:#14892c}$ peer chaincode query -n a5389f7dfb9efae379900a41db1503fea2199fe400272b61ac5fe7bd0c6b97cf10ce3aa8dd00cd7626ce02f18accc7e5f2059dae6eb0786838042958352b89fb -c '{"Function": "query", "Args":  "b" }'{color}  Usage: peer chaincode query  flags   Flags: -x, --hex =false : If true, output the query value byte array in hexadecimal. Incompatible with --raw -r, --raw =false : If true, output the query value as raw bytes, otherwise format as a printable string   Global Flags: -a, --attributes="  ": User attributes for the chaincode in JSON format -c, --ctor="{}": Constructor message for the chaincode in JSON format -l, --lang="golang": Language the chaincode is written in --logging-level="": Default logging level and overrides, see core.yaml for full syntax -n, --name="": Name of the chaincode returned by the deploy transaction -p, --path="": Path to chaincode --test.coverprofile="coverage.cov": Done -t, --tid="": Name of a custom ID generation algorithm (hashing and decoding) e.g. sha256base64 -u, --username="": Username for chaincode operations when security is enabled -v, --version =false : Display current version of fabric peer server  {color:red}Error: Error querying chaincode: rpc error: code = 2 desc = "Error:Failed to launch chaincode spec(Could not get deployment transaction for a5389f7dfb9efae379900a41db1503fea2199fe400272b61ac5fe7bd0c6b97cf10ce3aa8dd00cd7626ce02f18accc7e5f2059dae6eb0786838042958352b89fb - LedgerError - ResourceNotFound: ledger: resource not found)"{color}    ></description> </Issue>
