<Action id="32551" issue="18526" author="fredbi" type="comment" created="2017-10-17 09:55:34.0" updateauthor="fredbi" updated="2017-10-21 16:24:22.0"> <body><! CDATA Hello. I've been playing around with first-network, customizing it and mixing it with some components from fabcar sample.     Some documentation issues I have noticed: * doc does not reflect the options available in byfn.sh (-s and -f)-- * therefore, the paragraph related to couchdb is not easy to understand and requires some code digging to figure out (1) HOW couchdb may be setup and (2) HOW generating a config with e2e template. Best to be explicit : ./byfn.sh -m up -s couchdb * best to be more explicit about exposing a couchDB backdoor port by stating this is the default configuration in this sample  "Why CouchDB" section is troubling and in my opinion, should be skipped altogether, with a link to some more advanced material on using couchdb with Fabric, unrelated with the "first-network" example. * Talks about ACL support in CouchDB raise an interesting point ** However, my instinct tells me that ACL at db user level is probably not workable when used from a chaincode, which connects with a predefined user ** Discussing / Documenting such advanced possibilities should definitely deserve a dedicated document on using Couch DB in the master doc index. In the current state, it is at best misleading. ** I believe the idea was to guide the reader to this:  https://wiki.apache.org/couchdb/HelpOnAccessControlLists#Basics  * Talks about JSON query is out of touch with the "first-network" sample: the example cc manipulates binary data which are automagically managed as attachments (which is an interesting feature in its on right) * Talks about replication / clustering in CouchDB is also interesting ** I recall some presentation when first releasing CouchDB support stating that replication MUST NOT be used (because of deferred commits/"eventual consistency") ** However, it should be possible to use couchdb sharding ** I noticed in the couchdb config file ( https://github.com/yeasy/docker-hyperledger-fabric-couchdb/blob/master/payload/local.ini)  a small note on delayed commits parameter, which hints that the peer manages consistency (and, I gather, probably recovery). Peer savepoints are in my opinion an important topic to be further detailed in docs as it indicates how far we might use couchdb ** This point again should deserve a dedicated explanation in the master doc, and is probably out of scope for our "first-network" application     ></body> </Action>
<Action id="45883" issue="18526" author="christopherferris" type="comment" body="no longer relevant" created="2018-06-13 14:41:54.0" updateauthor="christopherferris" updated="2018-06-13 14:41:54.0"/>
