<Action id="34238" issue="20916" author="ales" type="comment" created="2017-11-02 10:58:02.0" updateauthor="ales" updated="2017-11-02 10:58:02.0"> <body><! CDATA  ~jyellick  I'm almost done with this, but there's one point that requires a bit more clarity: instantiation policies. From what I understood: * instantiation policies would be artifacts of an installed chaincode, coupled with the installed cc bundle * instantiation policies would not be stored as part of the cc resource tree * instantiation policies would not be checked when the chaincode has been installed * instantiation policies would be checked by a peer upon receipt of a tx proposal, to determine whether that peer is willing to endorse that proposal ** in particular, the check would retrieve the instantiation policy from the cc bundle and verify that the config update that deployed/upgraded the chaincode contains a signature set that satisfies the instantiation policy (note that the signature set on that config update would have to satisfy two policies: the mod policy for that branch of the tree *AND* the instantiation policy); ** the check could be performed before every endorsement; alternatively, we could attach the check to - say - the Launch function that starts a chaincode  Do we have agreement on this? Can we spot any problems with this approach? Adding  ~mne   ~ellaki   ~elli-androulaki   ~angelo.decaro   ~adecaro   ~mastersingh24   ></body> </Action>
<Action id="34307" issue="20916" author="ales" type="comment" body="A WIP for review https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/#/c/15141/" created="2017-11-03 10:34:01.0" updateauthor="ales" updated="2017-11-03 10:34:01.0"/>
<Action id="34373" issue="20916" author="elli-androulaki" type="comment" created="2017-11-06 16:23:36.0" updateauthor="elli-androulaki" updated="2017-11-06 16:23:58.0"> <body><! CDATA As discussed with  ~ales , this approach would not work as cc container is per chaincode and not per channel. Variants of this approach that include a per chaincode and channel flag would also incur into more complex code written, and would tax auditability.  Regarding instantiation policies, various approaches and their advantages/shortcomings have been documented  here| https://docs.google.com/document/d/1VDQT0SXWbH4c5l-4KK1BkRslSI1WX9LP3Ahg38Tzffw/edit?usp=sharing     It would make sense to move the discussion there.     ></body> </Action>
