<Issue id="17672" key="STL-398" number="398" project="10001" reporter="tkuhrt" assignee="amolk" creator="tkuhrt" type="10002" summary="Resolve license issues uncovered by Fossology Scan" priority="2" resolution="10000" status="10001" created="2017-06-08 19:44:21.0" updated="2019-04-18 13:38:54.0" resolutiondate="2019-04-18 13:38:10.0" votes="0" watches="5" workflowId="17676"> <description><! CDATA h2. Context  Hyperledger Sawtooth source files (pulled on June 5, 2017) were scanned by The Linux Foundation utilizing Fossology to determine license for files contained in the following repositories: *  https://github.com/hyperledger/sawtooth-core.git   From the Hyperledger Charter ( https://www.hyperledger.org/about/charter ) Section 13, all files that are included in Hyperledger projects should either be licensed with the Apache License, Version 2.0 for source code or Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License for documentation. h2. Expected Behavior  All files should have license text included either directly or via a LICENSE file in the directory for files that cannot be modified to include a comment with the license text (think binary files). h2. Actual Behavior  See attached file for results. h2. Possible Fix  For files with Attribution license, ideally, we would replace those with Apache 2.0 files and dependencies; otherwise, we will need to go to the Hyperledger Governing board for exception.  For _ALL_ files that do not have a license included, the first step is to check with the contributor to ensure that the file can be released as Apache 2.0 or CC-BY-4.0. If the contributor agrees, the file should be modified to include the license. You can utilize  SPDX Identifiers|https://spdx.org/  to represent the correct license.  For those non-modifiable files, you will need to include a LICENSE file in the directory containing the license that the files are covered by. Here are a few examples of how this might be done: *  OPNFV Apex|https://github.com/opnfv/apex/blob/master/LICENSE.rst  -- this is an example of explicitly calling out Apache 2.0 for source code and CC-BY-4.0 for docs. *  containerd|https://github.com/containerd/containerd/blob/master/README.md  -- see notice at bottom. This also calls out the separate Apache / CC-BY-4.0 docs, and explicitly references the "docs" directory.  h2. Steps to Reproduce  Run code through Fossology (contact tkuhrt at linuxfoundation dot org) to have the source re-run after bug has been fixed.  ></description> </Issue>
