<Issue id="16167" key="INDY-3" number="3" project="10303" reporter="danielhardman" assignee="dfarns" creator="danielhardman" type="10002" summary="improve OSCAP template for ubuntu 16.04 nodes" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="10001" created="2017-05-02 19:12:37.0" updated="2019-03-29 20:37:00.0" resolutiondate="2019-03-29 20:37:00.0" votes="0" watches="3" workflowId="16709"> <description><! CDATA One of the efforts that Sovrin is making to enhance the security of its validator pool is to require all sysadmins to run a weekly OSCAP scan against their node, and to submit the resulting report to Sovrin's Technical Governance Board. This allows us to see whether sysadmins have appropriately locked down their firewalls, whether they've set up SSH properly, etc. This work is described in  section 7.2 of Sovrin's Provisional Trust Framework|https://docs.google.com/document/d/18V1c0rOQYxNMleuV_2z7yQny0KdBnuDkWlN8DNUrioM/edit#heading=h.wwj5wrxedflt .  Although Sovrin-specific governance is outside the scope of concerns of Indy, it would still be valuable to the Indy community to provide an OSCAP template that sysadmins could use to vet the security posture of Indy nodes they create (whether destined for Sovrin or not); hence this issue is being logged in Indy's Jira.  What we want to do is test our initial OSCAP template against various servers, to see if the template works and provides value--and then to tweak in whatever way seems prudent. I have attached the initial template (ssg*.xml).  One Sovrin community member has done an initial pass of testing. He reported the following:  It seems like the OSCAP file have tests that are not consistent as I configured for instance  {code:java} fs.protected_symlinks=1 {code} but the report still marks it as {code:java} error {code}. Another example is test  {code:java} _xccdf_org.ssgproject.content_rule_sshd_set_idle_timeout_ {code} although it is set in /etc/ssh/sshd_config to be  {code:java} ClientAliveInterval interval 600 {code} .  The tool that's easiest to use with these OSCAP scans is called SCAP-Workbench. See https://www.open-scap.org/tools/scap-workbench/.  Please download and install the workbench, download the attached policy, and scan several production ubuntu 16.04 servers to see whether the policy works correctly on them. If the policy fails in the same places that are reported above, try to modify the policy language so the bugs are resolved. If the policy language cannot be fixed, then eliminate the problematic sections of the template. Either way, upload an improvement by attaching it to this ticket when it's resolved.  ></description> </Issue>
