<Issue id="44451" key="FABC-898" number="898" project="10607" reporter="pvrbharg" creator="pvrbharg" type="10100" summary="Customer assertion - Fabric CA is not required not a blockchain network - OpenSSL will do!" priority="3" status="10100" created="2020-02-27 22:29:35.0" updated="2020-03-24 00:41:44.0" votes="0" watches="2" workflowId="58359" archived="N"> <description><! CDATA These questions are coming from a context of a current customer engagement and is related to Hyperledger Fabric CA. By extension these questions are also applicable and relevant to IBP CA.  The specific questions are:0)  Is Fabric CA server “required” or “optional” – for running a successful, thriving and well architected permissioned  blockchain network? A)  A customer or customer blockchain professional declares – “Fabric CA is not approved to operate in our enterprise and we want to implement a successful Hyperledger Fabric Permissioned Blockchain solution”           B)    Can Fabric CA server be entirely removed from a HLF blockchain network and run the network with OpenSSL/or some  other CA provisioned PKI only? Statically and out-of-band                   Stating alternatively – no active CA in the network at all – ever  hence no storage connected with Fabric CA server instance                              All activities are done by scripts and shared out-of-band                                      Network changes are zero and certificates never expire  no addition of peers or member orgs or their permissions or extended attributes or affiliations or promotions or demotions, no API wrap                                                 However network comes up on day 1 – remains same on day it gets to sunset  commissioned out Customer does not need or intend to use anything that Fabric CA offers – over and above PKI provisioning  no liveness, no active live certificate life cycle management, no enroll/register or reenroll of peer or orderer or application or client, no ABAC, no LDAP, no CID, no idmixer, no ZKP, no nothing – ZILSH  C)     What is HLF official guidance on the above?         Asking alternatively                   If a Fabric CA is not in the network and network is brought up statically PKI provisioned and bootstrapped  OpenSSL or some other CA provisioned                              What parts of capabilities work? What can they enjoy nice and free without sweat?                             What parts of capabilities do not work? What would someone miss – that they have to add to on their own or with another COTS vendor product                             What parts of capabilities do not work online/live – but can be made to work out-of-band/non-online/batch mode?                             What was tested and supported officially?                             What was not tested and not supported officially?                             What parts of capabilities are pluggable and tested with other vendor CA products? Fabric CA tested to work with OpenLDAP or MS-AD on this release, version, etc.                             What parts of capabilities are pluggable and not tested with vendor CA products? Hence not in support scope                   Would HLF recommend this or not this as recommended approach? As a recommended best practice D)     Did HLF blockchain ever use anything other than Fabric CA? For any of basic or extensible capabilities? Did they work in field? Are they supported? E) Customers are also challenging on key size options – because the documentation says that these are customizable. We have not seen any indication  of anyone using anything other than 256 size.  Is there a suggestion or indication that all the key lengths are full supported and tested/regressed?  https://hyperledger-fabric-ca.readthedocs.io/en/release-1.4/users-guide.html#fabric-ca-server   Where could we find answers to these questions in HLF documentation? V1.4.4 and v2.0.0 and vMaster? What are the implications from: Vulnerability/penetration testing point of view and also from auditing and compliance point of view?What are CSP responsibilities versus customers or service receivers? Thanks.  ></description> </Issue>
