<Action id="34647" issue="23963" author="rameshthoomu" type="comment" body="Explained how we publish tagged images to nexus repository and we have some reference jobs to do this.  ~sambhavdutt  as discussed could you please work on this." created="2017-11-15 19:30:38.0" updateauthor="rameshthoomu" updated="2017-11-15 19:30:38.0"/>
<Action id="34699" issue="23963" author="scottz" type="comment" created="2017-11-17 00:50:41.0" updateauthor="scottz" updated="2017-11-17 00:50:41.0"> <body><! CDATA I think https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/#/c/15545/ is a great start.  I do have some questions. I have some ideas, but honestly do not have all the answers, so I thought these can be discussed here for the record.  Do we have plans for the following?: 1. what README file(s) will be edited in what repositories? 2. how will we advertise/announce the enablement of this functionality to the community? 3. how will we advertise (maybe post a message in rocketchat ci channel?) whenever new DEV_STABLE images are tagged?  Also: I cannot tell; will this be done ONLY when the daily test suite passed? How long will the images be stored? Will we keep only the latest images, or shall we keep older ones around? (I am not sure if that is necessary; just asking.)     jjb/fabric/include-raw-nexus-stable-docker-push.sh :  File Comment: We have more repositories. I expected to see these also. Are we planning on adding them later? cello fabric-samples fabric-sdk-node  and fabric-sdk-java - once we finally include tests for it (and am I missing any?)  Line 13: does this include the configtxgen configtxlator cryptogen ?  It is unfortunate that we cannot push fabric-test because (even though the CI updates the submodules for all the other repositories) we would first need to create/approve/merge a gerrit PatchSet containing those commit levels for those repositories after the daily test suite passed - but I know Ramesh said LF would not allow our automation tools to do that automatically. Just wanted to mention it here, in case anyone has alternative idea.  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="35964" issue="23963" author="rameshthoomu" type="comment" body="this has been fixed.. fabric-test-daily job executes all the integration tests and publish stable and binaries to nexus repository." created="2017-12-07 02:39:33.0" updateauthor="rameshthoomu" updated="2017-12-07 02:39:33.0"/>
