<Action id="31016" issue="20107" author="ajp" type="comment" created="2017-09-19 18:03:13.0" updateauthor="ajp" updated="2017-09-19 18:03:13.0"> <body><! CDATA Three finance-sector industry samples are being researched for potential development: # Private equity (settling pink-sheet rates) # Commercial paper (peer-to-peer short term loans) # Reinsurance  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="31022" issue="20107" author="ajp" type="comment" created="2017-09-19 19:51:08.0" updateauthor="ajp" updated="2017-09-19 19:51:08.0"> <body><! CDATA *Private Equity* *  www.stockontheblock.com|http://www.stockontheblock.com/  – some sort of private equity firm that claims to run on blockchain *  https://bravenewcoin.com/news/guernsey-to-host-the-first-ever-private-equity-blockchain-deployment/  - IBM developed a private equity blockchain alongside Northern Trust on the island of Guernsey * Relation to pink sheets – pink sheets is the term used to refer to OTC (over-the-counter) stocks, meaning stocks that are not traded on a known and regulated exchange like the NYSE ** Private individuals or entities can invest in these stocks with little federal oversight or regulation ** High-risk, high-reward ** The big disadvantage is pink sheet companies do not need to file with the SEC or really abide by any of the financial reporting laws, so information about them is very hard to come by ** Blockchain could help add some transparency to the pink sheet system ** There also exists the OTCBB (over-the-counter bulletin board) which is owned by NASDAQ and lists OTC stocks (pink sheets are technically a privately held company) ** Blockchain could potentially act as a public, more transparent replacement to the pink sheet/OTCBB system ** Several technologies already exist that seek to integrate blockchain into OTC stocks: ***  https://www.coindesk.com/nasdaq-inks-blockchain-trading-deal-swiss-stock-exchange/  ***  http://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20161116005521/en/Korea-Exchange-Opens-KRX-Startup-Market-Exchange      Conclusion:  The applicability of blockchain to the private equity market is extremely broad and uncertain. It's hard to justify simply replacing existing methods of buying/selling private equity if the solution doesn't also bring an additional level of transparency or trust. That level is difficult to define and will vary depending on the type of private equity being discussed. For example, when it comes to OTC stocks, what does a blockchain bring? Companies can still choose not to share any information, or if the blockchain enforces some sort of reporting system, can choose to entirely fabricate this information. How would you correlate the value of a stock on the blockchain to a real-world value? Would we have to integrate a cryptocurrency in Fabric?  The only perceivable advantage of the blockchain would be to eliminate the middle-men (pink sheet, OTCBB) which manage the trading of OTC stocks. But then who runs the network and who owns the peers? Perhaps every company who wishes to participate would have to run a peer or in some way be part of the OTC blockchain network to be able to sell their stock, but then there would conversely have to be an extremely easy way for end-user investors to buy this stock, and this would inevitably lead to the creation of a middle-man market which continues scamming users.  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="31042" issue="20107" author="ajp" type="comment" created="2017-09-20 15:39:38.0" updateauthor="ajp" updated="2017-09-20 15:39:38.0"> <body><! CDATA *Reinsurance* * Insurance companies insuring their insurance policies with other insurance companies * Allows risk to be spread out across multiple insurance companies even if one company writes most of the policies in a geographical area ** Keeps them from going bankrupt and defaulting on their policies if a major catastrophe affects many people * Allows insurance companies to put out more policies than they actually have money for, so they can grow their business without requiring the full amount of liquidity required to pay out all policies ** For example, if an insurance company has $100 million to insure people, they can write a treaty reinsurance with one or more reinsurers where the reinsurers agree to take on 75% of the value of the insurer's policies ** So the reinsurers get 75% of the premium and 75% of the risk ** The insurance company can now put out $400 million worth of policies while only being responsible for $100 million of those $400 million * Reinsurance policies can be written between an insurer and a company that only does reinsurance, or from insurer to insurer * There are several different types of reinsurance contracts ** Facultative reinsurance is reinsurance on a specific policy, these are dealt on a case-by-case basis and require an underwriter to assess the risk and value of the policy that's being insured ** Facultative reinsurance is typically purchased by the underwriter who wrote the original policy ** Facultative reinsurance is typically taken out for unusual policies or non-standard risk ** Treaty reinsurance is when a reinsurer agrees to take-on a specific portion of a whole class of policies ** Treaty reinsurance has several sub-types, primarily proportional and non-proportional *** Proportional treaty reinsurance has the reinsurer agree to take on a percentage of every policy in the contract, i.e. reinsurer receives 50% of premium and takes on 50% of risk *** Non-proportional treaty reinsurance specifies a specific dollar amount which the reinsurer is responsible for, for a specific time period *** An insurance may accept $10 million of risk up-front and take a non-proportional treaty reinsurance contract for $10 million in excess of this *** If in the specified the company must pay out more than $10 million, the difference gets paid out by the reinsurer up to another $10 million *** Any amount in excess of the $20 million will have to be paid out by the insurer ** Treaty reinsurance is typically purchased by high-level execs of an insurance company * Blockchain reinsurance white paper:  https://www.pwc.com/gx/en/financial-services/publications/assets/blockchain-for-reinsurers.pdf      Conclusion:  The advantage of applying blockchain to reinsurance is primarily in eliminating paperwork. Currently, an extensive amount of paperwork to establish the terms and manage a reinsurance contract. All of the manual paperwork and compliance checking which currently occurs could instead happen on the blockchain. A company would have to prove compliance just one to the blockchain, paperwork could be streamlined to be entirely digital, and auditing would be much easier. The primary benefits here are eliminating repeated tasks and providing a digital through which all paperwork can be sent, received, signed, and audited.  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="31043" issue="20107" author="eacoeytaux" type="comment" created="2017-09-20 17:34:21.0" updateauthor="eacoeytaux" updated="2017-09-20 17:34:21.0"> <body><! CDATA *Commercial Papers* * Promissory notes ** States a company will pay a given amount to either a specified entity or whoever holds the promissory note ** Some promissory notes specify a date that the note cannot be redeemed before *** Often the longer the payee waits the more they will be paid ** Drafts *** Three party agreement (buyer, seller, and seller’s bank) **** Seller draws a draft with it’s bank as the payee and the seller as the payer **** Seller’s bank delivers draft to bank in buyer’s community **** Once buyer pays the bank it gets the goods it ordered *** Used when buyer cannot immediately pay seller full amount for order ** Checks *** Type of draft *** Promises money from an individual who has deposited money into a bank ** Certificates of deposit *** Proof that a depositor has deposited money into a bank with a promise of repayment with an interest rate *** Usually specify a time that the money must remain with the bank  CPs could be treated like any other asset and traded on the blockchain, with logic added to assure the requirements are met (e.g. cannot be traded in until the specified date) but most functionality that makes trading CPs easier (e.g. notifying the CP holder the date of maturity has arrived) would have to be implemented in the UI and not on the blockchain, the blockchain would only provide an irrefutable record of transaction.  If the “money” the CPs promise is also tracked on the blockchain as a separate resource then cashing in CPs could be automated on the blockchain, otherwise the settlement of CPs would have to be done off the blockchain and the participants would need to agree when a CP has been dealt with.  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="67105" issue="20107" author="sykesm" type="comment" body="Stale" created="2020-01-22 22:00:28.0" updateauthor="sykesm" updated="2020-01-22 22:00:28.0"/>
