<Issue id="30273" key="FAB-10116" number="10116" project="10002" reporter="elli-androulaki" assignee="jonathanlevi" creator="elli-androulaki" type="10101" summary="TEST PLAN: Idemix for Fabric Core" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2018-05-16 13:20:15.0" updated="2018-11-19 04:16:46.0" resolutiondate="2018-11-19 04:16:46.0" votes="0" watches="4" workflowId="43704"> <description><! CDATA Before closing this testplan task, coverage must be reviewed and approved (via upvote or comment) by the epic feature owner and the test leads identified below.  +*Location / Description of*+ docs, APIs, config vars, system configuration (fabric, SDKs, fabric-samples) :   Docs:    https://hyperledger-fabric.readthedocs.io/en/master/idemix.html   https://hyperledger-fabric.readthedocs.io/en/master/idemixgen.html   APIs:   Fabric: MSP API,   +*Unit Test (UT) leader*+:  ~mdr   Automated unit tests are merged in repo, as go tests or otherwise part of build/verify jenkins jobs. Code coverage tracked in Jenkins:  https://jenkins.hyperledger.org/view/Daily/job/fabric-unit-test-coverage-daily-master-x86_64/   The idemix package (containing the crypto functionality required) has a code coverage of 85%, the msp package (where we make the idemix functionality available as an MSP) has a code coverage of 85%. The idemixca used in idemixgen (a tool to create idemix cryptographic material) has a coverage of 86%.  Different scenarios were included in unit tests, including the following: # Using the wrong certificate keys # Setting the wrong attribute values # Corrupting the certificate by inserting random values into the serialized Identity and transaction signature # Inserting empty values  +****************++*Function Test (FVT) leader*+:  ~mdr  These are integration tests, some of which may be component mocked in order to force certain scenarios, others may be full system integration.  E2E testcases scenarios (There is a jira test-task for each of these): # Manual Test: Have an identity mixer client perform a chaincode query without gingko (---------FAB-10113---------) # Convert the above e2e test to use the ginkgo framework (FAB-10174) # E2E Test: Have an identity mixer client perform a chaincode invocation  (FAB-10117) # E2E Test: Have an identity mixer admin perform an identity mixer MSP reconfiguration (FAB-10118)  C.  Other functional testing required: N/A     +*System Verification Test (SVT) leader*+:  ~mne   Idemix is an alternative MSP in addition to the standard X509 MSP. It is used to signing by / verification of transaction creators in an anonymous/unlinkable fashion. From a system perspective, test scenarios that exercise standard MSP functionality for this purpose also apply to Idemix.  The SVT network setup that mixes standard X509 and Idemix MSPs. The standard long-running (~72h) full system integration test features 32 organizations with 2 peers each, driving regular Fabric transaction flow, including sign/verify failure cases.  Multiple multi-threaded tests should be executed that verify the ability to execute multiple Idemix-based transactions within the system. Any notable performance changes should be documented.  ></description> </Issue>
