<Issue id="34671" key="FAB-12455" number="12455" project="10002" reporter="subhramazumdar" creator="subhramazumdar" type="10001" summary="Proposing an anonymous endorsement system using linkable ring signature" priority="3" resolution="10001" status="6" created="2018-10-15 06:58:17.0" updated="2020-01-22 22:32:31.0" resolutiondate="2020-01-22 22:32:31.0" votes="0" watches="3" workflowId="46075"> <description><! CDATA To endorse a transaction, an endorser mentions its identity along with the signature so that it can be verified. However, for certain transactions, difference in opinion may exist among endorsers. Disclosure of identity of endorser may lead to conflict within the consortium. In such cases, an endorsement policy which allows an endorser to support a transaction discreetly but simultaneously takes into account the decision of the majority is preferred. As a solution, we propose an Anonymous Endorsement System which uses a threshold endorsement policy. For hiding the identity of endorsers, a new ring signature scheme, called Fabric’s Constant-Sized Linkable Ring Signature (FCsLRS) with Transaction-Oriented linkability has been proposed. The code for the algorithm proposed is written in Golang and a performance analysis has also been done.  So the following are the contributions made in this work :  1. We have proposed an Anonymous Endorsement System which implements a simple threshold endorsement policy which requires at least t out of n endorsers to approve of the transaction without explicitly mentioning their identity.  2. We have given the construction of a constant sized linkable ring signature scheme, Fabric’s Constant-Sized Linkable Ring Signature (FCsLRS), to hide the identity of an endorser.  3.A new linking criterion, called as “transaction-oriented” linkability, is used which prevents an endorser from signing same transaction more than once.  4. We have implemented this scheme in Golang and analysed its performance.  5. A detailed description of the integration of the scheme with existing framework of Hyperledger Fabric has been discussed.  This is a part of my thesis work - Link http://library.isical.ac.in:8080/jspui/bitstream/123456789/6956/1/Diss-390.pdf  Presentation : https://drive.google.com/file/d/1D9YoGXZSb0yyzt9UZVnRnWjHY_5jAYTN/view?usp=drive_open  ></description> </Issue>
