<Issue id="15075" key="FABN-253" number="253" project="10604" reporter="jjjjibm" assignee="jimthematrix" creator="jjjjibm" type="10004" summary=" node-SDK  https://github.com/hyperledger/fabric-sdk-node -- you still need the vagrant environment" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2017-02-27 19:55:42.0" updated="2018-07-19 00:53:23.0" resolutiondate="2017-03-08 05:17:58.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="33984"> <environment><! CDATA fabric-sdk-node : commit bc36ef5e6a70bf31adb852951f1b5a217f24a099 fabric commit 29d7fc035df697a68d271d628e693c556354486f fabric-ca commit c3d00c32499232c484df57b68b6f2314f784179e  Ubuntu is running on a vlaunch VM   ></environment> <description><! CDATA The readme at https://github.com/hyperledger/fabric-sdk-node  contains this sentence which is logical to those of us how have  worked on Fabric since v0.5 days:  Because v1.0 is still in active development, you *still need *the vagrant environment to build the {color:#d04437}necessary{color} Docker images {color:#d04437}needed{color} to run the network.   1) It will mystify users who are new to the project.    2) If an image is 'needed to run ...' , it's redundant to call it necessary.   Is now:  you still need the vagrant environment to build the {color:#d04437}necessary {color}Docker images needed to run the network.  Should be: you require a vagrant environment to build the  Docker images needed to run the network.  Allen and I have been happily testing without recourse to vagrant for a few months now, and this section of the readme is followed by a section on running natively without Vagrant.    Is now: Because v1.0 is still in active development, you *still need *the vagrant environment to build the necessary Docker images needed to run the network  Could be: You can use a vagrant environment to build the Docker images needed to run the network.    In the same readme, here is another reference which makes sense to old hands but not new users: start fabric-ca {color:#d04437}(new {color}membership service)  Is now:  start fabric-ca {color:#d04437}(new {color}membership service)  Should be: start fabric-ca (membership service)  Could be: start fabric-ca  (fabric-ca membership service replaces the V0.6 membership service)   ></description> </Issue>
