<Issue id="24467" key="FAB-7103" number="7103" project="10002" reporter="yandrypozo" assignee="nickgaski" creator="yandrypozo" type="10004" summary="chaincode-docker-devmode example not working" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2017-11-25 06:49:54.0" updated="2018-07-20 14:15:02.0" resolutiondate="2017-12-16 11:48:54.0" votes="0" watches="2" workflowId="40586"> <environment><! CDATA *OS*: ubuntu 16.04 LTS *docker version*: {code:java} Client: Version:      17.09.0-ce API version:  1.32 Go version:   go1.8.3 Git commit:   afdb6d4 Built:        Tue Sep 26 22:42:18 2017 OS/Arch:      linux/amd64  Server: Version:      17.09.0-ce API version:  1.32 (minimum version 1.12) Go version:   go1.8.3 Git commit:   afdb6d4 Built:        Tue Sep 26 22:40:56 2017 OS/Arch:      linux/amd64 Experimental: false {code}  ></environment> <description><! CDATA Hello there, I've done and followed every step on the  Chaincode for Developers|http://hyperledger-fabric.readthedocs.io/en/release/chaincode4ade.html  section several tries with 3 different versions: *x86_64-1.0.0* , *x86_64-1.0.2* , *x86_64-1.0.4* but each time I reach to one of the last steps "Terminal 3 - Use the chaincode" I get the same error after executing the instantiate command: {code:none} peer chaincode instantiate -n mycc -v 0 -c '{"Args": "a","10" }' -C myc {code} The error is: {code:none} Error endorsing chaincode: rpc error: code = Unknown desc = Failed to init chaincode(handler not found for chaincode mycc:0) {code} The full output of docker-compose when I execute that command is  here|https://gist.github.com/yanpozka/003704bcfd953550e554a4ceb8883add  The full output of cli container when I execute that command is  here|https://gist.github.com/yanpozka/31a488f1cf2e8ca9279d23b896b6e1ce   Also I have tried with the _basic-network_ from the same fabric-samples, but I get the same error :( ---- Because I have experience with Go I've been able to understand some debug logs and I've found the  line|https://github.com/hyperledger/fabric/blob/2cab745abf031d8ff5d3e8f4fa7a5e5af8907fad/core/chaincode/chaincode_support.go#L327  that it's showing that error, looks like the chain-code wan't installed in a right way or something like that, but the _install_ command worked well. I apologize in advance if this isn't the right place to ask for help, but I've watched most of the videos on Youtube and lot of articles on Internet and most of them always end in the official documentation, which is good. I also want to collaborate with this project, maybe with a little of guidance I can fix or learn why is this happening. Happy to help!  ></description> </Issue>
