<Action id="57354" issue="36935" author="gennadyl" type="comment" created="2019-02-20 12:52:16.0" updateauthor="gennadyl" updated="2019-02-20 12:53:21.0"> <body><! CDATA Link to  ~alacambra  work: https://bitbucket.org/alacambra/fabric-toolbox/src  We had productive discussion at 19/02/2019, between me, Albert and Matthew.   ></body> </Action>
<Action id="57416" issue="36935" author="alacambra" type="comment" created="2019-02-21 12:22:52.0" updateauthor="alacambra" updated="2019-02-21 12:22:52.0"> <body><! CDATA Indeed a nice talk :). Please, let me explain a little bit more about the project. The main objective I was following was to make a more friendly environment for developers coming from enterprise world. More specifically java EE. So I was writing some code to make the developer experience similar to a JAX-RS, CDI stack. Also I wanted in a {color:#222222}future{color} version to add several interfaces that abstract the capabilities of the stub (entityManager, eventbus, CC communicator, CCEventSourcing, ...) making the stub invisible for the user. Also some client classes would be provided in order to make an easy coupling with SmartContracts.   In the current code, it already exists a routing mechanism where you can access different SmartContracts (similar to a jax-rs resource @PATH) and a dependency-free marshaling system, that allows to serialize/deserialize any kind of object. If using json messages it also allows to inject parts of this json in a desired type. That is similar to the way it is possible to inject @ResourceParam (even not coming from URL but from payload) and MessageBodyReader/Writter + Reflexion.   This code was in pure development, not near to be finished and production ready and I have stopped it at the moment that I have seen that  ~gennadyl  was working on some similar objective.   In my opinion the fabric product has several good use cases, but it makes really difficult to get complex logic done. And if logic is too simple, it is not really useful. Good development and test tools are missing and I would like to put some personal effort into create a nice development experience :).  ></body> </Action>
