<Issue id="15325" key="FABC-282" number="282" project="10607" reporter="khutpidor" assignee="aambati" creator="khutpidor" type="10004" summary="Hyperledger Fabric “Error when deploying chaincode: Failed loading TCerts from TCA”" priority="1" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2017-03-13 09:18:30.0" updated="2018-07-18 22:04:08.0" resolutiondate="2017-05-01 14:21:41.0" votes="0" watches="3" workflowId="32462"> <description><! CDATA I have 1 membersrvc and 2 validating peers with security enable. I run 1 validating peer and membersrvc together in 1 vm (1st peer) and another 1 validating peer (2nd peer) in other vm. I successful from a network and connect the peers together. While I try to use the 2nd validating to login with user in membersrvc.yaml of 1st peer. It's fine. The status is "OK ...." After register sample chaincode (chaincode_example02) of fabric defualt v0.6, I tried to init the chaincode with the help of Postman and it load error  { "jsonrpc": "2.0", "error": { "code": -32001, "message": "Deployment failure", "data": "Error when deploying chaincode: Failed loading TCerts from TCA" }, "id": 1 }  Again, while I disable the security in core.yaml of each peer, start the peers again without membersrvc start. I tried to init the 2nd peers. I am able to make it. SO I think the problem is causing from security enable, but in my scenario to used membersrvc is needed.  I try to surf around about TCerts & TCA, but I couldn't find any clear explanation and how to did it. I found one, I follow ,but I cannot find certificate.crt, what about to overwrite CN. I think it's not work I try to follow other, it ask me to set the root certificate and it's path "tlsca.cert". I know it locate at --/var/hyperledger/production/.membersrvc, when I try to put it in membersrvc.yaml with the path and tlsca.cert ("/var/hyperledger/production/.membersrvc/tlsca.cert"), and start membersrvc, it loads, cannot file any directory or file  Any suggestions toward this problems ?  *Note I am not using vagrant or docker. I install Fabric directly to separate VM  ></description> </Issue>
