<Issue id="36183" key="FABCN-216" number="216" project="11207" reporter="aspring" creator="aspring" type="10000" summary="npm problem with v1.4.0 RC " priority="3" resolution="10201" status="6" created="2018-12-14 22:38:03.0" updated="2019-11-30 21:14:48.0" resolutiondate="2019-07-01 14:41:44.0" votes="0" watches="5" workflowId="57034"> <description><! CDATA I have a Fabric 1.1.0 running on a ubuntu 18.04 virtual machine for quite some time now.  Node.js chaincode install, instantiate, invoke and query, all the four chaincode life cycle works fine with Fabric REST API server that came with the "balance-transfer" sample app.  But started late yesterday when I attempted to install and instantiate new Node.js chaincode, installed successfully but instantiate failed.  Error message: UNKNOWN.  After some digging, I noticed a new hyperledger/fabric-tools:latest docker image was download and installed 3 days ago ( I did not download and install it ), and looking at its timing, so, it seems the Fabric v1.4.0 RC release has caused it to happen.  And since its image id does not match that of my existing hyperledger/fabric-tools:x86_64-1.1.0 I suspect it may cause problem.  To isolate the problem, I then removed this new docker image, and yet, instantiating Node.js chaincode still failed.  Based on the above new problem with instantiate, also, the creation of a docker image for a new chaincode ( previously it's created after successful instantiation ), I conclude that the new npm architecture as described below is most likely the culprit. " The existing npm packages are still available for use, while the new npm packages provide a layer of abstraction to improve developer productivity and ease of use. ",  * Additional Info  * One thing, I forgot to mention is that, I accidentally or something else accidentally shut down the Fabric REST API server, so, I restarted it and then ran the node chaincode install and instantiate process.   Around mid or late Thursday ( the 13th ) afternoon, when the Fabric REST API server was still up and running, I was able to run some other Node.js chaincode install, instantiate, invoke and query, the whole process for a new project. My bad, and I feel bad for missing this info    Looking forward to the problem resolution.  My new project is unable to move forward due to this show stopper problem.  ></description> </Issue>
