<Issue id="36539" key="FAB-13541" number="13541" project="10002" reporter="pandrejko" assignee="pandrejko" creator="pandrejko" type="10001" summary="Updates to Commercial paper tutorial" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2019-01-07 15:40:16.0" updated="2019-03-08 10:10:31.0" resolutiondate="2019-03-08 10:10:31.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="48078"> <description><! CDATA 1.Chaincode instantiate - add this may take a few minutes to complete.  2. Change This is because it additionally submits an instantiate transaction to the orderer, which will include the transaction in the next block and distribute it to all peers that have joined mychannel, enabling any peer to execute the chaincode in their own isolated chaincode container. To This is because it additionally submits an instantiate transaction to the orderer, which will include the transaction in the next block and distribute the chaincode to all peers that have joined mychannel, enabling any peer to execute the chaincode in their own isolated chaincode container.   3. Change: Note that instantiate only needs to be issued once for papercontract even though typically it is installed on many peers. To Note that instantiate only needs to be issued once for papercontract on a channel even though typically it would have already been installed on all the peers that will run it.  4. networkConnection.yaml contains a reference to Hyperledger Composer ../gateway/networkConnection.yaml # the "x-type" property with the "hlfv1" value example below is used by Hyperledger Composer to # determine the type of Fabric networks (v0.6 vs. v1.0) it needs to work with. #     5. I didn’t see any instructions on how the ../gateway/networkConnection.yaml.  As an application developer,  I would be interested to know where that comes from and if I need to provide it and how to create it.   6.Change The response needs to deserialized from a buffer into paper, a CommercialPaper object which can interpreted correctly by the application. To The response needs to be deserialized from a buffer into paper, a CommercialPaper object which can interpreted correctly by the application.  7. Should `beta` be removed from here: "dependencies": {    "fabric-network": "^1.4.0-beta",    "fabric-client": "^1.4.0-beta",    "js-yaml": "^3.12.0"  },  8. Let’s install these packages with the npm install command – this may take up to a minute to complete: I think we need to tell them that `npm install` needs to be run from the ../commercial-paper/organization/magnetocorp/application directory  ></description> </Issue>
