<Issue id="29295" key="FAB-9439" number="9439" project="10002" reporter="pandrejko" creator="pandrejko" type="10001" summary="Update DOCs readme to edit Setup Steps " priority="3" resolution="10200" status="6" created="2018-04-09 18:50:43.0" updated="2020-01-10 22:39:02.0" resolutiondate="2020-01-10 22:39:02.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="35690"> <description><! CDATA  ~rameshthoomu  Can you confirm this is correct?   https://github.com/hyperledger/fabric/tree/master/docs/README.md      1. Remove the setup steps which refer to creating our own staging repo as this is no longer recommended.     There are two possible setups you can use to do so: setting up your own staging repo and publication website, or building the docs on your machine. The following sections cover both options: h3.  |https://github.com/hyperledger/fabric/tree/master/docs#setting-up-your-own-staging-repo-and-publication-website Setting up your own staging repo and publication website  You can easily build your own staging repo following these steps: # Fork  fabric on github|https://github.com/hyperledger/fabric  # From your fork, go to {{settings}} in the upper right portion of the screen, # click {{Integration & services}}, # click {{Add service}} dropdown, # and scroll down to ReadTheDocs. # Next, go to  http://readthedocs.org|http://readthedocs.org/  and sign up for an account. One of the first prompts will offer to link to github. Elect this then, # click import a project, # navigate through the options to your fork (e.g. yourgithubid/fabric), # it will ask for a name for this project. Choose something intuitive. Your name will preface the URL and you may want to append {{-fabric}} to ensure that you can distinguish between this and other docs that you need to create for other projects. So for example: {{yourgithubid-fabric.readthedocs.io/en/latest}}  Now anytime you modify or add documentation content to your fork, this URL will automatically get updated with your changes!        2.In order to get the following command to work on our macs:  {{sudo pip install Sphinx}}  Both joe and I had to first run:  sudo pip install six --ignore-installed six sudo pip install pyparsing --ignore-installed pyparsing     Do we need to mention this in the instructions?  Do we need to mention that you might have to upgrade your version of pip for these commands to run?     ></description> </Issue>
