<Action id="20228" issue="13750" author="latitiah" type="comment" created="2016-12-29 18:26:53.0" updateauthor="latitiah" updated="2016-12-29 18:26:53.0"> <body><! CDATA In checking for possible gaps, these were the issues that were marked as done as of 12/26/2017. I figured that I'd put them here for reference, just in case it's helpful.  Keith: * FAB-1460: Add COP support for tcert generation * FAB-1147: COP certificate renewal * FAB-1144: COP LDAP integration * FAB-1132: Error messaging from COP CLI * FAB-989: Add license headers to COP files * FAB-809: JSON token authentication support for COP APIs -- REST apis?? JWT-JSON Web Token * FAB-807: Define the proto for trusted root certificates and CRL for config change * FAB-456: Enroll a peer * FAB-454: Start a COP server (CLI)  Saad: * FAB-1294: Extend CFSSL DB accessor to support adding enrollment ID to certificates table * FAB-1086: Incorporate database configuration as part of server config * FAB-983: Add certificate serial number to users table * FAB-943: Integrate tcert process to user DB # Check that the Ecert has been issued to the user having User id. # Whenever a group is created, Pre-Key has to be stored for that group. # Retrieve PreKey for user by passing user id. Here is the flow: a. pass user id to call, it passes back user object b. User object should have group assigned to it. If not make another call to DB to get user group info c. Using user group, retrieve PreKey for the group. * FAB-862: enroll user with username and password to COP server * FAB-455: user registration info must be stored in CFSSL's DB  Ashutosh: * FAB-876: Generate local tcert based on ecert used with the COP service * FAB-874: JSON processing utility: # Read JSON file from file system and coverts it to JSON string # Retrieve values from JSON file in for key in the format a.b # Create golang CertificateSpec object from Input json # Create Attribute map from Attributes that are being supplied in the Request json. * FAB-873: Crypto support for tcert generation -- https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/#/c/3281/  Pho: * FAB-836: Generate Token and verify token * FAB-449: COP initializer (CLI) * FAB-392: ACA combined with TLS -- Allen would also know about this  Elli: * FAB-635: document alternative tcert key derivation schemes that can be implemented with standard PKCS#11 calls   ></body> </Action>
<Action id="22027" issue="13750" author="christopherferris" type="comment" body=" ~latitiah   ~rennman  this hasn&apos;t been updated in a while. What is the status, please?  ~bmos299 " created="2017-04-10 12:36:16.0" updateauthor="christopherferris" updated="2017-04-10 12:36:37.0"/>
<Action id="22042" issue="13750" author="bmos299" type="comment" created="2017-04-10 14:15:18.0" updateauthor="bmos299" updated="2017-04-10 14:15:18.0"> <body><! CDATA  ~rennman  you have a lot of work in our google test doc at: https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1_IdXCuYMKkqXr3Za0pVnFP3sP1jBcNbYnTJGV-nSkxI/edit#gid=1540473089.  I think there are few items we can add to it and post to this item? What do you think?   ></body> </Action>
