<Action id="34705" issue="23995" author="andkononykhin" type="comment" body=" ~mgbailey  actually you don&apos;t need to specify python3-indy-crypto during sovrin/node/plenumr installation explicitly. If it doesn&apos;t work without that - it&apos;s a bug." created="2017-11-17 08:28:08.0" updateauthor="andkononykhin" updated="2017-11-17 08:28:08.0"/>
<Action id="34706" issue="23995" author="andkononykhin" type="comment" created="2017-11-17 08:28:13.0" updateauthor="andkononykhin" updated="2017-11-17 08:45:25.0"> <body><! CDATA Problem reason: - rc component of sovrin apt repo includes temporary artifacts (v.0.1.6-6 and v.0.1.6-7) generated by sdk team during releasing 1.0.6 version of indy-crypto. It breaks sovrin (indy-node) normal package installation  Changes: - removed v.0.1.6-6 and v.0.1.6-7 of pyhon3-indy-crypto from rc component, chekcked stable as well - no issue there. IS-360 should fix that case completely.  Committed into: - nothing  Risk factors: - Nothing is expected.  Risk: - Low  Covered with tests: - tested manually: {code:java} $ tail -n5 /etc/apt/sources.list # deb-src http://security.ubuntu.com/ubuntu xenial-security multiverse deb https://apt.dockerproject.org/repo/ ubuntu-xenial main # deb-src https://apt.dockerproject.org/repo/ ubuntu-xenial main deb http://us.archive.ubuntu.com/ubuntu xenial main universe deb https://repo.sovrin.org/deb xenial rc  $ sudo apt-get install sovrin Reading package lists... Done Building dependency tree  Reading state information... Done The following additional packages will be installed: at indy-anoncreds indy-node indy-plenum libleveldb1v5 libsnappy1v5 python3-base58 python3-dateutil python3-indy-crypto python3-intervaltree python3-ioflo python3-jsonpickle python3-lazy-object-proxy python3-leveldb python3-libnacl python3-msgpack python3-orderedset python3-portalocker python3-prompt-toolkit python3-psutil python3-pygments python3-pyzmq python3-raet python3-rlp python3-semver python3-sha3 python3-sortedcontainers python3-timeout-decorator python3-ujson python3-wcwidth Suggested packages: default-mta | mail-transport-agent python3-simplejson python3-numpy python-psutil-doc ttf-bitstream-vera The following NEW packages will be installed: at indy-anoncreds indy-node indy-plenum libleveldb1v5 libsnappy1v5 python3-base58 python3-dateutil python3-indy-crypto python3-intervaltree python3-ioflo python3-jsonpickle python3-lazy-object-proxy python3-leveldb python3-libnacl python3-msgpack python3-orderedset python3-portalocker python3-prompt-toolkit python3-psutil python3-pygments python3-pyzmq python3-raet python3-rlp python3-semver python3-sha3 python3-sortedcontainers python3-timeout-decorator python3-ujson python3-wcwidth sovrin 0 upgraded, 31 newly installed, 0 to remove and 227 not upgraded. Need to get 6 079 kB of archives. After this operation, 23,4 MB of additional disk space will be used. Do you want to continue?  Y/n   $ apt-cache show python3-indy-crypto | grep "^Version" Version: 0.1.6 Version: 0.1.5-5 Version: 0.1.4-4 Version: 0.1.4-3 Version: 0.1.4-2{code}  Recommendations for QA: do the following sequence of steps * set rc component for sovrin repo in apt sources.list * check available versions of python3-indy-crypto (apt-cache show python3-indy-crypto) * (try to) install sovrin: apt-get install sovrin     ></body> </Action>
<Action id="34710" issue="23995" author="vladimirwork" type="comment" created="2017-11-17 12:00:55.0" updateauthor="vladimirwork" updated="2017-11-17 12:00:55.0"> <body><! CDATA Build Info: indy-node 1.2.44  Steps to Validate: 1. Install 1.2.44 (rc) pool.  Actual Results: Pool is installed normally. !pool_setup.PNG|thumbnail!   ></body> </Action>
