<Action id="29964" issue="20141" author="smithbk" type="comment" body="https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/12573  FAB-5740  Disable tcert and remove from doc" created="2017-08-17 16:48:39.0" updateauthor="smithbk" updated="2017-08-17 16:48:39.0"/>
<Action id="29970" issue="20141" author="jonathanlevi" type="comment" body="We have kept procrastinating the TCerts feature... it&apos;s pretty straight-forward to add it to any of the SDKs." created="2017-08-17 19:16:25.0" updateauthor="jonathanlevi" updated="2017-08-17 19:16:25.0"/>
<Action id="30016" issue="20141" author="smithbk" type="comment" created="2017-08-19 13:20:07.0" updateauthor="smithbk" updated="2017-08-19 13:21:50.0"> <body><! CDATA Yes, I agree Jonathan that it is taking a long time.   In the interest of moving this forward, here is a suggestion.  1) There has been confusion from folks that TCerts are currently usable because of the fabric-ca documentation.  Since there is currently no way to use TCerts since the SDKs don't support it, temporarily remove references to it from the documentation ... or at least make it clear that the capability is not functional in the SDKs and so it is not yet usable.  I would push a new patch set which does NOT disable the tcert endpoint for now.  2) We need to then decide how to move forward with the implementation. There are currently two implementations of TCerts with which we could move forward: a) the x509-based version b) the idemix version - see fabric/idemix (based on zero-knowledge proofs) Which do we support going forward, or both? I think it is preferable to only support one. A couple of advantages of "b" are: - does not require going back to the fabric-ca-server to get a batch of tcerts.  They can be generated locally in the client.  I was trying to do this with "self-signed TCerts", but still had issues to work through. - allows more limited disclosure of info.  For example, if one of the attributes is a person's birthdate, we could reveal that the person is over 21 without revealing their actual birthdate.    ></body> </Action>
<Action id="30283" issue="20141" author="smithbk" type="comment" created="2017-08-28 22:56:15.0" updateauthor="smithbk" updated="2017-08-28 22:56:15.0"> <body><! CDATA Just removing tcerts from the documentation in order to avoid confusion. https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/#/c/12891/  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="30883" issue="20141" author="clayton sims" type="comment" body="CR merged so marking done" created="2017-09-14 17:53:57.0" updateauthor="clayton sims" updated="2017-09-14 17:53:57.0"/>
