<Issue id="15166" key="FABN-559" number="559" project="10604" reporter="jjjjibm" assignee="jimthematrix" creator="jjjjibm" type="10004" summary=" node-SDK  http.&lt;ip:port&gt; /docs/gen/EventHub.html" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2017-03-02 14:53:44.0" updated="2018-07-19 00:54:31.0" resolutiondate="2017-04-05 18:39:54.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="34290"> <environment><! CDATA fabric      commit 39da6d5f263913668567112399c1708e3f87efc3 fabric-ca commit c9fb04e0f795589485915883fcbca3ae2fc0aaad fabric      commit 817fa851931e2614646800bcdd6da75940f85dd8  ></environment> <description><! CDATA (0) json --> JSON  (1) from an event {color:#205081}source(peer) {color}--> from an event{color:#205081} source (peer) {color}  (2) connect() This needs to document thows  Error('Must set peer address before connecting.');   (3) registerChaincodeEvent(ccid, eventname, callback) The Type token appears twice in this table:  ccid             string            {color:#205081}string{color} chaincode id eventname string            {color:#205081}string{color} The regex string used to filter events callback 	    function        {color:#205081}Function{color} Callback function for filter matches that takes a single parameter which is a json object representation of type "message ChaincodeEvent" from lib/proto/chaincodeevent.proto   (4) registerTxEvent(txid, callback) used by the sdk ==> used by the SDK instantiate and invoke ==> Instantiate and Invoke ?  (4a) txid 	string 	string transaction id ==> txid 	string 	transaction id  (4b) (very long sentence)  Function that takes a parameter which is a json object representation of type "message Transaction" from lib/proto/fabric.proto and a parameter which is a boolean that indicates if the transaction is invalid (true=invalid) ==> Function that takes a parameter which is a JSON object representation of type "message Transaction" from lib/proto/fabric.{color:#205081}proto, and {color}a parameter which is a Boolean that indicates if the transaction is invalid (true=invalid).  or ==> Function that takes a parameter which is a JSON object, and a parameter which is a boolean. The JSON object represents type 'message transaction' from lib/proto/fabric.proto.  The boolean indicates whether the transaction is invalid (true = invalid)   (4c)  lib/proto/fabric.proto.    There's no fabric.proto in fabric-sdk-node/fabric-client/lib/protos, and there's no fabric-sdk-node/fabric-client/lib/proto.  Please correct this pathname  (but it is great that the pathname of the prototype is mentioned here!)  (5) setPeerAddr(peeraddr, opts) vs setPeerAddr(peerUrl) The generated document describes the opts parameter, but the code has no such parameter: setPeerAddr(peerUrl)  (6) txCallback(block) private internal callback for processing tx events ==> Private internal callback for processing transaction events  (6a) If this is private in the sense that we don't want nodejs clients calling it, is it wise to document its parameters? (6b) json object representing block of tx from the fabric ==> JSON object representing block of transactions from the fabric  (7) unregisterTxEvent(txid) In the Parameters table, for row txid, the Type column is empty but 'string' appears in the Description column.      ></description> </Issue>
