<Issue id="13222" key="FABN-295" number="295" project="10604" reporter="jjjjibm" assignee="cdaughtr" creator="jjjjibm" type="10004" summary=" node-SDK  headless-tests.js error: not ok 10 .end() called twice" environment="vlaunch VM running Ubuntu 14 " priority="2" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2016-10-27 19:23:41.0" updated="2018-07-19 00:53:32.0" resolutiondate="2016-11-02 14:11:18.0" votes="0" watches="2" workflowId="34026"> <description><! CDATA My kvsTest directory happened to be owned by root.  I tried running headless-tests.js as ibmadmin.   One of the tests failed like this:   not ok 9 FileKeyValueStore read and write test: Failed to set value, reason: Error: EACCES: permission denied, open '/home/ibmadmin/kvsTemp/keyValFileStoreName' --- operator: fail  which exposes this test case error:   not ok 10 .end() called twice --- operator: fail    Here is some context for you:  # Chain constructor test info:  Chain.js : Constructed Chain instance: name - testChain, securityEnabled: true, TCert download batch size: 200, network mode: true ok 5 Chain constructor test: getName successful error:  Chain.js : No key value store was found on this Chain instance: name - "testChain" ok 6 Successfully rejected a "getMember()" call on a chain without keyvalue store error:  Chain.js : No member services was found on this Chain instance: name - "testChain" ok 7 Successfully rejected a "getMember()" call on a chain without member services ok 8 FileKeyValueStore read and write test: Successfully created new directory for testValueStore not ok 9 FileKeyValueStore read and write test: Failed to set value, reason: Error: EACCES: permission denied, open '/home/ibmadmin/kvsTemp/keyValFileStoreName' --- operator: fail ... not ok 10 .end() called twice --- operator: fail ... ok 11 FileKeyValueStore error check tests: Delete store & setValue test. Failed to set value: Error: ENOENT: no such file or directory, open 'tmp/keyValStore4/keyValFileStoreName'   ></description> </Issue>
