<Issue id="38959" key="FAB-14962" number="14962" project="10002" reporter="rameshthoomu" assignee="negupta" creator="rameshthoomu" type="10004" summary="DOC: Fix minor content issues on fabric &quot;Build Your First Network&quot; Life Cycle changes" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2019-04-02 14:49:28.0" updated="2019-07-25 11:13:15.0" resolutiondate="2019-07-25 11:13:15.0" votes="0" watches="3" workflowId="51817"> <description><! CDATA Recent changes made in the below document has some minor content issues related to new life cycle changes. https://hyperledger-fabric.readthedocs.io/en/master/build_network.html  ex: ``` 1)  t is possible to discover the approval status for the chanincode definition across all organizations by issuing the following query  The command will produce as output a JSON map showing if the organizations in the channel have approved the chaincode definition provided in the queryapprovalstatus command. In this case, given that both organizations have approved, we obtain ``` *queryapprovalstatus command is not provided.*  2) The endorsement policy of mycc will be set to require endorsements from a peer in both Org1 and Org2. Therefore, we also need to install the chaincode on a {color:red}peer in Org2.{color}  *Specify the peer number. like the way it mentioned here `Issue the following command to install the package on {color:red}peer0{color} of Org1.`*  3) # this returns the {color:red}details of the packages{color} installed on your peers peer lifecycle chaincode queryinstalled.  *I think this should be "details of the chaincode package" * 4) The package ID may not be the same for all users, so you need to complete this step using the package ID returned from your console.  *Instead of saying all users, better keep something like this. Package ID gets created dynamically on the install command, so use the package ID which got returned.*  5) The approval is distributed within each organization using {color:red}gossip{color}, so the command does not need to target every peer within an organization.  *Change this to gossip protocol.*  6) Finally, the chaincode is accessible after it is installed (like peer1.org2.example.com in the above example) because it has already been {color:red}instantiated.{color}  *I think with the new life cycle changes, there is no instantiation.*  7) commands mentioned in this section needs to be modified https://hyperledger-fabric.readthedocs.io/en/master/build_network.html#how-can-i-see-the-chaincode-logs  *When I execute, I see below container name..  dev-peer0.org1.example.com-mycc_1-27ef99cb3cbd1b545063f018f3670eddc0d54f40b2660b8f853ad2854c49a0d8 *  ></description> </Issue>
