<Issue id="14836" key="FAB-2274" number="2274" project="10002" reporter="joshhus" creator="joshhus" type="10002" summary="Write channels (multichannel) topic" priority="2" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2017-02-16 19:14:40.0" updated="2018-07-20 14:11:40.0" resolutiondate="2017-02-17 15:27:46.0" votes="0" watches="2" workflowId="37469"> <description><! CDATA https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/#/c/6017/  by end of your day- if you tell me what is updated- I can try to look on plane tomorrow- provided i have access to the internet on plane. (sometimes that gets iffy depending where you are in flight)   Sharon Weed Cocco Director Development,Blockchain e-mail: weeds@us.ibm.com  -----Joshua Horton/Poughkeepsie/IBM wrote: ----- To: Sharon Weed/Raleigh/IBM@IBMUS From: Joshua Horton/Poughkeepsie/IBM Date: 02/16/2017 12:21PM Cc: Mark Parzygnat/Raleigh/IBM@IBMUS, Nicholas Gaski/Raleigh/IBM@IBMUS Subject: Re: Channels section feedback  The new channels topic, been working it last couple of days, should be in the TOC shortly.   UX is working a diagram for us to add to the channels topic, which would encompass the table below.  Thanks,  Josh    -------------------------------------------------------------------------------- Joshua H. Horton IBM Blockchain Information Development 2455 South Road Poughkeepsie, NY 12601 Email: joshh@us.ibm.com Tel: 845-433-1711  Inactive hide details for Sharon Weed---02/16/2017 11:44:49 AM---For Channels:  I am not sure pointing to the design documentatSharon Weed---02/16/2017 11:44:49 AM---For Channels:  I am not sure pointing to the design documentation is wise.  Some of these documents  From: Sharon Weed/Raleigh/IBM To: Joshua Horton/Poughkeepsie/IBM@IBMUS, Nicholas Gaski/Raleigh/IBM@IBMUS, Mark Parzygnat/Raleigh/IBM@IBMUS Date: 02/16/2017 11:44 AM Subject: Channels section feedback  --------------------------------------------------------------------------------    For Channels:  I am not sure pointing to the design documentation is wise.  Some of these documents are out of date.  Also, i think it would be helpful to have an example.  While i explained similar to you in class with customers yesterday, they struggled until I gave them an example.  I'd show them a picture (which seems to work with people).  Bank A          Bank B           Bank C channel 1           yes                 yes               no channel 2           no                  yes               yes channel 3           yes                 no                yes channel 4           yes                 yes               yes  yes means they are on cahnnel no means they are not on channel  In this example, we need to explain that Bank A and Bank B can be endorsers as well as comitters for channel 1. Bank C can not see the # of transactions... and they can't see the data on the ledger  The reason why I included channel 4 is included is some people think you can't have all participants in a channel- which you can.  Sharon Weed Cocco Director Development,Blockchain e-mail: weeds@us.ibm.com   ></description> </Issue>
