<Issue id="35944" key="FAB-13187" number="13187" project="10002" reporter="adnanchoudhury" creator="adnanchoudhury" type="10004" summary="Fabric Operational Metrics with StatsD: Fails to put the metrics in any other address than 127.0.0.1" priority="2" resolution="10201" status="6" created="2018-12-06 23:19:18.0" updated="2018-12-07 18:32:46.0" resolutiondate="2018-12-07 18:32:46.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="47450"> <description><! CDATA Setup: A docker network of 4 peers, with the `operations` section of core.yaml as follows {code:java} ############################################################################### operations: # host and port for the operations server listenAddress: 127.0.0.1:9443  # TLS configuration for the operations endpoint tls: # TLS enabled enabled: false  # path to PEM encoded server certificate for the operations server #cert: #    file: tls/server.crt  # path to PEM encoded server key for the operations server #key: #    file: tls/server.key  # require client certificate authentication to access all endpoints clientAuthRequired: false  # paths to PEM encoded ca certificates to trust for client authentication clientRootCAs: files:     metrics: # statsd, prometheus, or disabled provider: statsd  # statsd configuration statsd: # network type: tcp or udp network: udp  # statsd server address address: graphite:8125  # the interval at which locally cached counters and gauges are pushsed # to statsd; timings are pushed immediately writeInterval: 10s  # prefix is prepended to all emitted statsd merics prefix: peer  {code} In the same network, a container named graphite (containing graphite-statsd) from  https://github.com/graphite-project/docker-graphite-statsd  *Expected*: When the there are events in the network (peer join/install/instantiate/invoke/query) the metrics end up in the designated port of the designated address. *Observed*: There are no metrics in the statsd/graphite UI, and listening to the desginated address/port in the peer via netcat listen ( {code:java} nc -lu graphite -p 8125{code} ) shows no action.  *Additional* info: manual netcat messages from the peer container ( {code:java} echo -n "example:$((RANDOM % 100))|c" | nc -w 1 -u graphite 8125{code} ) successfully ends up in the graphite UI  ></description> </Issue>
