<Issue id="17183" key="FAB-4179" number="4179" project="10002" reporter="elli-androulaki" creator="elli-androulaki" type="10000" summary="Collection of bugs and other documentation topics to address for v1" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2017-05-26 16:53:58.0" updated="2021-03-15 14:04:01.0" resolutiondate="2018-07-06 12:54:38.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="38685" security="10001"> <description><! CDATA This is the collection of bugs to address for v1.     *Critical to address* (security vulnerabilities, or critical to address cause appear often):   * extend security (pre-endorsement) checks to the chaincode to chaincode case (FAB-3892)     Notes: we could get away without this given that     i. chaincode-to-chaincode is only possible if the peer has both chaincodes installed     ii. to install a chaincode to a peer the org admin needs to approve both chaincodes     iii. org admin is trusted to install chaincodes that do not compromise the security/confidentiality of any of the two chaincodes installed     We could document these, but we already have plenty of documentation chaincode developers need to keep in mind. Perhaps it is easier to just implement this part. This is especially given the fact that install permissions can be opened up later to a wider set of users that may not altogether trust each other to have their chaincodes interact.    * remove expiration checks from identity validation function inside the default MSP implementation (FAB-4138)   * fix endorsement policy language issue  (FAB-3215)   * unused vars in /msp (FAB-3708)   * bccsp panic with invalid provider name (FAB-3454) by  ~vpaprots@ca.ibm.com       *Need review:* - cryptogen intermediate CA and CRL generation enablement (FAB-3888) - ( https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/#/c/9275/ )  - OU certificates fail to match (-FAB-4003-) ( https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/#/c/9519 ) - Error handling in bccsp/signer (FAB-3540) ( https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/#/c/9279/)  - Enhance UT in core/policy (FAB-4116) ( https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/#/c/9689/ )     *Documentation*:  FAB-4135(cc-to-scc access control configuration), FAB-4137(scc ACLs), identity validity terms (FAB-3893), RSA non-support      *Enhancements that we think are necessary*:   -  e2e enhancements (FAB-3355)     *Other* (not clear answer of whether we need to address for v1):   - purge ccinfo cache (FAB-3742)   - PKCS11 DER encoding needed by CKA_EC_POINT of all vendors(FAB-4177)  ></description> </Issue>
