<Action id="29728" issue="20053" author="jimthematrix" type="comment" created="2017-08-11 15:21:08.0" updateauthor="jimthematrix" updated="2017-08-11 15:21:25.0"> <body><! CDATA from a quick chat with  ~mdr , here's my understanding of the overall flow and the impact to the SDKs:  Overall flow is actually very similar to how TCert was done before, except that the client are not issued x.509 certificates, but instead idmixer credentials. - client and server are configured to have the same CA root (same as before, although the CA root may not be represented as certificates,  ~mdr ?) - client enrolls with fabric-ca (to be enhanced to issue idmixer creds in lieu of ECerts) - with the idmixer creds, client signs transactions in a zero-knowledge proof style so as to not reveal its identity - the peer/orderer verifies the creator identity (using the same SerializedIdentity proto), and signature  Note that the peer and orderer will continue to sign with x.509 certificates. only the client's signatures are produced with idmixer.  What the SDKs need to do: - support enrollment with fabric-ca to get idmixer creds - implement MSPs for idmixer identities, so as to properly serialize identity bytes and sign - support multiple MSP IDs for the same organization. It's currently the case, at least with node.js and Java SDK, that MSP IDs are equated to organizations. Now you may have "org1MSP-x509" and "org1MSP-idmixer" both belonging to the same organization   ~troyronda   ></body> </Action>
<Action id="29735" issue="20053" author="mdr" type="comment" body="Exactly  ~jimthematrix . Regarding the CA root, it is indeed not an x509 certificate but will have a different structure. We have a proto that defines the idemix msp config that we can use for that. " created="2017-08-11 15:54:42.0" updateauthor="mdr" updated="2017-08-11 15:54:42.0"/>
<Action id="71228" issue="20053" author="lesleyannj" type="comment" body="Backlog Review - Closing due to inactivity.  Can be re-opened if work starts again." created="2021-01-12 15:25:44.0" updateauthor="lesleyannj" updated="2021-01-12 15:25:44.0"/>
