<Issue id="31009" key="FABN-232" number="232" project="10604" reporter="mariwade" creator="mariwade" type="10001" summary="The javascript SDK throws errors for get apis and objects do not exist" priority="3" resolution="10001" status="6" created="2018-06-12 16:16:16.0" updated="2019-10-29 16:35:53.0" resolutiondate="2019-10-29 16:35:53.0" votes="0" watches="2" workflowId="44853"> <description><! CDATA An Application that uses the node sdk has to use exception/error flow to check if an object exist as a result of the javascript SDK throwing errors when get apis and the objects do not exist.  The problem is that all coding is done by handling the errors, even if there is not a true error which may cause true errors not to be handled correctly.  Either the sdk needs to return a result/undefined or the sdk needs a presence api.   For example:  In the application, *client.getChannel()* will throw an error if the channel is not on the client.  The code needs to check if the channel is not already there.   The test in the application code to check for presence is: try \{ channel=client.getChannel(channelName, throwErrorIfNotFound); logger.debug(`$\{loggerHeader} found in client.`); } catch (err) \{ logger.debug(`$\{loggerHeader} not found in user client. Creating a new instance`); }   The result of this call if the channel is not on the client is an error: error:  Client.js : Channel not found for name mychannel.     Another example: *this.channel.queryTransaction(this.txId)*   let processedTransaction:any; try \{   processedTransaction=await this.channel.queryTransaction(this.txId); } catch (queryTransactionError) \{ // 2 scenarios- 1) there is an error reading the query 2) there is no processed transaction result for the TXID  logger.debug(`$\{loggerHeader} queryTransaction did not find transaction state: queryTransaction  error message: $\{queryTransactionError.message}`); }   The result throws an error:   error:  client-utils.js : sendPeersProposal - Promise is rejected: Error: 2 UNKNOWN: chaincode error (status: 500, message: Failed to get transaction with id a81da323ada56d1718f2aef4722a2a328059f85936e239bd15f944bccdc3d196, error Entry not found in index)      at new createStatusError (/Users/mariwade/Developer/PBSA/sds-cc-client/node_modules/grpc/src/client.js:64:15)      at /Users/mariwade/Developer/PBSA/sds-cc-client/node_modules/grpc/src/client.js:583:15  error:  Channel.js : Failed Transaction Query. Error: Error: 2 UNKNOWN: chaincode error (status: 500, message: Failed to get transaction with id a81da323ada56d1718f2aef4722a2a328059f85936e239bd15f944bccdc3d196, error Entry not found in index)      at new createStatusError (/Users/mariwade/Developer/PBSA/sds-cc-client/node_modules/grpc/src/client.js:64:15)      at /Users/mariwade/Developer/PBSA/sds-cc-client/node_modules/grpc/src/client.js:583:15  debug: TransactionState queryTransactionState correlationId:1111 - queryTransaction did not find transaction state: queryTransaction error message: 2 UNKNOWN: chaincode error (status: 500, message: Failed to get transaction with id a81da323ada56d1718f2aef4722a2a328059f85936e239bd15f944bccdc3d196, error Entry not found in index)    ></description> </Issue>
