<Action id="45352" issue="30775" author="odowdaibm" type="comment" body="Working place for  ~SjirNijssen   Letting  ~cmgabriel  know too!" created="2018-05-31 14:39:37.0" updateauthor="odowdaibm" updated="2018-05-31 14:39:37.0"/>
<Action id="46693" issue="30775" author="isaacwch" type="comment" created="2018-06-28 17:08:34.0" updateauthor="isaacwch" updated="2018-06-28 17:08:34.0"> <body><! CDATA After reading this document, I would probably think of how to implement this network technically and will compare this docs with the "BYFN" document immediately.   A few points and comparisons come to my mind now : # Crypto-config.yaml in BYFN serves the purpose of several CAs. In reality, it is the responsibility of the CA in each organization to generate the X.509 certificates to its members. And in the network docs, the term "network administrator" is mentioned quite a lot, does it mean the one holding the configtx.yaml and a valid X.509 certificate identifying himself would be considered as the network admin?  # How can we add a new network administrator just like adding R1 to have equal administrative right as R4.  # Ordering service is the initial administrative point of the network. That's why we need to start the docker containers to ensure the orderer is there before submitting the channel transaction request. # Defining anchor peers is not a must and we can therefore optionally run the "update anchor peer" commands.  # Even we run the install and instantiate command on one of the four peers, all the four peers can interact with the ledger using commands (even though the actual code execution will be on one peer).  So I think this network docs not only does a great job in explaining the functionality of each of the network components , but also makes some of the ideas in "BYFN" doc easier to understand. But I am just thinking it may be even better if we can have a small section at the end of the network docs or elsewhere to link the concepts in both docs together so that developer/ architects would have a better understanding on how to implement this technically. For example, addressing point 1 and 2 or possibly others as well.   ></body> </Action>
