<Issue id="41915" key="FABN-1353" number="1353" project="10604" reporter="bestbeforetoday" assignee="bestbeforetoday" creator="bestbeforetoday" type="10001" summary="Simplified wallet structure" priority="2" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2019-08-20 13:04:58.0" updated="2019-12-19 11:58:56.0" resolutiondate="2019-09-27 17:03:41.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="54956"> <description><! CDATA *As a* client application developer *I want* a simple structure for both the wallet code and persistent data *So that* I can easily develop new wallet implementations that are compatible across SDKs  The wallet persistent data structure is tied very closely to internal implementation details of the Node SDK and not any other language SDKs. Much of this data structure is not relevant to the persisted identity and credentials. Additionally, these internal implementation details are being removed for the 2.0 release of the Node SDK. The persistent data needs to include only: * Member Services Provider ID. * Credentials of varying types, e.g. X.509 certificate and associated private key, X.509 certificate only for HSM, etc. * Some version information to allow compatibility with and migration to any future persistent format.     The wallet implementation consists of several tightly coupled concerns: * De/Serialization. * Persistence. * Configuration of the SDK using credentials.     Users attempting to create new wallet implementation need to understand and implement all of these concerns to be successful, and we provide no assistance in doing this. Typically when a new wallet implementation is created, what they want to provide is just a different persistence layer and not worry about any of the other concerns that have been coupled with the wallet implementation. A new structure should separate the persistence layer from other concerns, making the persistence layer easily pluggable while maintaining control of elements that we need to keep consistent across wallet implementations, such as persistent data format.  ></description> </Issue>
