<Issue id="37774" key="INDY-1999" number="1999" project="10303" reporter="esplinr" assignee="ashcherbakov" creator="esplinr" type="10001" summary="POA: Transaction authors don&apos;t need to be endorsers" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="10001" created="2019-02-18 14:49:28.0" updated="2019-08-28 09:14:35.0" resolutiondate="2019-07-25 15:36:54.0" votes="0" watches="2" workflowId="49390"> <description><! CDATA *Story* As a transaction author, I need my transactions to be written to the ledger preserving me as the author without my needing to accept the responsibilities of an endorser so that I can focus on my business. Instead, I will have a business relationship with an endorser who will endorse my transactions.  *Goals* * It is easy to tell from the ledger who is the endorser and who is the transaction author for each transaction. * A transaction author can use a different transaction endorser for future transactions, including updates to attribs and key rotations. * The transaction must use the author key to sign the transaction author agreement regardless of whether an endorser signature is also needed. * If the endorser field is included in a transaction, then the ledger will reject the transaction if it is not signed by the endorser.  *Acceptance Criteria* * Analyze the work required. * Raise issues for completing the work.  *Notes* * The transaction author field is intended to be used for all future permissions. * The endorser field only needs to be recorded in order to: ** Allow auditability, that the transaction was written with correct permissions ** Allow the network administrator to bill the endorser for the write * Sub-endorsers or chains of endorsers would be desirable for a global network, but are not required at this time. We recognize that in the future adding multiple levels of endorsers or delegated endorsers could be a breaking change. ** Endorsers could be a list, but it would still require the transaction author to know all endorsers at the time the transaction is created. That list could be built off-ledger by sharing a draft transaction. * Suggested user flow: ** Transaction author identifies the need for creating a transaction ** Transaction author identifies which endorser they want to use ** Transaction author includes the DID of the endorser in the transaction, and signs the transaction. ** Transaction author passes the signed transaction to the endorser ** Endorser adds their signature ** Endorser submits the multi-signed transaction to the ledger ** If the endorser will not accept the transaction, and the transaction author wants to try a different endorser, the transaction author must recreate the transaction in order to include the new endorser DID. * This process is separate from a potential process by which payment could be attached to a third party transaction so as to allow it to be written to the ledger. That potential feature of the Sovrin Network is being tracked in  ST-608|https://sovrin.atlassian.net/browse/ST-608 . In other words, transaction endorsers and authors don't need to be tracked separately for Sovrin XFER transactions.  ></description> </Issue>
