<Issue id="30550" key="FAB-10332" number="10332" project="10002" reporter="karthik37" assignee="mastersingh24" creator="karthik37" type="10001" summary="Chaincode data visibility in ledger." priority="4" resolution="10001" status="6" created="2018-05-23 17:28:29.0" updated="2020-01-22 22:32:35.0" resolutiondate="2020-01-22 22:32:35.0" votes="0" watches="2" workflowId="35810"> <description><! CDATA I have seen in FAQ that we can set chaincode input/output visiblity. h2. Security & Access Control  *Data Privacy and Access Control*: # How do I ensure data privacy?  A. There are various aspects to data privacy. First, you can segregate your network into channels, where each channel represents a subset of participants that are authorized to see the data for the chaincodes that are deployed to that channel. {color:#8eb021}Second, within a channel you can restrict the input data to chaincode to the set of endorsers only, by using visibility settings. The visibility setting will determine whether input and output chaincode data is included in the submitted transaction, versus just output data.{color} Third, you can hash or encrypt the data before calling chaincode. If you hash the data then you will need to provide a means to share the source data. If you encrypt the data then you will need to provide a means to share the decryption keys. Fourth, you can restrict data access to certain roles in your organization, by building access control into the chaincode logic. Fifth, ledger data at rest can be encrypted via file system encryption on the peer, and data in-transit is encrypted via TLS.     Is there any documentation or sample code for chaincode visibility?.     I have set up fabric network which has two organizations(2 peers in each organization). These two organizations can access/view the ledger data.Then i have added third organization with two peers to the {color:#8eb021}same channel{color}. I do not want this(Org3) organization to see the data shared by org1 and org2. Is encryption the only way to restrict?. How does visibility work in chaincode?. Is this feature still in development?.  ></description> </Issue>
