<Issue id="27956" key="INDY-1189" number="1189" project="10303" reporter="benjsmi" creator="benjsmi" type="10001" summary="New Node Catchup for Long Ledgers" priority="3" status="10200" created="2018-02-23 16:22:54.0" updated="2019-10-09 09:36:11.0" votes="0" watches="4" workflowId="27958"> <description><! CDATA The documentation for Indy, in particular for running a Sovrin Steward Node, says: {noformat} High availability in Sovrin is achieved via the consensus algorithm; hot-swapped machines in a cluster configuration may actually make the network less reliable{noformat} This makes sense intuitively to any students of distributed ledger technologies (DLTs) in that when a new node joins the network, it will ask its neighbors for the consensus-verified copy of the ledger such that it is now "caught up" with the events so it can validate the next transaction (otherwise it doesn't have the relevant hashes, etc, to do the crypto work required).  In the Bitcoin DLT for example,  we can see that the size of the blockchain/ledger is ever increasing|https://blockchain.info/charts/blocks-size .  Indeed, there are concerns about this unbounded growth  on reddit|https://www.reddit.com/r/Bitcoin/comments/1fgj4n/the_blockchains_neverending_increase_in_size/  and users  have started to complain|https://bitcoin.stackexchange.com/questions/8923/where-do-i-find-the-actual-blockchain-size  about the size that the chain takes up on their systems.  I've heard various solutions proposed for other DLTs such as only requiring a node to verify the past X transactions to be considered "caught up" vs. the whole history of the chain as one potential solution. What is Indy/Plenum's approach to this problem?   In particular, I've linked  issue 1182 because in debugging this issue, we've discovered that the read_ledger script distributed with Indy makes a copy of the entire tree that contains the chain, reads from the copy, and then deletes the copy.  This could get to be a very expensive approach/implementation for larger Indy ledgers.  ></description> </Issue>
