<Issue id="40819" key="INDY-2160" number="2160" project="10303" reporter="andkononykhin" creator="andkononykhin" type="10004" summary="Intermittent failure during indy-node debian installation" priority="3" status="10200" created="2019-06-27 14:55:12.0" updated="2019-06-27 14:55:12.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="53775"> <description><! CDATA Sometimes indy-node installation using apt tool failed because of the strange error related to one of the dependencies: {code:java} Setting up python3-pygments (2.2.0) ... Fatal Python error: Py_Initialize: Unable to get the locale encoding Traceback (most recent call last): File "/usr/lib/python3.5/encodings/__init__.py", line 32, in <module> ImportError: cannot import name 'aliases' Aborted (core dumped) dpkg: error processing package python3-pygments (--configure): subprocess installed post-installation script returned error exit status 134 Setting up python3-six (1.11.0) ... Setting up python3-wcwidth (0.1.6+dfsg1-1) ... dpkg: dependency problems prevent configuration of python3-prompt-toolkit: python3-prompt-toolkit depends on python3-pygments; however: Package python3-pygments is not configured yet.  dpkg: error processing package python3-prompt-toolkit (--configure): dependency problems - leaving unconfigured  ...  dpkg: dependency problems prevent configuration of indy-plenum: indy-plenum depends on python3-prompt-toolkit (= 0.57-1); however: Package python3-prompt-toolkit is not configured yet. indy-plenum depends on python3-pygments (= 2.2.0); however: Package python3-pygments is not configured yet.  dpkg: error processing package indy-plenum (--configure): dependency problems - leaving unconfigured Setting up python3-timeout-decorator (0.4.0) ... Setting up python3-distro (1.3.0) ... dpkg: dependency problems prevent configuration of indy-node: indy-node depends on indy-plenum (= 1.9.0~dev827); however: Package indy-plenum is not configured yet.  dpkg: error processing package indy-node (--configure): dependency problems - leaving unconfigured Processing triggers for libc-bin (2.23-0ubuntu10) ... Processing triggers for systemd (229-4ubuntu21.2) ... Errors were encountered while processing: python3-pygments python3-prompt-toolkit indy-plenum indy-node{code} Possibly it might be related to in-docker installation.  Example (in scope of system-testing):  https://build.sovrin.org/blue/organizations/jenkins/indy-node%2Findy-node-cd/detail/master/1010/pipeline   ></description> </Issue>
