<Issue id="37433" key="STL-1483" number="1483" project="10001" reporter="danintel" assignee="ryanbeck" creator="danintel" type="10004" summary="Installing sawtooth nightly (1.2) results in unmet dependencies error" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="10001" created="2019-02-04 23:36:00.0" updated="2019-05-20 20:17:45.0" resolutiondate="2019-05-20 20:17:45.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="49038"> <description><! CDATA Following these directions with Sawtooth nightly (1.2): https://sawtooth.hyperledger.org/docs/core/nightly/master/app_developers_guide/ubuntu.html results in an error:  {{$ sudo pkg install sawtooth  sudo  password for dano: sudo apt install sawtooth Reading package lists... Done Building dependency tree Reading state information... Done Some packages could not be installed. This may mean that you have requested an impossible situation or if you are using the unstable distribution that some required packages have not yet been created or been moved out of Incoming. The following information may help to resolve the situation:  The following packages have unmet dependencies: sawtooth : Depends: python3-sawtooth-poet-cli but it is not installable Depends: python3-sawtooth-poet-common but it is not installable Depends: python3-sawtooth-poet-core but it is not installable Depends: python3-sawtooth-poet-families but it is not installable Depends: python3-sawtooth-poet-simulator but it is not installable E: Unable to correct problems, you have held broken packages. monroe ~ $ uname -a Linux monroe 4.15.0-45-generic #48-Ubuntu SMP Tue Jan 29 16:28:13 UTC 2019 x86_64 x86_64 x86_64 GNU/Linux monroe ~ $ lsb_release -a No LSB modules are available. Distributor ID: Ubuntu Description:    Ubuntu 18.04.1 LTS Release:        18.04 Codename:       bionic}}  The problem is basically PoET packages are listed as dependencies, but do not exist (yet) for Sawtooth 1.2 nightly.  *Workaround #1* You can also install Sawtooth with Docker. See: https://sawtooth.hyperledger.org/docs/core/releases/latest/app_developers_guide/docker.html  *Workaround #2* If you wish to install the nightly development packages on Ubuntu 18.04 LTS (Bionic), then, for now, specify the individual packages you wish to install instead of parent package ``sawtooth``.  For example, ``sudo apt-get install python3-sawtooth-cli python3-sawtooth-integration python3-sawtooth-rest-api python3-sawtooth-sdk python3-sawtooth-settings python3-sawtooth-signing python3-sawtooth-validator sawtooth-devmode-engine-rust``  Filing this JIRA issue was recommended during a review of Sawtooth FAQ additions: >  vaporos 4 hours ago  Member >  This should also be tied to some bug, otherwise we won't know when to remove the >  workaround from the FAQ.   ></description> </Issue>
