<Issue id="22949" key="INDY-938" number="938" project="10303" reporter="tkuhrt" creator="tkuhrt" type="10004" summary="Resolve licensing issues discovered by Fossology scan" priority="3" status="10405" created="2017-10-30 19:31:28.0" updated="2019-10-09 09:16:55.0" votes="0" watches="4" workflowId="22950"> <description><! CDATA Hyperledger Indy source from October 12, 2017 was scanned using Fossology to determine license for files contained in the following repositories *  https://github.com/hyperledger/indy-plenum.git   *  https://github.com/hyperledger/indy-node.git   *  https://github.com/hyperledger/indy-sdk.git   *  https://github.com/hyperledger/indy-anoncreds.git   *  https://github.com/hyperledger/indy-crypto.git   From the Hyperledger Charter ( https://www.hyperledger.org/about/charter)  Section 13, all files that are included in Hyperledger projects should either be licensed with the Apache License, Version 2.0 for source code or Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License for documentation.  There are a few files in the Indy source base that do not meet these requirements.  See the attached file for results.   The files listed under Attribution and No License Found need to be resolved. For the Attribution tab, these files should be replaced with code meeting the Apache 2.0 license.  For the files listed as No License Found, we should first check with the original contributors to make sure that they can contain an Apache 2.0 license (for source code) or a Creative Commons with Attribution 4.0 license (for documentation). Once this has been verified, the editable files must be annotated with the correct license text and/or the SPDX short identifiers (see   https://spdx.org/sites/cpstandard/files/pages/files/using_spdx_license_list_short_identifiers.pdf ). For binary files, a license.txt file should be included in the directory calling out the file types and the associated license.  In addition, there are 5 files that say "MIT/Apache-2.0" as the license. It would be great if we can get confirmation from the contributor that this is a dual-license choice (e.g. we can choose one OR the other), and not a requirement that both licenses be followed.  Any files that are not covered by Apache 2.0 or CC by 4.0 that need to remain with the project will need to go through an exception process with the governing board.  ></description> </Issue>
