<Issue id="29677" key="INDY-1295" number="1295" project="10303" reporter="dsurnin" creator="dsurnin" type="10004" summary="Reboot machine running Node leads to issues with consensus " priority="3" resolution="10001" status="10001" created="2018-04-25 14:14:21.0" updated="2019-10-23 14:41:36.0" resolutiondate="2019-10-23 14:41:36.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="29683"> <description><! CDATA This issue is create to split different problems from  INDY-1256|https://jira.hyperledger.org/browse/INDY-1256    ~ozheregelya  Environment: indy-node 1.3.364 (master) AWS QALive pool (20 nodes) with 260,490 txns in ledger.  Steps to Reproduce: 1. Make sure that all nodes are in consensus and that all nodes have the same primary. 2. Reboot instance with primary node (Node10).  Actual Results: ViewChange was not happened on one node (Node15). For the rest nodes primary was changed (to Node11). Pool is still in consensus.  After restart of problematic node (Node15) primary on this node was changed (to Node11), problematic node successfully completed catch-up and continued to work properly.  Logs: https://drive.google.com/file/d/1CBZYr2pMs1dapRqVbKSvn9RgVIb5quas/view?usp=sharing Journalctl: https://drive.google.com/file/d/1_Nd4Exqe2Bhh1_OHh0l5c0y56obsGZMb/view?usp=sharing  Additional Information: Similar case was tried by NIkita Zhigunenko and Vladimir Shishkin on another pools with stable version. ViewChange was successfully completed on all of the nodes in case of simple reboot.   ~zhigunenko.dsr  Environment: indy-node 1.3.364 (master) AWS QALive pool (20 nodes)  Steps to Reproduce: 1. Make sure that all nodes are in consensus and that all nodes have the same primary. 2. execute on primary node (Node11) this "execute sudo apt-get update && sudo apt-get upgrade && sudo reboot" Actual results: Ex-primary node cannot catch up new txns. Rest of nodes are consider ex-primary as unreachable Expected results: Ex-primary successfully catch up and write new txns.  Logs: https://drive.google.com/open?id=1YxjUlWcSxpXylq1Mu09dIY9kcyqJ5WV3 Thu Apr 12 07:31:20 2018 - approximate reboot time    ></description> </Issue>
