<Issue id="18144" key="FABJ-221" number="221" project="10605" reporter="rhegde" assignee="rickr" creator="rhegde" type="10004" summary="Orderer rejects broadcast mesasge sent by HFC (fabric-sdk-java) " priority="3" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2017-06-16 13:51:20.0" updated="2018-07-19 00:20:47.0" resolutiondate="2017-06-29 23:53:49.0" votes="0" watches="4" workflowId="33659" security="10001"> <description><! CDATA  ~jyellick    Environment  Our setup contains organization been part of public and a private channel. This organization's client has its own CA and has enrolment performed successfully.  The same crypto is used by the client now to perform transaction on public and private channel.  Transaction is successfully updated on the Public Channel however on Private channel the transaction is rejected.  Orderer logs message  {quote}2017-06-15 00:09:47.735 UTC  orderer/common/broadcast  Handle -> WARN 45c2 Rejecting broadcast message because of filter error: Rejected by rule: *sigfilter.sigFilter {quote}  HFC (fabric-sdk-java) {quote}OrdererClient - resp status value: 400, resp: BAD_REQUEST{quote}   This was discussed in detail by sharing failure-success logs seen on the orderer, configtx.yaml and channel configuration block of public and private channel. Can you use this material available  ~jyellick  for analysis which i cannot upload here.  This is the analysis reported so far on RC by  ~jyellick    {quote} The CA cert for the org is the same in both channels 2. The signing cert used for both transactions is the same 3. The signature is not validating on the private channel, but does on the public one  So, at this point, it seems to me like this is likely an SDK problem. If I had access to the transaction bytes which were submitted on each channel, I could verify (3) manually, but I'm guessing we need to drag  ~rickr  into this.  The certificate sent to the orderer is correct, it is the signature that seems incorrect    {quote}  Observation 1. This setup was working fine on Fabric Alpha Images (19th May Build) however and has started failing on Fabric Beta v1.0.0. 2. We can run Peer CLI end-2-end with our chaincode without any issues.         ></description> </Issue>
