<Issue id="18728" key="FABJ-275" number="275" project="10605" reporter="scottz" creator="scottz" type="10001" summary="provide failure reason when fail to create channel" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2017-06-27 18:40:35.0" updated="2018-07-20 19:17:38.0" resolutiondate="2017-08-23 12:40:10.0" votes="0" watches="2" workflowId="33713" security="10001"> <description><! CDATA As described in FAB-4924 , when using java sdk to run End2endIT, and while attempting to create a channel, the user receives a "BAD_REQUEST" status response which is printed. _In that particular test failure scenario, the tester rebooted the application without restarting the network - so the request was not malformed, but rather simply a request that could not be satisfied because the same exact channel was already created previously._ The error message would be much more helpful if it would print a detail response text string in addition to the status response value. This text could differentiate between various reasons for failure/rejection of the request to create a channel.  This request is to enhance the error message. In addition to the current error message         'StatusValue 400. Status BAD_REQUEST'  the orderer should provide more information, and the end result should be to provide the user with a more helpful message containing a reason for failure, such as         'cannot create; channel <channel-name> already exists'   Designers can confirm if we need to change the fabric as well as the fabric-sdk-java (and other sdk APIs as well), but it seems that when printing the status ( 'StatusValue 400. Status BAD_REQUEST'), the java sdk should also print some additional response text (which could be provided by the orderer).  Once the interface is enhanced to do so, it could be leveraged to provide more specific reasons for failure of this command - and other admin commands as well - for all SDKs and CLI. This would greatly reduce the number of questions arriving in rocket.chat or to the level 2 SRE team.  ></description> </Issue>
