<Issue id="25200" key="FAB-7420" number="7420" project="10002" reporter="alexanderlhicks" creator="alexanderlhicks" type="10004" summary="Orderer &quot;Error reading from stream&quot; after beginning batch timer" environment="Ubuntu 16.04 AWS virtual machines." priority="3" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2017-12-11 18:50:53.0" updated="2018-07-20 14:15:14.0" resolutiondate="2018-01-24 16:00:51.0" votes="0" watches="4" workflowId="40772"> <description><! CDATA I'm trying to set up a network of four organisations, each with one peer (set as admin), and an orderer with kafka ordering service along with a client, which makes 7 VMs.  Setting up the cryptographic material, starting every channel (two of them), joining them with the appropriate peers and installing/instantiating chaincode happens with no trouble.  When trying to invoke chaincode, the chaincode can be successfully invoked (status:200) however the results do not seem to be recorded on the ledger. When running chaincode which returns the value for a/multiple key(s), the resulting payload is simply null. This seems to be due to a fault in the ordering service: I get keeping the error message "Error reading from stream: rpc error: code = Canceled desc = context canceled".  Here are logs for the orderer and endorsing peers of the transaction (which returns status:200) * Orderer:  https://gist.github.com/alexanderlhicks/91f32fb5ed2b6d5d232dcdad0572ffee  * Peer1 (initiating transaction):  https://gist.github.com/alexanderlhicks/a2c7a37d3e692336dbc9a8a9f7fd66ba  * Peer2 (has the chaincode installed):  https://gist.github.com/alexanderlhicks/75c76b11a26963d7a6962f51295ea816  * Peer3 (on channel but does not have that chaincode installed):  https://gist.github.com/alexanderlhicks/951757e880d8c2f658d2d188e25b9274   What could be causing the "Error reading from stream" message which seems to be the only error happening? I'm tried playing around with peer and orderer configurations but to no avail. Searching for this error also returns issues in channel creation, or joining channels, which I assume has gone fine since I can invoke chaincode on the channels with my peers.  This is the first time I create an issue on JIRA so let me know if you would like more information. I am using the latest images (1.0.5) which I updated to a few days ago, the same error happened with 1.0.4.     ></description> </Issue>
