<Issue id="32652" key="FAB-11509" number="11509" project="10002" reporter="aspring" creator="aspring" type="10004" summary="Unable to join fabric network" priority="3" resolution="10001" status="6" created="2018-08-07 21:49:07.0" updated="2018-08-14 15:00:04.0" resolutiondate="2018-08-14 15:00:04.0" votes="0" watches="2" workflowId="43878"> <description><! CDATA Hi,  I have two Ubuntu VM instances running.  Say, one is named UbuntuVM1 and the other UbuntuVM2.   The basic-network sample runs fine for each of them independently.  CA service running, Orderer service running, peer0.org1.example.com running and couchDB for state management running as well for UbuntuVM1.  Same is true for UbuntuVM2 (replace peer0 with peer everything else stays put).  In addition, UbuntuVM1 also created a channel named "mychannel".  Fyi, this is Fabric 1.1.  However, here we're talking a blockchain network, even just for testing.   Thus, it makes sense to make peer1 to join the "mychannel".   Hence, I edited the start.sh script under "basic-network" directory of the "fabric-sample" to the following:  docker exec -e "CORE_PEER_LOCALMSPID=Org1MSP" -e "CORE_PEER_MSPCONFIGPATH=/etc/hyperledger/msp/users/Admin@org1.example.com/msp" peer1.org1.example.com peer channel join -b mychannel.block  Well, it resulted in error.  err msg:  "Error response from daemon: Container 60a10fa37d2ef33fc23d60dbedee7e4a6a66e0a13acc44552e0650f9f268f95f is not running"  It seems that the peer1 was looking for peer0 on the same vm instance, that is, my UbuntuVM2 instead of my UbuntuVM1.  And here's the thing.  ifconfig indicates that the docker0 under both UbuntuVM1 and UbuntuVM2 are running on an identical IP of 127.17.0.1.  So, no wonder that error.  It's said if we add the IP of each peer to the /etc/hosts file and map IP to peer such as  127.17.0.1 peer0  127.18.0.1 peer1  then,  peers on the same network would be able to identify each other.  Is such understanding correct?  If so, how could we assign some specific IP address to each peer?  Or?  Thanks in advance.              ></description> </Issue>
