<Issue id="30363" key="FAB-10190" number="10190" project="10002" reporter="scottz" assignee="dongming" creator="scottz" type="10101" summary="Service Discovery Performance Traffic 1 chaincode" priority="2" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2018-05-17 16:53:55.0" updated="2018-12-01 18:39:12.0" resolutiondate="2018-06-27 20:22:39.0" votes="0" watches="2" workflowId="44563"> <description><! CDATA Identify an existing pte traffic test, and write a new one for comparison using Serv Disc. We must configure the network and the pte client to use service discovery, and run the traffic mix in a network that ideally contains many peers and orgs and channels and chaincodes with different endorsement requirements. Details TBD.  This is dependent on: # SDK code completion (FAB-8830) # PTE client application development for Mutual TLS # PTE client application development for using service discovery during initialization and in designing traffic patterns # it MAY also require writing a plugin or two for SDK behavior for the service discovery and for handling failures for transaction proposals, but we are hoping to use the default behavior for now     Test Name: FAB-10190 performance benchmark: constant run with service discovery  Component: Performance  Description: Performance constant invokes with service discovery      chaincode: each channel has one chaincode, sample_cc NodeJS, instantiated      transactions: 4 threads, each thread sends 10,000 invokes to each channel as the following: # thread 1 sends to channel 1 # thread 2 sends to channel 1 # thread 3 sends to channel 2 # thread 4 sends to channel 2      Each invoke has payload size of 1kb-2kb.  Artifact Location: crypto-config  Network Topology: docker containers; 2 channels, 2 organizations, 2 peers per org, 4 kafka, 3 zookeepers, 3 orderers, 2 ca, with mutual TLS (clientauth)  Event:          service: FilteredBlock          listener: block  Client Driver: PTE  Output: # The benchmark passes if it completes without any error. # The benchmark fails if it encounters error or any event missing.  This testcase has the same setting as -FAB-7334- except the targetPeers in order to see the impact of using service discovery vs designated peers.  ></description> </Issue>
