<Action id="56806" issue="37516" author="latitiah" type="comment" created="2019-02-08 15:35:50.0" updateauthor="latitiah" updated="2019-02-08 15:35:50.0"> <body><! CDATA Withdrawing this bug. Upon further inspection, I found an issue with the test. The chaincode calling chaincode works as expected, but the upgrade still fails. The following chaincode calling chaincode steps are what is passing now: {code:java} Given I changed the "Application" capability to version "V2_0" And I have a bootstrapped fabric network of type solo And I want to use the new chaincode lifecycle  When an admin sets up a channel named "channel2" And an admin packages chaincode at path "github.com/hyperledger/fabric-test/chaincodes/example02/go/cmd" with name "ex02" And the organization admins install the built "ex02" chaincode package on all peers Then a hash value is received on all peers #When each organization admin approves the "ex02" chaincode package on "channel2" When each organization admin approves the "ex02" chaincode package on "channel2" with policy "OR ('org1.example.com.member','org2.example.com.member')" And an admin commits the chaincode package to the channel "channel2" And I wait up to "10" seconds for the chaincode to be committed And a user invokes on the channel "channel2" using chaincode named "ex02" with args  "init","a","1000","b","2000"  And I wait up to "30" seconds for deploy to complete  When an admin sets up a channel named "channel1" And an admin packages chaincode at path "github.com/hyperledger/fabric-test/chaincodes/example04/cmd" with name "ex04" And the organization admins install the built "ex04" chaincode package on all peers Then a hash value is received on all peers When each organization admin approves the "ex04" chaincode package on "channel1" with policy "OR ('org1.example.com.member','org2.example.com.member')" And an admin commits the chaincode package to the channel "channel1" And I wait up to "10" seconds for the chaincode to be committed And a user invokes on the channel "channel1" using chaincode named "ex04" with args  "init","Event","1"  And I wait up to "30" seconds for deploy to complete  When a user queries on the channel "channel2" using chaincode named "ex02" with args  "query","a"  Then a user receives a success response of 1000 When a user queries on the channel "channel1" using chaincode named "ex04" with args  "query","Event","ex02","a","channel2"  Then a user receives a success response of 1000 {code}  ></body> </Action>
