<Issue id="12543" key="FAB-242" number="242" project="10002" reporter="joshhus" creator="joshhus" type="10001" summary="Document deploying Fabric on Azure" priority="2" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2016-08-24 20:31:50.0" updated="2018-07-20 18:55:51.0" resolutiondate="2018-03-22 22:31:10.0" votes="0" watches="2" timeoriginalestimate="115200" timeestimate="115200" workflowId="36125"> <description><! CDATA We really need a component for deployment considerations.    ---- (Migrating issue from GH, Write paper on deploying hyperledger #1024)   joshhus commented on Apr 8  Allen Bailey and Josh Horton to write one-page "whitepaper" for the April 30 weekend "hackathon" with business partners and competitors.  The whitepaper will describe in detail how to deploy hyperledger on Azure.  A second goal is for the whitepaper to describe how to deploy hyperledger on ANY platform - any "bare metal softlayer" deployment of hyperledger. But the immediate goal for the paper and confirmation / testing is to provide the deploy to Azure procedure for the hackathon. @joshhus joshhus changed the title from Write paper on deploying hyperledger to Azure to Write paper on deploying hyperledger on Apr 8 @hannibalhuang Hyperledger Project member hannibalhuang commented on Apr 9  Hi @joshhus , I'm interested in the "any platform" concept, would be glad to participate in the discussion @srderson srderson added the documentation label on Apr 10 @stanacton stanacton commented on Apr 17 • edited  Hi, I'm very interested in the "any platform" concept too. VM is great for development, it would be nice to have a 'anywhere' client built in GO. Can anyone help me find this information on setting up independent nodes that talk to each other? The "Setting up a network" example does it within the Vagrant machine. @joequant joequant commented on Apr 19  Yes. Look at https://github.com/joequant/hyperledger These are scripts that are derived from scripts written by yeasy.  ./startnet.sh should download the docker images from docker hub and spin them off. @stanacton stanacton commented on Apr 19 Thank you very much!  This looks life what I need. … @yeasy Hyperledger Project member yeasy commented on Apr 19  Thanks joequant. @stanacton I highly recommend u to have a look at https://github.com/yeasy/docker-compose-files#hyperledger and https://github.com/yeasy/docker-hyperledger-peer.  Which will help you quickly boot up a hyperledger cluster without any local configuration and vagrant layer. @joequant joequant commented on May 2  Yes. I'll take a look at using docker compose. @wangbin767 wangbin767 commented 9 hours ago  I am interested in whether this paper finished? @joshhus Hyperledger Project member joshhus commented 41 minutes ago  Investigating, this was dependent on some test results, TBA. @christo4ferris Hyperledger Project member christo4ferris commented 26 minutes ago  can we please open this in Jira? Thanks.   ></description> </Issue>
