<Issue id="15433" key="FAB-2860" number="2860" project="10002" reporter="stchrysa" creator="stchrysa" type="10001" summary="As a fabric developer I need  an implementation of threshold signatures, with a modular API for threshold signatures and  multiple instantiations." priority="3" resolution="10001" status="6" created="2017-03-23 10:03:00.0" updated="2020-01-22 18:57:26.0" resolutiondate="2020-01-22 18:57:26.0" votes="0" watches="6" timeoriginalestimate="1728000" timeestimate="230400" workflowId="42901"> <description><! CDATA Threshold cryptography distributes a cryptographic scheme among the members of a group of peers in a resilient way, such that N peers execute the function collaboratively, while tolerating a number F of faulty and misbehaving peers.  With a threshold signature scheme, a digital signature is produced collaboratively by the group of N peers, and despite that F of them could be corrupted, no valid signature can result unless some correct peers have also consented to sign. This property is also achieved by multi-signatures, but in a different way: for multi-signatures, a verifier needs to know the list of all peers authorized to sign; a threshold signature scheme instead uses one ordinary signature verification key and produces signatures in the usual format. A threshold signature only needs one verification key and a signature represents the resilient consensus of the abstract signing group.  More precisely, a threshold signature scheme consists of the following algorithms:  (1) A key generation algorithm that generates a public-private key pair, a set of N secret key shares, one for each peer, and a set of verification keys.  (2) A signing algorithm that, given a message and a secret key share, outputs a signature share.  (3) A signature share verification algorithm. Given a message, a signature share, the public key, and a peer-specific verification key, it succeeds if the signatures share is valid.  (4) A share combination algorithm that given a set of N - F valid signature shares from distinct peers outputs the final signature.  (5) A signature verification algorithm, which is no different from ordinary digital signature schemes.  This work includes the implementation of two different threshold signature schemes: * RSA-based threshold signatures  Shoup, Victor. "Practical threshold signatures." In International Conference on the Theory and Applications of Cryptographic Techniques, pp. 207-220. Springer Berlin Heidelberg, 2000. * BLS-signatures (based on EC cryptography)  Boneh, Dan, Ben Lynn, and Hovav Shacham. "Short signatures from the Weil pairing." Journal of cryptology 17, no. 4 (2004): 297-319.  Threshold signatures enhance the robustness and the resilience of the blockchain system.  ></description> </Issue>
