<Action id="20532" issue="14134" author="joshhus" type="comment" body="This task is essentially to strip the TOC (/fabric/mkdocs.yml) of everything and start over for Jan. 31 delivery." created="2017-01-23 15:14:07.0" updateauthor="joshhus" updated="2017-01-23 15:14:07.0"/>
<Action id="20981" issue="14134" author="joshhus" type="comment" created="2017-02-17 17:18:37.0" updateauthor="joshhus" updated="2017-02-17 17:18:37.0"> <body><! CDATA Note to myself and Nick and FYI for cc: ... this will all be pasted into the JIRA issue: https://jira.hyperledger.org/browse/FAB-1705?filter=-1  Nick just one thing for you - check the items marked "TOC" here. ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------   Results of compare of v0.6 RTD content to current build.   Next I'll move the items that clearly should be included, and will mark the JIRA issue with these results and the moves.   Nick please search on "TOC" string for your TOC items. Section B. mostly. - the only short term reqs. for you.  (This mapping is not always a simple task - some content has been renamed/moved/consolidated or removed by the community.)   Flagging 2 categories of items in this note, A and B below.  (Will convert to Jira issues where appropriate.)  ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------  A. Things we have in the v0.6 RTD doc that we don't appear to have in the current build (Barry's repo):  Note some of this might have been left out purposefully, or renamed/moved:  # Fabric Starter Kit (perhaps this is intended / covered by the Getting Started info now?)  http://hyperledger-fabric.readthedocs.io/en/v0.6/starter/fabric-starter-kit/ # Migrating chaincode: http://hyperledger-fabric.readthedocs.io/en/v0.6/v0.6_migration/  ... (note chaincode isn't the only migration thing that might need some doc). # New Features: http://hyperledger-fabric.readthedocs.io/en/v0.6/v0.6_migration/#new-features # Fabric Network Setup: http://hyperledger-fabric.readthedocs.io/en/v0.6/Setup/Network-setup/ # Logging Control - From http://fabric-rtd.readthedocs.io/en/latest/dev-setup/build/#logging -- we point to the github repo instead of to the RTD built file. http://hyperledger-fabric.readthedocs.io/en/v0.6/Setup/logging-control/  ... will move.  # ACL: http://hyperledger-fabric.readthedocs.io/en/v0.6/tech/application-ACL/ # Protocol spec: http://hyperledger-fabric.readthedocs.io/en/v0.6/protocol-spec/ # Attributes: http://hyperledger-fabric.readthedocs.io/en/v0.6/tech/attributes/ # V1.0 Preview: http://hyperledger-fabric.readthedocs.io/en/v0.6/abstract_v1/  ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------  B. Things that need updating in the current build / Barry's repo / build:  (I'm omitting from this list, all the "WIP" topics, b/c I think those are well-tracked already / have Jira issues.)  * Release notes: http://fabric-rtd.readthedocs.io/en/latest/releases/ * Nit / low FYI text in "command" table at the bottom too small: http://fabric-rtd.readthedocs.io/en/latest/chaincode/ * TOC tweaks - a) "Docker Compose" caps. b) Are we going to use the "smart contracts" term -- or instead "chaincode applications" only? c) "CP Paper" is redundant.  * Notice -- in some cases we point to doc that is NOT in the fabric/docs dir, but in other dirs, such as fabric/dev-setup.... There are some fabric/apis etc. directories also ... These will need some confirmation that the devs have updated their content in there for v1.0 ... e.g. this page still references Vagrant: http://fabric-rtd.readthedocs.io/en/latest/dev-setup/build/  * Nit / low ... I don't like use of "the blockchain" ... there is no one "blockchain" that everyone uses. Even on one network, there are mutliple "blockchains" (ledgers with crypto-linked "chain" of blocks). So blockchain is a concept / abstraction, not a physical object. And can be used as a noun - "we're using blockchain" or an adjective - "we're using a "blockchain network". See http://fabric-rtd.readthedocs.io/en/latest/carlease/ ...  * While we're on car lease, let's at some point add title/registration tracking, and renewal / transfer of title/ownership, and insurance and registration renewal and proofs of purchase and not expired status. Also since we're selling the used car, also show me the carfax / vehicle history.  * Usage FAQ: http://fabric-rtd.readthedocs.io/en/latest/FAQ/usage_FAQ/  (esp. "validating node" and the specific error message, which should be moved to Troubleshooting.)  * "Troubleshooting" is currently limited to "Docker Troubleshooting" so it should either be renamed as such, or expanded to include other problems / error msgs. (It's also labeled "optional" ... which isn't really true for those having the problem. - delete "optional".) http://fabric-rtd.readthedocs.io/en/latest/asset_trouble/ * TOC - "Multi Channel" - change to "Channels" and point to the new topic. * "Consensus" WIP http://fabric-rtd.readthedocs.io/en/latest/consensus/  ... text says that consensus is used as a "broader term than ordering to include the entire transactional flow" ... We should change that text--we don't want to reinvent the established concept of "consensus algorithms" or "consensus protocols." ... I think what we mean here is that depending on the plug-in used for the ordering component, it may or may not be a "consensus" algorithm/protocol. ... e.g. PFBT is a consensus protocol because it solves, to a degree, the consensus problem - which is when message recipients receive divergent conflicting messages, basically. (I'm not certain that SOLO and Kafka are also truly consensus protocols in that they solve the consensus problem - that a protocol orders stuff doesn't mean that it necessarily solves the consensus problem. ... I will have to look into that more.) If all agree, I can take the Consensus topic. * TOC: Appendix: "Development process and code" is limited to just "Fabric development process and code" so needs a rename. * TOC: Gerrit heading - there are a number of adjacent topics at same level as Gerrit heading that are also Gerrit topics.  * Contributing - Legal Stuff - we have the signoff, but do we need to add the hooks for the ChangeID? ... (and is that really "legal" stuff? - scary.) http://fabric-rtd.readthedocs.io/en/latest/CONTRIBUTING/#legal-stuff * Nit  / low - some of our links that take the user to an external site we should be opening a new browser tab for them. - someone goes to an external site, click a few times, and then can't find their way back to us easily. e.g. we link to https://jira.hyperledger.org/secure/Dashboard.jspa  from http://fabric-rtd.readthedocs.io/en/latest/CONTRIBUTING/#coding-guidelines ... (and while we're there, it's fewer than eight, not less than, in Maintainers.)     ></body> </Action>
<Action id="20989" issue="14134" author="joshhus" type="comment" created="2017-02-17 21:26:57.0" updateauthor="joshhus" updated="2017-02-17 21:26:57.0"> <body><! CDATA B) Moved to https://jira.hyperledger.org/browse/FAB-2346 ... those are separate items from the move issue.    ></body> </Action>
<Action id="20990" issue="14134" author="joshhus" type="comment" created="2017-02-17 21:36:10.0" updateauthor="joshhus" updated="2017-02-17 21:36:10.0"> <body><! CDATA Examination of v0.6 complete, and the relevant files are in the RTD staging dir. ...  i.e. these might be / are candidates for being edited / included in v1.0 library.  They are as follows:   # fabric/docs/abstract_v1.md # fabric/docs/protocol-spec.md # fabric/docs/v0.6_migration.md # fabric/docs/tech/application-ACL.md # fabric/docs/tech/attributes.md # fabric/docs/starter/fabric-starter-kit.md # fabric/docs/Setup/Network-setup.md # fabric/docs/dev-setup/build.md  ></body> </Action>
