<Issue id="29381" key="FAB-9504" number="9504" project="10002" reporter="bur" assignee="bur" creator="bur" type="10001" summary="Support for secure chaincode execution using Intel SGX" priority="3" resolution="10001" status="6" created="2018-04-13 13:46:03.0" updated="2020-01-22 22:32:41.0" resolutiondate="2020-01-22 22:32:41.0" votes="2" watches="16" workflowId="35695"> <description><! CDATA Many applications of blockchains require data confidentiality. In particular, financial transactions, voting on the blockchain, sealed-bid auctions, and many more applications come with strong requirements in terms of privacy and correctness. A voting system, for instance, must protect the confidentiality of every vote cast and must provide means to verify that every submitted vote has been considered in the final voting result. The latter can be achieved by using blockchain technologies, where every vote is a transaction stored on the ledger. However, maintaining confidentiality in an open and verifiable blockchain is a difficult problem (also in a permissioned, consortium blockchain). For example, an application for voting running on Fabric would be implemented by a chaincode that receives encrypted votes, records them, and decrypts them later, in order to compute the final voting result and take further actions. This system would need to keep the decryption key for the encrypted votes secret, since the chaincode is executed by all endorsing peers. Or it would need to trust all endorsers, which reduces the benefits of the blockchain model.  The design should work with only one Fabric channel. Apart from using advanced cryptographic protocols, such as Zero-knowledge Proofs or Secure Multiparty Computation, no solution is available for this within Fabric today. In other words, maintaining confidentiality of secrets manipulated by a chaincode requires trust in the endorsing peers. Thus, a single corrupted endorsing peer may violate the confidentiality of the application.  To overcome this issue trusted execution environments such as Intel SGX have been proposed. This document starts the design for adding support to securely execute chaincode using Intel SGX in Fabric. With Intel SGX, a peer executes chaincode in a trusted execution environment, also called an enclave. SGX enforces confidentiality and integrity of the chaincode even when the peer system is misbehaving. In order words, using SGX, a voting chaincode may evaluate the voting results without revealing the encrypted votes to the executing peer.  However, simply running "the chaincode" in an enclave is not enough, as steps for ensuring consistency between the execution and the ledger state and for verification of the outputs by the clients are needed.  The design document describing the model:  https://docs.google.com/document/d/1-4BQpBOnFs7ijj2iirbO38FNJU5F7DLdpXJ1GQqboAM/edit?usp=sharing   A detailed design and a research prototype for this function are described in a paper released on arxiv in May 2018:   https://arxiv.org/abs/1805.08541   Comments should be discussed here.  The prototype code is available as a Hyperledger labs. https://github.com/hyperledger-labs/fabric-secure-chaincode  ></description> </Issue>
