<Issue id="40692" key="FABN-1276" number="1276" project="10604" reporter="jjetten" assignee="jesro" creator="jjetten" type="10004" summary="typescript definitions for ConnectOptions on ChannelEventHub are incorrect" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2019-06-19 15:24:01.0" updated="2019-10-24 15:10:24.0" resolutiondate="2019-10-24 15:10:24.0" votes="0" watches="2" workflowId="53642"> <description><! CDATA    Connectoptions definition in index.d.ts: {code:java} 344 export interface ConnectOptions {  345 full_block?: boolean;  346 signedEvent?: SignedEvent;  347 } {code}       ConnectOptions from fabric-client/lib/ChannelEventHub.js    {code:java} 251 /** 252 * @typedef {Object} ConnectOptions 253 * @property {boolean} full_block - Optional. To indicate that the connection 254 * with the peer will be sending full blocks or filtered blocks to this 255 * ChannelEventHub. 256 * The default will be to establish a connection using filtered blocks. 257 * Filtered blocks have the required information to provided transaction 258 * status and chaincode events (no payload). 259 * When using the non filtered blocks (full blocks) the user 260 * will be required to have access to establish the connection to 261 * receive full blocks. 262 * Registering a block listener on a filtered block connection may not 263 * provide sufficient information. 264 * @property {Number | string} startBlock - Optional. This will have the connection 265 * setup to start sending blocks back to the event hub at the block 266 * with this number. If connecting with a 267 * a startBlock then event listeners may not be registered with a 268 * startBlock or endBlock. 269 * If the event hub should start with the last block it has seen 270 * use the string 'last_seen'. 271 * If the event hub should start with the oldest block on the 272 * ledger use the string 'oldest'. 273 * If the event hub should start with the latest block on the ledger, 274 * use the string 'latest' or do use a startBlock. 275 * Default is to start with the latest block on the ledger. 276 * @property {Number | string} endBlock - Optional. This will have the connection 277 * setup to end sending blocks back to the event hub at the block 278 * with this number. If connecting with a 279 * a endBlock then event listeners may not be registered with a 280 * startBlock or endBlock. 281 * If the event hub should end with the last block it has seen 282 * use the string 'last_seen'. 283 * If the event hub should end with the current block on the 284 * ledger use the string 'newest'. 285 * Default is to not stop sending. 286 * @property {SignedEvent} signedEvent - Optional. The signed event to be sent 287 * to the peer. This option is useful when the fabric-client application 288 * does not have the user's privateKey and can not sign requests to the 289 * fabric network. 290 * @property {Peer | string} target - Optional. The peer that provides the 291 * fabric event service. When using a string, the {@link Channel} 292 * must have a peer assigned with that name. This peer will replace 293 * the current peer endpoint of this channel event hub. 294 */ {code}  ></description> </Issue>
