<Action id="20141" issue="13831" author="muralisr" type="comment" created="2016-12-15 23:35:56.0" updateauthor="muralisr" updated="2016-12-15 23:35:56.0"> <body><! CDATA Thanks  ~denyeart .  The use case for upgrade is this. * SDK sends Proposal{ To: "lccc", ChainID: "mychain", Function: "upgrade", Args:  "example01", <newcode bytes> } * endorser creates r/w set from lccc to do the above upgrade.. this is basically the PutState("example01", <upgrade data>), ie, essentually the "Args" part.  NOTE that this DOES NOT contain "input" data such as "Function: upgrade" * Committer receives TX with the above r/w set * lccc_vscc needs to extract out (1) the function to answer the question is the TX an upgrade (2) get the information such as chaincode name (example01), version   Let us focus on the first part - needing to know the function to answer the quetion "is the tx is an upgrade ?" This is an input data and is not part of the r/w set. One way to get this data is to make the operation a state var and do a Put("example01_op", "upgrade"). But this pollutes the state namespace with side effect data in order to make it available for VSCC processing. And would only get for more complex scenarios and basically exposes the limitation of attempt to infer TX information via r/w set introspection and side-effects.  Per understanding of the proposal from  ~manish-sethi   ~denyeart  ...  It would be nice if we can tag "metadata" or "information" data along with transaction to the rw set that is accessible as a PER TRANSACTION data (as opposed to State data which is PER CHAINCODE).  The Chaincode would do a SetInfo() on the proposal which can be accessed with a GetInfo at Commit time.   This opens the door for such processing in a natural manner and seems to be consistent with other ledger data access mechanisms and will benefit use cases far more complex than the "upgrade" one above.  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="20142" issue="13831" author="denyeart" type="comment" body=" ~binhn  Do you agree with the design proposed in this user story? Any other thoughts?  Any synergy with your &apos;side data&apos; ideas?" created="2016-12-16 02:44:49.0" updateauthor="denyeart" updated="2016-12-16 02:44:49.0"/>
<Action id="20250" issue="13831" author="denyeart" type="comment" body=" ~binhn  Please review the description and comment and let us know if you agree with the approach here." created="2017-01-03 14:43:42.0" updateauthor="denyeart" updated="2017-01-03 14:43:42.0"/>
<Action id="20257" issue="13831" author="binhn" type="comment" body="I have discussed with  ~muralisr  and we should explore alternative rather than this proposal now." created="2017-01-03 19:15:22.0" updateauthor="binhn" updated="2017-01-03 19:15:22.0"/>
<Action id="66941" issue="13831" author="sykesm" type="comment" body="Stale" created="2020-01-22 18:45:15.0" updateauthor="sykesm" updated="2020-01-22 18:45:15.0"/>
