<Issue id="46576" key="FABCN-441" number="441" project="11207" reporter="ryjones" assignee="JIRAUSER20406" creator="ryjones" type="10004" summary="azure-mocha-reporter is vulnerable to package confusion" priority="1" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2021-02-16 17:29:48.0" updated="2021-03-26 14:07:54.0" resolutiondate="2021-03-26 14:07:54.0" votes="0" watches="4" workflowId="60520" security="10000" archived="N"> <description><! CDATA Source: https://hackerone.com/bugs?subject=hyperledger&report_id=1104728     In the context of your bug bounty program I wanted to inform you I have found some misconfigurations in one of your open source node projects that lead to RCE (this was disclosed some days ago). Please read the vulnerability details to get more information about the "dependency confusion" vulnerability:  https://medium.com/@alex.birsan/dependency-confusion-4a5d60fec610   Basically, if you reference a private package without specifying the full path to it, somebody can take those package names on npm and this leads to RCE. I have done several PoC for this vulnerability and it is actually quite effective. Unfortunately, even though I tried to do so for this case my npm account was just blocked :sad:. So I basically registered your misreferenced package names but I cannot transfer their ownership to you now because of my npm account being blocked. I already sent npm several emails without response but I will definitely let you know if they unlock my account.  The packages misreferenced in your open source projects are: azure-mocha-reporter:1.0.0  While the package was up I did receive some install requests with the following information (3 times), these may be coming from your servers or maybe from any of your package users, I would not be able to determine: { ip: '13.66.219.121', org: 'hyperledger', packageName: 'azure-mocha-reporter', hostname: '97deadae9444', username: 'root', path: '/opt/src/npm/azure-mocha-reporter/1.0.2/installed/node_modules/azure-mocha-reporter' }  Please fix your package references to be safer for now and I will let you know if I have my account unblocked for you to have the ownership of this package name.  Have a great day!  Impact Remote code execution on any machine that installs the project by running npm install.  ></description> </Issue>
