<Action id="70983" issue="45548" author="lesleyannj" type="comment" created="2020-12-18 14:23:36.0" updateauthor="lesleyannj" updated="2021-01-08 15:05:56.0"> <body><! CDATA Add to github  fabric-sdk-node/RELEASING.md   _Release Process Using v1.4 and last release being v1.4.15 as an example _  *Pre-check* * Check top level package.json version and tag are one above the current release and correct for publishing snapshots.   * Expect v1.4.16-snapshot and unstable-1.4.   * If this is not the case then create PR and change.  *Submit release PR* 1.	Create jira for publish (Publish v1.4.16). 2.	Run the scripts/changelog.sh script from the project root directory. It takes 2 arguments: last release commit hash, and next release version number. a.	./scripts/changelog.sh <commit hash> 1.4.16 3.	Update the version and tag properties in the top-level package.json to the appropriate values.  E.g. the next release version number (to 1.4.16) and the release npm tag of latest-1.4 4.	Create release_notes/v1.4.16.txt file with text “This is a maintenance release containing bug fixes....” 5.	The merge build once the PR is merged will do the npm publishing.  Check it has npm published  https://www.npmjs.com/package/fabric-client and https://www.npmjs.com/package/fabric-common  *Tag Release* Create in GitHub release draft with similar text to release_notes “This is a maintenance release containing bug fixes."   Code > Tags > Releases > Draft a new release.   Save as draft   Be sure to set: •	Tag version > 1.4.16 •	Target Branch > release-1.4 ‘Publish release’ publishing the release in GitHub creates a corresponding Git tag.  *Post Release Clean up* Create jira for Reset snapshot publishing to 1.4.17 Once the release is done, create a second PR to change the top-level package.json verion and tag properties back to the ones for publishing snapshots, which for v1.4 would be 1.4.17-snapshot and unstable-1.4  *Post Release on Slack* Mention release on fabric-dev slack channel with link to release notes   ></body> </Action>
<Action id="71074" issue="45548" author="lesleyannj" type="comment" created="2021-01-07 14:41:40.0" updateauthor="lesleyannj" updated="2021-01-08 15:06:10.0"> <body><! CDATA Update https://github.com/hyperledgendary/hyperledgendary.github.io/wiki/Release-playbook   ></body> </Action>
