<Issue id="29990" key="FAB-9918" number="9918" project="10002" reporter="denyeart" assignee="angelo.decaro" creator="denyeart" type="10001" summary="TEST PLAN: Idemix for Advanced Functionalities (revocation, BCCSP)" priority="3" resolution="10001" status="6" created="2018-05-07 03:00:20.0" updated="2020-01-22 22:32:15.0" resolutiondate="2020-01-22 22:32:15.0" votes="0" watches="1" workflowId="35743"> <description><! CDATA Before closing this testplan task, this must be reviewed and approved by this epic feature owner and the Test Prime (identified below), to agree on appropriate coverage for each test phase.  +*Location / Description of*+ docs, APIs, config vars, system configuration (fabric, SDKs, fabric-samples) :     +*Unit Test (UT) leader*+: ????  Automated unit tests are merged in repo, as go tests or otherwise part of build/verify jenkins jobs. Code coverage tracked in Jenkins:  https://jenkins.hyperledger.org/view/Daily/job/fabric-unit-test-coverage-daily-master-x86_64/      +***+*+*Function Test (FVT) leader+*: ???? In v1.2 the peer is not well structured for integration tests, therefore we will compensate with expanded Unit tests and expanded E2E tests using ginkgo. Describe function test coverage approach here:  A.  Expand unit testcases beyond traditional UT coverage, for the following integration scenarios that otherwise might be done using the ginko framework): # Scenario Description X # Scenario Description Y # Scenario Description Z  B.  E2E testcases scenarios (Add one individual jira TASK within this feature Epic for each of these): # Scenario Description X # Scenario Description Y # Scenario Description Z  C.  Other functional testing required: # Method/Tool, and Scenario Description # Method/Tool, and Scenario Description # Example: ginkgo (future availability). Description xyz. Untestable in v1.2 ; an identified test coverage gap.     +*System Verification Test (SVT) leader*+: ???? V1.2 System Test Plan (Epic) FAB-???? Covers stress, load, performance, full system integration, resiliency, recover, etc.  Considering this feature, what scenarios are of particular interest and concern: # Scenario Description X # Scenario Description Y # Scenario Description Z  ></description> </Issue>
