<Action id="31237" issue="21044" author="adnanchoudhury" type="comment" body=" ~scottz   ~latitiah " created="2017-09-28 14:26:38.0" updateauthor="adnanchoudhury" updated="2017-09-28 14:26:38.0"/>
<Action id="31248" issue="21044" author="latitiah" type="comment" created="2017-09-28 19:09:01.0" updateauthor="latitiah" updated="2017-09-28 20:05:54.0"> <body><! CDATA I would propose something along the lines of the following: Add explicit "within X seconds" phrasing on some Given, When, and Then calls that allows for timing out of certain calls. This is not around the assert calls but is dependent on the calls themselves. For example, {code} Then within 10 seconds, the peer0.org1.example.com log should contain "Done with transaction simulation / query execution" {code}  But if an action may need to be repeated in order to move to the next step, then the timeout should be with that step. For example, {code} When a user deploys chaincode within 30 seconds {code} If the deploy is not completed within that time period, then this step fails.  Note: we know that sometimes it takes time for docker containers and the executables to complete initialization. Docker returns once the containers are up; it does not wait to make sure that everything is running successfully. This is especially significant when bringing up fabric networks and when deploying chaincodes.  Though, it will be worth it to look into adding health_checks in our "depends_on" clauses - condition: service_started (docker composition files version 2.1)  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="31590" issue="21044" author="adnanchoudhury" type="comment" created="2017-10-03 20:24:41.0" updateauthor="adnanchoudhury" updated="2017-10-03 20:24:41.0"> <body><! CDATA To summarize, the goal is to make sure that tests do not fail due to timing issues where a reasonable increase in wait time would have made them pass.  To achieve that goal, there are several proposals mentioned: 1)  For the "Then" statements that are repeatable:  ----->there should be a max-time mentioned in the statement that specifies for how long the polling should continue 2)  For some Given, When, and Then calls where the call themselves might not be repeatable but there are well-defined explicit checks to see if the call passed/failed: ---->  There should be a max time mentioned in the statement that specifies how long it should keep polling with the explicit check. 3) For the other statements that do not have well defined explicit checks: -----> TBD   ~latitiah  Please provide feedback about the summary and/or additional comments.  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="32569" issue="21044" author="adnanchoudhury" type="comment" body="https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/#/c/14243/" created="2017-10-17 16:05:26.0" updateauthor="adnanchoudhury" updated="2017-10-17 16:05:26.0"/>
<Action id="32570" issue="21044" author="adnanchoudhury" type="comment" body="Opening this up again to include polling in gossip log searching tests." created="2017-10-17 16:06:14.0" updateauthor="adnanchoudhury" updated="2017-10-17 16:06:14.0"/>
<Action id="33374" issue="21044" author="adnanchoudhury" type="comment" body="https://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/#/c/14619/" created="2017-10-30 16:04:49.0" updateauthor="adnanchoudhury" updated="2017-10-30 16:04:49.0"/>
