<Action id="68045" issue="44386" author="sergey.khoroshavin" type="comment" created="2020-02-21 17:04:34.0" updateauthor="sergey.khoroshavin" updated="2020-02-21 17:20:12.0"> <body><! CDATA In general CircleCI has same featureset as GitHub Actions, so answers to main questions will mostly refer to GitHub Actions research results. They even have a pretty straightforward migration guide, which also highlights some advantages of CircleCI over GitHub Actions:  https://circleci.com/docs/2.0/migrating-from-github   *Easy of use* Generally as easy as GitHub Actions.  *Platform and environment support* All required platforms are supported on commercial plans, however on free plan MacOS is absent (but it looks like they do have plans to support it). Also it is possible to run on more powerful hardware if needed, for example linux vm runners can have up to 64 Gb RAM and 16 CPUs (GitHub Actions doesn't have this feature)  *Difficulty of launching an Indy Pool for CI testing* Generally same as with GitHub Actions - it is possible to run jobs on virtual machines with docker installed, so docker configurations of any complexity can be created. Also CircleCI allows caching docker layers between runs (GitHub doesn't allow this directly), which can significantly speed up build, however this feature is paid.  *Cost* When comparing open-source plans GitHub Actions seem to win hands down, as they are totally free (at least their  website|https://github.com/features/actions  says so). However it isn't clear what are limitations in this case. Also, when looking at commercial plans CircleCI is actually cheaper, especially for MacOS builds:  https://circleci.com/pricing/   https://help.github.com/en/github/setting-up-and-managing-billing-and-payments-on-github/about-billing-for-github-actions      *A bit more details on cost*  Circle CI billing is a bit more obscure due to "credits", so a little bit explanation here: according to pricing link 25000 credits cost $15, and one minute of cheapest linux, windows and macos vms cost 10, 40 and 50 credits respectively, and it is possible to run inside docker container for as little as 5 credits per minute. With that in mind *one minute of CircleCI machines cost*: * Linux: $0.006, or $0.003 when run in Docker * Windows: $0.024 * MacOS: $0.03  Compare that with *GitHub Action prices per minute*:  * Linux: $0.008 * Windows: $0.016 * MacOS: $0.08  ></body> </Action>
<Action id="68138" issue="44386" author="sergey.minaev" type="comment" body="Current vision is to use GitHub Actions and keep in the mind the option to migrate Azure Pipelines or Circle CI if needed" created="2020-02-27 13:13:03.0" updateauthor="sergey.minaev" updated="2020-02-27 13:13:03.0"/>
