<Issue id="36703" key="IS-1139" number="1139" project="10401" reporter="mgbailey" assignee="vladimirwork" creator="mgbailey" type="10002" summary="Packages prevent installation of both indy-cli and libsovtoken" priority="3" resolution="10000" status="10001" created="2019-01-11 19:20:17.0" updated="2019-04-01 07:03:11.0" resolutiondate="2019-03-26 12:32:26.0" votes="0" watches="6" workflowId="51676"> <description><! CDATA Apparently the currently deployed packages for indy-cli and libsovtoken have conflicting dependencies, as shown: {code:java} vagrant@sandbox:~$ sudo apt-get install -y indy-cli libsovtoken Reading package lists... Done Building dependency tree Reading state information... Done Some packages could not be installed. This may mean that you have requested an impossible situation or if you are using the unstable distribution that some required packages have not yet been created or been moved out of Incoming. The following information may help to resolve the situation:The following packages have unmet dependencies: libsovtoken : Depends: libindy (= 1.6.8) but 1.7.0 is to be installed E: Unable to correct problems, you have held broken packages.  vagrant@sandbox:~$ sudo apt-get install -y indy-cli libsovtoken libindy=1.7.0 Reading package lists... Done Building dependency tree Reading state information... Done Some packages could not be installed. This may mean that you have requested an impossible situation or if you are using the unstable distribution that some required packages have not yet been created or been moved out of Incoming. The following information may help to resolve the situation:The following packages have unmet dependencies: libsovtoken : Depends: libindy (= 1.6.8) but 1.7.0 is to be installed E: Unable to correct problems, you have held broken packages. {code} Here are the package versions at the head of the repo: {code:java} libsovtoken: Installed: (none) Candidate: 0.9.6 Version table: 0.9.6 500 500 https://repo.sovrin.org/deb xenial/stable amd64 Packages ... vagrant@sandbox:~$ apt-cache policy indy-cli indy-cli: Installed: (none) Candidate: 1.7.0 Version table: 1.7.0 500 500 https://repo.sovrin.org/sdk/deb xenial/stable amd64 Packages {code}  ></description> </Issue>
