<Issue id="16795" key="FAB-3963" number="3963" project="10002" reporter="tkuhrt" assignee="christopherferris" creator="tkuhrt" type="10002" summary="Resolve licensing issues discovered by Fossology scan" priority="2" resolution="10000" status="6" created="2017-05-17 00:25:35.0" updated="2018-07-20 14:12:49.0" resolutiondate="2017-07-19 14:49:58.0" votes="0" watches="5" workflowId="38546"> <description><! CDATA Fabric source code was scanned using Fossology to determine the licenses specified in the files in the following repositories: *  http://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/fabric   *  http://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/fabric-sdk-java   *  http://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/fabric-sdk-node   *  http://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/fabric-ca   *  http://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/fabric-sdk-go   *  http://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/fabric-baseimage   *  http://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/fabric-sdk-py   *  http://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/fabric-chaintool   *  http://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/fabric-api   *  http://gerrit.hyperledger.org/r/fabric-test-resources   The attached file shows the results.  Following is a summary |License| |Number of files| | | | | |Apache 2.0:| |1670| |MPL:| | | | |MPL-2.0|59| | |Dual-licensed: GPL-2.0+, LGPL-2.1+ AND MPL-1.1|1| |MIT, BSD, …:| | | | |BSD-2-Clause|208| | |BSD-2-Clause-FreeBSD|4| | |BSD-3-Clause|6| | |BSD-style|98| | |BSD-style AND Apache 2.0|2| | |BSD-style AND MIT|4| | |BSD-style OR See-URL|1| | |Google-BSD|1147| | |Google-BSD AND MIT|2| | |ISC|1| | |MIT|157| | |MIT-style|42| |Other:| | | | |Disclaimer only|2| | |Google patent notice|13| | |OASIS Notice and URL|9| | |Public-domain|11| | |WTFPL|2| |No License Found:| |7042| | | | | | |TOTAL|10481|     The files listed under MPL, MIT, BSD, Other, and No License Found need to be resolved. For a good number of the cases, it appears that dependencies have been checked into the repository (usually found under a vendor directory). Ideally, the repositories should not include any dependencies, but rather the build process should make sure to pull the latest version of any dependencies. This will ensure that "local changes" are not made to these dependencies that we would be dependent on. In addition, it will ensure that any security issues resolved by those dependencies will be included in our binaries.  For the files listed as No License Found, we should first check with the original contributors to make sure that they can contain an Apache 2.0 license (for source code) or a Creative Commons with Attribution 4.0 license (for documentation). Once this has been verified, the editable files must be annotated with the correct license text and/or the SPDX short identifiers (see   https://spdx.org/sites/cpstandard/files/pages/files/using_spdx_license_list_short_identifiers.pdf ).  For binary files, a license.txt file should be included in the directory calling out the file types and the associated license.  Please note that there are a few files that did not properly make it into the attached spreadsheet because of a bug in Fossology. These files need to be manually included. Look for a new spreadsheet to be uploaded; however, I wanted to get this on someone's radar sooner rather than later due to the size of the non-compliant licensing.  Any files that are not covered by Apache 2.0 or CC by 4.0 that need to remain with the project will need to go through an exception process with the governing board. Let me know if there will be any of these, and we can generate the correct presentation for requesting the exception when we re-run the licensing scan after this issue has been fixed.  ></description> </Issue>
